<?xml version='1.0' encoding="windows-1251"?>

<game_dialogs>
    <dialog id="escape_trader_start_dialog">
	<phrase_list>
	    	<phrase id="0">
			<text>Hi! How you doing? Hopefully feeling well.\n I’ve got a job for you for the weekend.</text>
	    	</phrase>                                                                                               
	</phrase_list>
    </dialog>

    <dialog id="escape_trader_jobs">
	<phrase_list>
	    	<phrase id="0">
			<text>What kind of job?</text>
			<next>2</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="2">
			<text>Usual stuff. First off, I need artefacts. Paying normal price, not more, no less.\n And well, now and then I need ‘special’ people for ‘special’ kind of job.</text>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="3">
			<text>Indeed, the usual stuff. Okay – if I find something will try not to forget to bring it.</text>
			<next>15</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="4">
			<text>And, would you have a ‘special’ job for a ‘special’ man?</text>
			<next>12</next>
			<next>51</next>
			<next>52</next>			
			<next>5</next>						
		</phrase>

		<phrase id="5">
	        <precondition>escape_dialog.trader_need_artefact</precondition>  
			<text>There is one thing here. As rumours go, there’s a place nearby. It has a rare artefact. But I wouldn’t send newbies there, if you know what I mean. Deliver me the artefact, and in the meantime, I’ll try to clarify about your Gunslinger. The artefact will be rewarded decently, of course.</text>

			<next>6</next>
			<next>7</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="6">
			<text>Deal.[Objective]</text>
	        <give_info>escape_trader_need_artefact</give_info>
			<next>8</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="7">
			<text>No, thanks.</text>
			<next>9</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="8">
			<text>Agreed.</text>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="9">
			<text>It’s up to you.</text>
		</phrase>
		
		<phrase id="51">
	        <precondition>escape_dialog.trader_need_blockpost_box</precondition>
			<text>There’s a thing. I need you to steal a case from the army post. Carefully though. When they are offended, they make mince of everything around, making even rats hell scared.</text>
			<next>61</next>
			<next>71</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="61">
			<text>Okay, I’ll try to be discreet.[Objective]</text>
	        <give_info>escape_need_blockpost_case</give_info>
			<next>81</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="71">
			<text>No, I’m not up to it.</text>
			<next>91</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="81">
			<text>When you bring the case, I’ll do the payment. Let me warn you though, if you start killing soldiers, I’ll proclaim you out of law. I don’t need recklessness. We’ve built a fragile world here. Soldiers shoot stalkers now and then, of course, but there’s no severe opposition and we have channels to vend the loot to. If someone starts raising up a storm here, it will all instantly change and such a scenario does not make excited at all. It’s simpler and cheaper to bring your head to the army post commander. I hope you read me.    </text>

		</phrase>
		<phrase id="91">
			<text>As you wish.</text>
		</phrase>			

		<phrase id="52">
	        <precondition>escape_dialog.trader_need_military_document</precondition>
			<text>There’s a thing. Bartender from stalker bar asked to locate a folder with documents from “Agroprom” SRI for him. There is one “but” here. Currently the building of the institute is occupied by the military. They are looking for something there.</text>
			<next>62</next>
			<next>72</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="62">
			<text>Alright, I’ll pick that up, but you need to explain me how to get there.[Objective]</text>
			<give_info>garbage_find_stalker</give_info>
			<give_info>escape_need_agroprom_documents</give_info>
			<next>82</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="72">
			<text>Sorry, I’m not yet ready for it.</text>
			<next>92</next>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="82">
			<text>Go to the zone center, through dumps, then turn to the west – you’ll find agroprom there.
			When you see agroprom, use your PDA to locate the institute. I dropped you the coordinates. And, something more here. 
			I found a stalker, who knows bits and pieces about the grouping of Gunslinger. You can locate him in garages in the north edge of the dump. I told him about you. He’s prepared to meet with you.</text>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="92">
			<text>Come back when you are done.</text>
		</phrase>			
	
		<phrase id="12">
	        <precondition>escape_dialog.trader_dont_has_job</precondition>
			<text>No, nothing for now.</text>
		</phrase>
		<phrase id="15">
			<text>Good, good. Anything else there?</text>
		</phrase>
	</phrase_list>
    </dialog>

    <dialog id="escape_trader_done_artefact">
    <precondition>escape_dialog.have_artefact_nightstar</precondition>
	<phrase_list>
		<phrase id="0">
			<text>Here’s your artefact. A rather cute thing.</text>
	        <action>escape_dialog.give_artefact_nightstar</action>
	        <give_info>escape_trader_have_artefact</give_info>
			<next>2</next>			
		</phrase>			
		<phrase id="2">
			<text>Deal.</text>
		</phrase>
	</phrase_list>
    </dialog>

    <dialog id="escape_trader_done_blockpost_box">
    <precondition>escape_dialog.have_blockpost_case</precondition>
	<phrase_list>
		<phrase id="0">
			<text>Here’s your case.</text>
	        <action>escape_dialog.give_blockpost_case</action>
	        <give_info>escape_have_blockpost_case</give_info>
			<next>2</next>			

		</phrase>			
		<phrase id="2">
			<text>Weeell, 1000 or no, 500 roubles, and we are quits.</text>
		</phrase>
	</phrase_list>
    </dialog>

	<dialog id="escape_trader_talk_about">
	<phrase_list>
	   	<phrase id="0">
			<text>Tell me about ...</text>
			<next>1</next>
		</phrase>                                                                                               
	   	<phrase id="10">
			<text>Thanks, that’s it for today.</text>
		</phrase>                                                                                               	
	    <phrase id="1">
			<text>Feel free to ask, though I don’t know much. You understand, I hang all the time around here, and life goes there, outside.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>10</next>
	    </phrase>                                                                                               
	    <phrase id="2">
			<text>Tell me about military stalkers.</text>
			<next>21</next>
	    </phrase>
	    <phrase id="21">
			<text>They are military, give or take. Look haughtily on everyone, as if they are local gods or something. 
			They have no reverence for customs, will never help out, however hard you call. They may shoot you down though, but no out of pity, out of their nature – first shoot, then think. However, I managed to find agreement with them. 
			Vodka, magazines and stuff in exchange for peace. You know what I’m talking about.</text>
			<next>22</next>
	    </phrase>
	    <phrase id="22">
			<text>What do the military do in the Zone?</text>
			<next>221</next>
	    </phrase>
	    <phrase id="221">
			<text>They guard, of course. Either the zone itself is guarded, or the entire world from the zone. It’s kinda vague. Sometimes the military arrange mass-scale expeditions into the zone. So they must be looking for something there. But I tell you one thing. The military don’t respect the zone, and the zone doesn’t like them too. Zinc coffins are a frequent sight here.</text>

			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>10</next>
	    </phrase>
	   	<phrase id="3">
			<text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
			<next>31</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="31">
			<text>It’s dangerous without weapons in the Zone... and you can always buy it from me, the prices for you are almost the lowest: virtually the lowest... almost... In the Zone center there definitely is an artifact bonanza and the one who will reach it will get fabulously rich. Understand what I’m driving at?</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>10</next>
	   	</phrase>
	</phrase_list>
	</dialog>

	<dialog id="escape_trader_talk_level">
	<phrase_list>
	   	<phrase id="0">
			<text>Tell about that place.</text>
			<next>1</next>
		</phrase>                                                                                               
	   	<phrase id="10">
			<text>Alright, thanks.</text>
		</phrase>                                                                                               	
	    <phrase id="1">
   			<text>It’s the Zone doorway, the army cordon. On the plains there roam packs of blind dogs. Sometimes here come mutants. Basically, it’s calm and peaceful here most of the time, but for the military who like to have fun now and then. Stalkers come and go. Only newbies would stay for a while sometimes. You won’t find a good loot here. What else shall I say, there is a ruined Bridge and abandoned factory nearby. That’s about it.</text>

			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
		</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="2">
			<text>Tell me more about the army post.</text>
			<next>21</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="21">
			<text>Several dozens of soldiers and order to shoot on sight. Best to avoid direct contact. When they get offended, they call for special forces. Those leave no stone unturned up there, so that I see no customers for a month then. So you better make sure you don’t offend them. I know their commander a bit. A complete alcohol-addict. It’s owing to him that I can hold here.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>
			<next>10</next>						
	    </phrase>
	   	<phrase id="3">
			<text>Tell me more about the ruined bridge.</text>
			<next>31</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="31">
			<text>If you go down the road deep in the zone, you will see a railway embankment. Previously there was a bridge above the road, but it fell down during the blowout. The military like to hide in wait for stalkers returning with loot there.</text>

			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="4">
			<text>Tell me more about the abandoned factory.</text>
			<next>41</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="41">
			<text>As you cross the road, you will surely see it. A whitish building it is. What could be stolen – was stolen long ago, and what couldn’t be is rusty by now. It’s a favourite bandit’s place. Right nearby there is a lowland – there you can even find some artifacts.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
	   	</phrase>	   	
	</phrase_list>
	</dialog>

	<dialog id="escape_trader_talk_flame">
	<phrase_list>
	   	<phrase id="0">
			<text>Let’s chat.</text>
			<next>1</next>
		</phrase>                                                                                               
	   	<phrase id="10">
			<text>Well, thanks.</text>
		</phrase>                                                                                               	
	    <phrase id="1">
   			<text>Alright.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
		</phrase>	   	
		<phrase id="2">
			<text>What do you know about Gunslinger?</text>
			<next>21</next>
	    </phrase>
	    <phrase id="21">
			<text>Rumours are there. He’s rumoured a kind of local celebrity or so. He’s rumoured to go into the Zone center. Ask stalkers, they know more.</text>
			<next>22</next>
	    </phrase>
	    <phrase id="22">
			<text>How did Gunslinger reach the Zone center?</text>
			<next>221</next>
	    </phrase>
	    <phrase id="221">
			<text>I have no idea. Possibly, the bartender or somebody from the veteran stalkers knows.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
	    </phrase>
		<phrase id="3">
			<text>I need equipment, where can I find it? Are there any shops or something around here?</text>
			<next>31</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="31">
			<text>Well, you are standing right in the middle of one of those at the moment. Selling everything at lowest prices. Ammunition, though is tough in the zone, that’s why it costs so much.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="4">
			<text>I need money, how can I earn it?</text>
			<next>41</next>
	   	</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="41">
			<text>Everything is pretty simple. You do favours to others, unless they kill you, they pay. You can sell artefacts to me. Will pay a good price, unlike other misers.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>3</next>
			<next>4</next>						
			<next>10</next>
	   	</phrase>		
	</phrase_list>
	</dialog>

    <dialog id="loser_hello_dialog">
        <phrase_list>
            <phrase id="0">
                <text>Mugs robbed me!!! Bring me a serious weapon. To be frank though, I can shoot Kalash or double-barreller only...\nBring it please! I won’t forget that...</text>
                <next>1</next>
                <next>2</next>
                <next>3</next>
                <next>6</next>
            </phrase>

            <phrase id="1">
				<precondition>escape_dialog.novice_gane_job</precondition>
                <text>I’ll see what can be done.[Objective]</text>
                <give_info>escape_novice_need_weapon</give_info>
                <next>5</next>
            </phrase>
            <phrase id="2">
                <text>Some other day.</text>
            </phrase>
            <phrase id="3">
                <precondition>escape_dialog.haveAK</precondition>
                <text>Here, grab Kalash, maybe it’ll do for you...</text>
                <next>4</next>
                <action>escape_dialog.give_kalash_to_loser</action>
                <give_info>escape_novice_has_weapon</give_info>
            </phrase>
            <phrase id="6">
                <precondition>escape_dialog.haveTOZ</precondition>
                <text>Here, take this rifle, perhaps it’ll do for you...</text>
                <next>4</next>
                <action>escape_dialog.give_toz_to_loser</action>
                <give_info>escape_novice_has_weapon</give_info>
            </phrase>
            <phrase id="4">
                <text>Thanks, brother... I will never forget your help. Now the mugs will suffer.\n          [attitude changed to "Friend"]</text>
				<action>escape_dialog.set_dialog_thank</action>
            </phrase>
            <phrase id="5">
                <text>Take care, I’ll be around here, just in case.</text>
            </phrase>
        </phrase_list>
    </dialog>

    <dialog id="escape_novice_thank_actor">
        <phrase_list>
            <phrase id="0">
                <text>Well, thanks brother. I won’t forget that. I’m in dept to you.</text>
            </phrase>
        </phrase_list>
    </dialog>
    
	<dialog id="escape_talk_about_escape">
	<precondition>dialogs.level_escape</precondition>
	<phrase_list>
	   	<phrase id="0">
			<text>Tell me about the place.</text>
			<next>1</next>
		</phrase>                                                                                               
	   	<phrase id="10">
			<text>Thanks.</text>
		</phrase>	
	   	<phrase id="1">
			<text>This is a road into the Zone. In a basement behind the village close to the army post you will find a dealer. I don’t recommend going to the army post and exposing yourself to soldiers, they were ordered to shoot on sight… You should not kill soldiers, only in extreme cases. For each soldier killed the dealer has to pay and he will not be happy of your killings. On the plains there roam large packs of blind dogs, it’s dangerous for newbies to challenge them. Now and then mutants come by.</text>
			<next>2</next>
			<next>10</next>
		</phrase>
	   	<phrase id="2">
			<text>And what’s next there on the way to north?</text>
			<next>21</next>
		</phrase>                                                                                               
	   	<phrase id="21">
			<text>There is a dump. A murky place. Sometimes the trash piles are too high to pass there.</text>
		</phrase>                                                                                               		
	</phrase_list>
	</dialog>
    
</game_dialogs>
