<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="artefact">
		<text>Get the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1">
		<text>Защитить стоянку сталкеров на Свалке от нападения бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1_descr">
		<text>Защитить стоянку сталкеров на Свалке от нападения бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1_text">
		<text>Ко мне идет группа сталкеров, в благополучном приходе которых я заинтересован лично. Они остановились недалеко от Бара. Один раскаявшийся криминальный элемент почти добровольно сообщил нам, что на них в ближайшее время должны напасть. Так что направляйся туда и защити их стоянку от нападения.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2">
		<text>На Агропроме помочь сталкерам отбиться от бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2_descr">
		<text>На Агропроме помочь сталкерам отбиться от бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2_text">
		<text>Вобщем такое дело есть. Недавно на Агропром группа сталкеров ушла, последний раз когда они на связь выходили, сказали что в подземке, надыбали что-то ценное, но на них бандюки насели. Пока они держатся, но и свалить не могут. Поможешь им?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1">
		<text>Eliminate the bandits at the Dump.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
		<text>Wipe out the bandit gang that settled at the Dump. It has to be a quick and efficient operation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1_text">
		<text>A job, eh? Let’s see what we’ve got… Aha! Here you go: can you knock out that pack of bandits at the Dump? The Duty, with all their speeches about law and order, just can’t get down to it. Those are some rare scumbags, too, so they won't last long anyway. But the guy who gets them first will score big… and the booze is on me, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2">
		<text>Eliminate the Mercs and bandits in Rostok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
		<text>Destroy the group of Mercs and bandits that block the passage through Rostok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2_text">
		<text>There’s a gang of Mercs not far away, in Rostok. They hit it off with the bandits, so now they’re scheming to block the passage through the plant. I don’t need to tell you what a nuisance it is, it’s got to be resolved straight away. The Duty guys and some of the old-timers have already gone to teach them a lessons, but we haven’t heard from them in a while… So why don’t you… eh… go and check on them. The money's good, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3">
		<text>Eliminate the bandits at the farmstead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
		<text>It's all simple: clear the farmstead of bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3_text">
		<text>There’s this farmstead by the old warehouses. Used to be a perfect place for a rendezvous, to exchange goods, you know… that sort of thing. But now the bandits have occupied it and, by the looks of it, they are not about to make off. Now, that doesn’t suit me at all. I need this farmstead asap. I don’t care what happens to the lodgers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4">
		<text>Зачистить лагерь бандитов на "Дикой территории"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
		<text>Зачистить лагерь бандитов на "Дикой территории"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4_text">
		<text>На "Дикой территории" бандиты. Мы не можем допустить, чтобы эти подонки разводили антисанитарию прямо рядом с баром. Надо зачистить их лагерь.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5">
		<text>Уничтожить логово диких собак-мутантов на "Дикой территории"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить логово диких собак-мутантов на "Дикой территории"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5_text">
		<text>Несколько наших ребят пошли в экспедицию, вернулся один. Весь ободранный, в крови, глаза стеклянные. Нарвались на собак скорее всего. Их там целая стая. Так вот, найди их логово и перебей всех до последнего.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6">
		<text>Уничтожить группу бандитов на Агропроме</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить группу бандитов на Агропроме</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6_text">
		<text>Помню, как-то в 94-м прицепились ко мне рэкетиры - давай, мол, отстегивай. Ух, натерпелся я тогда, ресторан у меня был. Тогда на них управы не было! А тут вдруг узнаю, что эта же шайка теперь орудует на Агропроме, проценты за находку артефактов собирает! Но здесь у меня руки длинные. Я даже знаю, где именно они засели. Будь добр, накажи их.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7">
		<text>Уничтожить логово снорков в "Темной долине"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить логово снорков в "Темной долине"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7_text">
		<text>Мда… Похоже правы те, кто говорит что зона расширяется. В темной долине несколько снорков заметили, раньше они там не попадались. Ну тут уже паниковать некоторые начали. Долговцы обещали снорков уничтожить, но все не соберутся никак. Возьмешься?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1">
		<text>Find the Meatball artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1_descr">
		<text>Find the Meatball artifact that heals ailments and injuries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1_text">
		<text>Some padres have stopped by, left an order for a Meatball. You know, they have a certain interest in this healing artifact… those rotten miracle-workers! Anyway… You gonna do it? It’s up to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2">
		<text>Find the Crystal Spiker artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2_descr">
		<text>Find the Crystal Spiker artifact that protects against psi-attacks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2_text">
		<text>A "stinker"?.. No, that’s not it. "Crystal water"?.. No, wrong again… Bugger! "Crystal Spiker", that’s it! So here’s the deal: I have an order for this artifact, "Crystal Spiker". Have you heard of it? They say that if you’ve got one, no creature will be able to mess with your brain. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3">
		<text>Find the Goldfish artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3_descr">
		<text>Find the Goldfish artifact to help the national military research effort.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3_text">
		<text>I need the Goldfish artifact. I’m sorry to say it doesn’t grant any wishes, been there, done that, but it can grant you some dough. The scientists cough up for it. They say they make some military stuff out of it… So, are you up for it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4">
		<text>Найти артефакт "Вспышка"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4_descr">
		<text>Найти артефакт "Вспышка"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4_text">
		<text>Задание простое, а оплата хорошая. Нужно найти артефакт "Вспышка". Даже и не спрашивай - кто и зачем заказал. Берешься?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5">
		<text>Найти артефакт "Золотая рыбка"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5_descr">
		<text>Найти артефакт "Золотая рыбка"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5_text">
		<text>Меченый, знаешь сказку про Золотую рыбку? Во, во! Еще анекдотов много про нее. Так вот, есть один старик, который все хочет ее поймать. В общем, нужен уникальный артефакт "Золотая рыбка", заказчик внешний, солидный. Поможешь?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_1">
		<text>Find the psi-suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_1_descr">
		<text>Find the suit that provides efficient protection against psi-emissions. The place to look is the deserted labs in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_1_text">
		<text>In those labs in the Dark Valley, they were trying to find a way to protect human brains from psi-emissions. They were taking their time, that’s for sure… Anyway, one of their attempts actually was a success, and there’s supposed to be this suit somewhere that you can wear and even kiss the controller. Yep, it’s that good. So if you get me this doodah, I’ll never forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_2">
		<text>Find the foreigner's gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_2_descr">
		<text>An interesting assignment. The name rings a bell… but where do I know him from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_2_text">
		<text>There once was this foreigner in our neck of the woods… Gordon was his name? His whole manner gave out an experienced stalker, but he said he’d never been to the Zone. But anyway, that’s not the point. He did vanish somewhere in the Zone eventually. But he had this rather curious thing, the Desert Eagle. If I could just take a closer look at it…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_3">
		<text>Find the modified Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_3_descr">
		<text>Find the modified Vintorez. Apparently, the place to look is the Radar area. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_find_item_3_text">
		<text>There was this odd story. This one fellow pops up, pockets full of dough, and sets off hiring himself a gang, not the old-timers though, but more of the nippy type. Bought tons of gear… I had this one brand new Vintorez, a marvelous gun! - so I was fool enough to sell it to him. I won’t lie to you, I made quite a bit of money… except this whole crew got knocked out close to the Radar. What can I say, they died for nothing… well, a good lesson for all to learn: you can’t pave your way through the Zone with money. But anyway… I can't stop thinking about that Vintorez, such a bang-up gun rusting somewhere! Won’t you find it for me? I’m paying good money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1">
		<text>Kill the soldier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1_descr">
		<text>A soldier has to bite the dust. The job is a piece of cake, except… it’s weird that the target’s a man in uniform, and the customer really has his dander up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1_text">
		<text>I need you to down this one grunt… don't ask me who he is, what do I care! Just do it. So? Can I entrust you with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2">
		<text>Kill the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2_descr">
		<text>Do in one of the stalkers. Death to the cheater, that's the trader's revenge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2_text">
		<text>You know, there’s this type of men that you could never say a bad word about… you trust him as you trust yourself, right? You bank on him… But suddenly you find out that he is the vilest and meanest son of a bitch… So here’s the deal: there’s this one case that needs to get sorted. Do it, and I’ll take care of the rest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3">
		<text>Kill the stalker from the Monolith faction</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3_descr">
		<text>Find trader's ex-friend and help him die.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3_text">
		<text>I used to have a friend… hard to believe, eh? Ah! we came to the Zone together when none of this stuff was here... The things we used to do, the places we used to go to… oh well, we were young, didn’t give a damn about anything… But he could never get enough. He wanted to go to the center of the Zone and was talking me into it, but I refused, and did the right thing… We had a really bad row, and he left on his own… And now I hear someone saw him there… he’s with Monolith now. So the deal is, Marked One… Grant my request, find him and… well, don’t make him suffer, it must be bad enough… He was like a brother to me, do you understand? You do…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4">
		<text>Kill the stalker called Vampire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4_descr">
		<text>Find and kill the stalker called Vampire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4_text">
		<text>That's it, I’ve had enough of this scumbag! I mean Vampire; do you know him? That bastard! Sucking luck out of people instead of blood. Whoever goes with him, they all die, all to a man, but he always comes back safe and sound! Done it five times now! That’s evil, don’t you think? I’d love to put some flowers on this Vampire’s grave… So, do you take the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5">
		<text>Kill the stalker called Sparrow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5_descr">
		<text>Find Sparrow and avenge the death of another stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5_text">
		<text>Damn musketeers! Playing D'Artagnan, assholes! As if surfing around anomalies and bowing to bullets is not enough, the oafs have now taken to fighting duels! Get this: there was this row… no one can even remember any more what started it. So these two dumbheads decided to shed some blood. And there you go, one dropped dead… a fine stalker he was, too! And the other one, Sparrow, beetled off, because I’d be the first one to put a bullet in his head. Find him. I’m sure he’s still in the Zone. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_monster_part_1">
		<text>Достать глаз "плоти"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_monster_part_1_descr">
		<text>Достать глаз "плоти"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_monster_part_1_text">
		<text>Скоро у нас праздник, и будет праздничный ужин, а некоторые местные гурманы в особо приподнятом настроении (не будем показывать пальцем) обязательно захотят попробовать мое коронное блюдо - глаза "плоти" под свинным соусом. То есть, в собственном соку под майонезом. В общем, нужен глаз этой твари, и поскорее.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_monster_part_2">
		<text>Принести копыто кабана</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_monster_part_2_descr">
		<text>Принести копыто кабана</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barmen_monster_part_2_text">
		<text>Знаешь, что мы заготовляем рога и копыта? Это сейчас большая редкость. Из местных мутированных копыт делают отличные украшения, я знаю одного ювелира, он заинтересован. Так что вперед, найди копыто кабана, и тебе в карман денег прибудет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1">
		<text>Защитить заставу Долга</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1_descr">
		<text>Защитить заставу Долга на Свалке.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1_text">
		<text>Значит так, ты наверняка встречал наших ребят на Свалке. Они там что-то вроде внешнего кордона, защищают бар от мутантов, прущих из темной долины. Пришла информация, что большая стая кабанов как раз приближается к ним. Помоги им отбить волну мутантов, за мной не заржавеет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1">
		<text>Уничтожить зомби</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
		<text>На Янтаре уничтожить зомбированых долговцев.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1_text">
		<text>Недавно мы посылали группу на Янтарь, к сожалению, никто из группы не вернулся. Мне доложили, что недалеко от мобильной лаборатории ученых на Янтаре видели несколько зомбированых сталкеров из группы. Мы не можем допустить, чтобы они оставались в этом ужасном состоянии. Твое задание: найти и уничтожить то, во что они превратились.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10">
		<text>Убрать стаю собак</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10_descr">
		<text>Убрать стаю собак на Свалке.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10_text">
		<text>Мы, конечно, не поручаем заданий чужим сталкерам. С другой стороны, эта задача проста, так что гонять наших ребят никакого смысла нет. Так, слушай. Надо зачистить небольшое логово тварей на Свалке. Одна наша группа там уже работает, потому в случае неприятностей есть куда отступить. С другой стороны, желательно, чтобы неприятностей не было, потому что тварей там немного - не больше десятка. Скорее всего, собаки: недавно была замечена миграция достаточно большой стаи в этом районе. Можешь приступать к выполнению задания.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11">
		<text>Уничтожить лагерь сталкеров</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить лагерь сталкеров на "Агропроме".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11_text">
		<text>Есть одно деликатное дело, но наших парней к его выполнению привлекать никак нельзя. Нашим союзникам невыгодно присутствие нейтралов на заводе при "Агропроме". Задача такая: освободить промзону от присутствия на ней сталкеров, кем бы они ни были и к каким бы группировкам ни принадлежали. Всё ясно?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12">
		<text>Уничтожить отряд наемников</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить отряд наемников на "Ростке".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12_text">
		<text>Значит, задача вот какая: нужно уничтожить отряд снайперов группировки наёмников. Обстановка: снайперы эти удерживают верхний этаж строительного комплекса. Предположительное количество - не менее двух, не более пяти. Вооружены, судя по всему, снайперскими винтовками Драгунова. Совет: днём к ним не суйся.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13">
		<text>Зачистить базу бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13_descr">
		<text>Зачистить основную базу бандитов в Тёмной долине.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13_text">
		<text>Необходимо совершить рейд на основную базу бандитов и уничтожить максимальное количество живой силы противника. Это в Тёмной долине, там, где недостроенный научный центр. Численность противника: около тридцати боевиков; вооружены лёгким автоматическим оружием, пистолетами, дробовиками. Всё ясно?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14">
		<text>Зачистить cнорков</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14_descr">
		<text>Зачистить тоннели от снорков в секторе "Янтарь".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14_text">
		<text>В этот раз придётся заняться зачисткой. Тоннели в секторе "Янтарь" просто ломятся от снорков: их там приблизительно около десятка. Да, теперь там от грозы не отсидишься, как раньше…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2">
		<text>Уничтожить стаю плотей</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить стаю плотей на "Дикой територии".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2_text">
		<text>Мы зафиксировали перемещение большой стаи тварей... Весьма гадкие свиноподобные мутанты, которых все называют плотями. Сейчас они в районе свалки. У нас все люди заняты, но этих тварей нужно уничтожить. Работа специфическая, мы заплатим.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3">
		<text>Уничтожить псевдособак</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3_descr">
		<text>Зачистить логово псевдособак возле военных складов.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3_text">
		<text>Наши союзники сообщили об обнаружении логова монстров на територии возле военных складов. Предположительно стая псевдособак. Нам сейчас там шуметь не к чему, так что это задание для нейтрала. Берешься?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4">
		<text>Уничтожить заставу наемников</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4_descr">
		<text>Недалеко от военных складов уничтожить заставу наемников.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4_text">
		<text>Последнее время увеличилась активность групп наемников, совершено несколько нападений на ученых, иследователей зоны. Безнаказаным это оставлять нельзя. Нужно совершить небольшую карательную операцию. Объект - застава наемников возле военных складов, за заброшеной деревней.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5">
		<text>Уничтожить наемников на "Дикой территории"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить наемников на "Дикой территории".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5_text">
		<text>Группа ученых собирается провести исследования "Дикой территории". Но там последнее время небезопасно, активизировались наемники. Проследи, чтобы наемников больше не было на "Дикой территории".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6">
		<text>Убить бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6_descr">
		<text>Убить бандитов, проникших на "Дикую территорию".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6_text">
		<text>Буду краток. Бандиты обошли наши заставы на Баре и сейчас находятся на "Дикой территории". Их надо устранить.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7">
		<text>Уничтожить контролера</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить контролера на Янтаре.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7_text">
		<text>Для выполнения этого задания необходимо обладать специальными навыками. Ученые сообщили нам, что на Янтаре возле входа в подземную лабораторию (в центральном здании) ими был замечен контролер. Контролеры очень опасны, но я уверен что ты справишься.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8">
		<text>Зачистить свободовцев</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8_descr">
		<text>Зачистить заброшеную деревню недалеко от военных складов от присутствия свободовцев.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8_text">
		<text>В заброшеной деревне возле военных складов повысилась активность патрулей Свободы. Зачисти деревню от боевиков. После выполнения тебя ждет особое вознаграждение.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9">
		<text>Уничтожить бандитов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9_descr">
		<text>Уничтожить бандитов на Свалке.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9_text">
		<text>Оперативная обстановка неблагоприятная, бандиты концентрируются в районе Свалки и Темной долины. Лучшим решением будет одновременно нанести два упреждающих удара! Долиной займутся наши боевики, тебе достанется Свалка.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_find_item_1">
		<text>Find the suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_find_item_1_descr">
		<text>Find the Enchanted suit by the warehouses in the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_find_item_1_text">
		<text>There’s an off the record mission, stalker. My friend’s birthday is coming up, and I’d like to surprise him with a neat present. We’ve gone through many things together… I hear there’s an Enchanted suit by the storehouse in the deserted village. Silly name, but that’s the name it goes by, so we’ll stick to it. In short, try to get hold of it. But remember: the village is not a safe place, so be on your guard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1">
		<text>Neutralize Cap</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1_descr">
		<text>Neutralize Cap, head of the Freedom faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1_text">
		<text>Listen closely. This is a tough mission. A man nicknamed Cap needs to be neutralized. He's the Freedom leader. Currently the troops under his command are holding positions at the border line with Radar. Target neutralization will wear down the cordon between Radar and Freedom’s main base. Consequence: elimination of the whole enemy gang by the penetration of Monolith and hordes of monsters. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item">
		<text>Найти оружие Долговца.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item_descr">
		<text>Долговец просит найти его оружие, он потерял его где-то в Темной долине, во время очередной вылазки.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item_text">
		<text>Ну надо же было так облажаться. Что же это зона делает с мозгами. Вроде же нервы крепкие, никогда ничего не боялся, а тут такое. Все этот вой в ушах стоит. Все же шло как и обычно. Была вылазка темную долину, сели с Кривым в засаде прикрывать основную группу, а тут как услышал вой, такой ужас охватил. Блин, я даже не помню оказался на кордоне. Когда вернулся на базу, Воронин чуть не расстрелял на месте: он мне как раз выдал пушку улучшенную, за хорошую службу так сказать. А тут… я в панике как деру дал, так видимо ее там и оставил. Если бы ты смог ее принести мне, а то куда я теперь, без нормального оружия.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1">
		<text>Зачистить логово снорков</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
		<text>На Янтаре уничтожить логово снорков.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1_text">
		<text>Я хочу предложить вам небольшую сумму денег, которую вы получите в том случае, если снорки, обитающие на болотах, перестанут отвлекать меня и мох коллег. Иногда во время экспериментов просто не получается сосредоточиться.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2">
		<text>Уничтожить логово диких собак</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
		<text>На "Дикой территории" зачистить логово собак.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2_text">
		<text>На "Дикой территории" есть логово собак-мутантов, я хочу, чтобы Вы отправились и зачистили его. Эти мутанты опасны для наших экспедиций. Я знаю, зоологи меня не поддержат, но здесь, согласитесь, не зоопарк. Такие твари разносят бешенство, чуму и еще Бог знает что.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1">
		<text>Find the Doughboy artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1_descr">
		<text>Sounds like the poor devil made a run for it, far away from those psychos. So, getting the Doughboy artifact… Now that’s some scavenger hunt. Still, it’s better than working as an assistant for this egghead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1_text">
		<text>I have a rather special request, stalker… I think you’ve already encountered this rather curious artifact called Doughboy and you are aware that somehow it prevents injuries inflicted by the hardest radiation. Unfortunately, after a number of experiments we lost contact with one of our assistants who was with … ehhh… the Doughboy in a high radioactivity area. This is a great loss to all of us. In view of these circumstances, we need another such artifact. By the way, I would be happy if you agreed to work with me as my assistant. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2">
		<text>Find the Mama's Beads artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2_descr">
		<text>So they don’t need the smart and the talented. That’s it, eh. Mama’s Beads slow down the flow of time… alright, we’ll figure it out. As long as one mission doesn’t take three years.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2_text">
		<text>Good news, young man! Together with our colleagues, we worked out a daring plan to reduce the time dedicated to research using the effect of the Mama’s Beads artifact. The artifact, as you know, slows down the flow of time in a limited volume of space. However, we fear it may affect the brain's activity and this particularity cannot possibly be ignored. I would like to ask you to bring back this artifact, because I see that I’m dealing with a strong and enduring man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3">
		<text>Find the Cobweb artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3_descr">
		<text>So now they’re going to make the working class toil away for one shift instead of two: from 4 am till 10 pm. A good stalker with such an artifact could cross half the Zone in a day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3_text">
		<text>Listen, my dear man... We’re now doing a research on "Increasing manpower efficiency and production intensification". In particular, we’re studying the possibility of increasing duration of a working day from eight to eighteen hours. The curious effect of the "Cobweb" artifact, when applied appropriately, endows its owner with tremendous stamina… So, do I have you working on this job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4">
		<text>Find the Battery artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4_descr">
		<text>The artifact is good, no question about that, but the side effect is pretty sad. I’m really sorry for those guys in uniforms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4_text">
		<text>Let me ask you, stalker… are you a patriot? Yes. I see, young man, that I made the right assumption. Listen, I have a very important request. The thing is, and I’m not afraid to say it, we’ve come very close to creating a super-soldier, the foundation of our future army, a great army! The "Battery" artifact has an amazing effect on human body: raises total immunity, speeds up blood coagulability, provides incredible resistance to radioactivity, to say nothing of stamina! Unfortunately, a side effect has also been detected. Wearing the artifact for a day or longer completely suppresses the reproductive function, and we do not know whether this process is reversible. That is why I strongly recommend that you do not abuse this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5">
		<text>Find the Shell artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5_descr">
		<text>I wonder if they did those experiments at the Chernobyl NPP?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5_text">
		<text>Alright, dear stalker. As you've heard, there is a rather curious artifact in the Zone, the Shell. I have to say it matches its name perfectly. The only property that our devices have been able to discover was the complete absorption of any type of energy. This is the property that we would like to examine more thoroughly. To think of the prospects… imagine if a certain number of these artifacts had been installed within the security system of the NPP... Disasters caused by the "peaceful atom" will become history!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_item_1">
		<text>Принести уникальный комбинезон</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_item_1_descr">
		<text>Принести из подземной лаборатории X16 необычный комбинезон.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_find_item_1_text">
		<text>У нас к Вам дело. Мы недавно наняли одного сталкера, чтобы он проник внутрь лаборатории. Еще тогда я заметил его необычный костюм, от него ощутимо отдавало теплом. Сталкер говорил, что этот костюм раны сам заживляет. В общем, сталкер не вернулся из лаборатории. Нет! Вы не подумайте, мы тут не при чем! И костюм его до сих пор, наверное, там лежит. Я бы с удовольствием получил его для изучения.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1">
		<text>Bring the arm of a zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1_descr">
		<text>Holy Moly. These nuts won’t miss a chance to turn us all into zombies… Alright. They need this scum’s arm? We’ve got plenty of this stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1_text">
		<text>Oh, young man! You know, we feel a need for a part of the body of a specific creature. Your colleagues call it a zombie, and I must say, this is not a very successful name for a body that had modified itself so that... Anyway, we need its arm. I have to tell you: our team is working on implanting the extremities of... eh... zombies to those who have lost an arm or a leg for some reason. In addition, further down the line, we intend to use vital organs as well; however, for the time being, this is a purely theoretical issue. So, the arm! Would you be interested, young man?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2">
		<text>Bring the eye of a flesh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2_descr">
		<text>I'd better keep my body away from these eggheads just in case! Very well, I'll get them a flesh's eye, and they can do all they want with their volunteers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2_text">
		<text>Good news, young man: we have a very interesting assignment for you! I think as an intellectual being with quite a bit of experience you will be able to appreciate my colleagues' theories. The thing is, our research revealed: the eyes of the creatures called flesh in the common language, are equipped with... are you following me?... with olfactory receptors! Thus, they can not only see with their eyes, but smell with them as well! We're getting ready for an operation on transplanting this miraculous eye to one of ... one of our voluntary assistants. I believe we're about to start a craze! By the way, would you like to become a recepient of this rather amazing organ?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3">
		<text>Bring the tail of a blind dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3_descr">
		<text>Well, look at Science! Trying to find a second brain in humans?.. Poor dogs, one of them will have to do without a tail now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3_text">
		<text>Good day, dear boy! Listen, would you like to help us once again? I hope you know that dogs belong to the vertebrates subtype... meaning their vertebral column starts with the head and ends with the tail. And here's the catch! One of my young collegues proved theoretically that the spine of the blind dogs - this is how you named this type of animals - starts from the tail, not from the head! Think of it, it totally turns upside down our assumptions pertaining to this area of knowledge. There are already some rather daring theories about human beings having around their sacrum a... well, this is a subject of many discussions. In short, we need the head of the dog, the blind dog, which through ignorance we considered to be its tail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4">
		<text>Bring the leg of a boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4_descr">
		<text>Gourmet thrillseekers… Alright, I'll get them some ham.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4_text">
		<text>Welcome, eh... traveler! I'm so glad you dropped by: we are in need of a man to take part in a highly important experiment. My colleague Brenter wants to try and cook a meal using local fauna for a practical experiment to study the influence of mutated protein on human body. For a start, we decided to try the boars. We need ham. A boar's leg, do you undestand? And if you agree to do it, please select the healthiest specimen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5">
		<text>Bring the foot of a snork'</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5_descr">
		<text>Heal the snorks… speaking of queer eggheads! Alright, at least that will stop these monsters from jumping around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5_text">
		<text>Good news, dear stalker! We've been racking our brain over this one question: what makes snorks literally drift above the ground, crawl up the walls, jump amazing distances... And the solution turned out very simple, young man! Snorks panic at the sight of the ground! They suffer from geophobia! The receptors that developed at the tips of their extremities send a signal of the greatest irritation when in contact with the ground or any more or less horizontal surface. We need a sample of the snork's paw: we'll try to inject a vaccine that may relieve these poor creatures of this unusual disease.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="eliminate_lager">
		<text>Camp elimination.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_item">
		<text>Find the item.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1">
		<text>Защитить сталкеров на Агропроме</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1_descr">
		<text>На Агропроме отбить атаку бандитов на лагерь сталкеров.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1_text">
		<text>Есть группа сталкеров, на Агропроме живут. Нормальные такие ребята, понимают, что Зона - место свободы, что законы тут вообще не применимы, а жить надо просто правильно, по своей морали. И вот они сейчас подумывают, не присоединиться ли к нам, да. Надо помочь им отбиться от бандитов, а? А мы тебе снаряженьица подкинем.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2">
		<text>Защитить барьер</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2_descr">
		<text>Защитить барьер возле армейских складов от монстров.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2_text">
		<text>Тут опять монстры прут со стороны выжигателя. Помоги ребятам на барьере отбиться. Награду гарантирую.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1">
		<text>Destroy the military camp </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
		<text>Destroy the military camp by the Agroprom R&D Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1_text">
		<text>The military are staging a gradual Zone takeover. We need to slow them down, otherwise the Zone will turn into a research zoo. One of the military camps is right by the Agroprom. Even if you don't wipe it out completely, it will at least slow down Zone's takeover by the army.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2">
		<text>Destroy the Merc camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
		<text>Destroy the Merc camp by the warehouses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2_text">
		<text>Listen, here's the deal. The Merc camp needs to be destroyed. We could leave them be, they're good shots... except they've been really asking for it, sneaking into our territory, trying to bribe my people. It's time to teach them a lesson. Can you do it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3">
		<text>Destroy the Duty detachment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
		<text>Destroy the clean-up Duty detachment in Rostok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3_text">
		<text>How 'bout going on a hunt? Duty's clean-up detachment showed up at Rostok. This is a great chance to take them by surprise. Duty keeps sending guys hunting for the monsters, but in the process they don't hesitate to shoot whoever isn't up to their likening. This detachment needs to be finished off before Duty comes to Rostok. There shouldn't be too many people: three or four veterans and a couple of rookies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_4">
		<text>Destroy the Duty outpost</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
		<text>Destroy the Duty outpost at the Dump as soon as possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_4_text">
		<text>There's a very urgent job. The passage from the Dump to the Bar needs to be cleared of the Duty unit... They've taken to hiding there and robbing the passers-by. We're expecting a very important package, but now it must not be ruled out that Duty already know about our courier and will try to waylay him. We need to wipe off this roadblock, even if for a little while. Ok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_5">
		<text>Clear the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
		<text>Clear the village of bloodsuckers and, if possible eliminate the controller.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_5_text">
		<text>Man, will you look at all those bloodsucking monsters swarming in the village! No one gets within a hundred meters of it, except complete dumbheads. And some say they've been seeing things there... a controller is all we need right now! Anyway, it's high time we put an end to it. I'm not forcing you, to tell you the truth I wouldn't go there myself. But if you're not afraid, then my gratitude won't have any bounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_6">
		<text>Уничтожить стаю кабанов и плотей</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
		<text>Возле военных складов уничтожить стаю кабанов и плотей.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_6_text">
		<text>Возле главного входа на базу, сидит наш снайпер. Сидит он себе ночью на вышке... тишина, ночь... и тут, взрыв, дикий визг, вспышка! Что за!... А дело вот в чём - рядом с минным полем повадились бродить кабаны и плоти. Чёрт его знает, чего их туда тянет, но минимум раз в неделю одна из этих тварей на мину нарывается. Задание простое - перебить всех этих существ к ядрёне фене. Сделаешь?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_7">
		<text>Уничтожить стаю тушкано</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_7_descr">
		<text>На "Дикой территории" уничтожить стаю тушкано.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_7_text">
		<text>Вот возле нашей базы нигде нет тушканов, хоть эти твари проникают куда угодно. А ещё недавно их тут было - закачаешься. Два месяца мы с ними разбирались, хе-хе. Ну так вот. Мы вычислили, откуда приходили тушканы к нам на базу. С "Дикой территории", прикинь? Есть такое опасение, что эти крысы прыгающие размножатся, и опять повалят к нам. Нам нужен человек, который сможет с ними разобраться. Пойдешь?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_1">
		<text>Steal the sniper rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_1_descr">
		<text>Steal the modified SVD from the Duty warehouse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_1_text">
		<text>There is a special assignment. And pretty tough, too... So, you'll need to retrieve an improved Dragunov from the Duty warehouse. This piece even has a name of its own, but never mind. The main thing is that with its awesome scope and recoil canceller you can shoot a squirrel in its eye from 400 meters. So, I trust you'll do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_2">
		<text>Obtain the modified Winchester 1300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_2_descr">
		<text>Obtain the modified Winchester 1300 from the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_2_text">
		<text>I hear the eggheads managed to improve the Winchester shotgun by using an artifact. The knockdown power of this thing is the same as a howitzer. So why don't you pay them a visit and see if you can make a bargain. I'll make up for all expenses!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_3">
		<text>Find the bulletproof vest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_3_descr">
		<text>Find a sample of the new bulletproof vest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_find_item_3_text">
		<text>Some of the grunts are sporting a new type of bulletproof vests. The inside lining is soaked in some healing ointment or something like that... anyway, it makes small wounds heal up very fast. If you get one of those, we'll take it apart and make us a bunch ourselves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1">
		<text>Kill Duty's security chief</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1_descr">
		<text>Kill Duty's security chief and try do it as quietly as possible. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1_text">
		<text>It would be well for Duty's security chief to quietly disappear. And when they're in a deep mess, I'll be able to plant a few of my guys in their gang. And then, the devil can pull off any stunt... alright, I better shut up. I suggest you take care of him from a distance, without kicking up a fuss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2">
		<text>Kill Captain Ivantsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2_descr">
		<text>Kill Captain Ivantsov, the closest aide of the Duty leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2_text">
		<text>It's a tough job, I'm warning you right away, but it's worth it. Ivantsov, a close aide of the Duty leader, has been asking for it. He does the dirtiest jobs: punitive operations, raids... If you only knew how many of our guys he's killed off! It's high time we did away with this slimeball. So if you make up your mind to do it, I suggest you get yourself well armed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3">
		<text>Kill Colonel Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3_descr">
		<text>Kill Colonel Petrenko, one of the founders of the Duty faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3_text">
		<text>Colonel Petrenko... I don't know if you've heard the name or met him, but it would be good for the two of you to meet. This man is one of the Duty founders and one of our worst enemies. Try to make sure your conversation ends as fast as possible... for him. Can you handle that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4">
		<text>Kill the Duty leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4_descr">
		<text>Kill the Duty leader to throw the gang into chaos.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4_text">
		<text>I really don't know how to put it... Anyway, it's time. It's time to finish off General Voronin. Certainly, taking down a Duty leader will be quite a job to do. But if you get him, you'll put an end to the bloodshed between Duty and us. After such a blow, Duty won't recover for a long time, if at all. Send him to the place he deserves. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5">
		<text>Kill a Duty bigwig </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5_descr">
		<text>Kill one of Duty bosses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5_text">
		<text>I'll pay for the head of any Duty leader! Knock one off and come back for reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6">
		<text>Kill the stalker called Scarecrow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6_descr">
		<text>Eliminate stalker Scarecrow, an excessively zealous mutant hunter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6_text">
		<text>We eliminate monsters, except for us it's a matter of survival, not profit. Mutant populations are not as numerous; besides, they're living beings too, so we can't permit their annihilation. Some individuals refuse to understand it. An apt illustration is the stalker called Scarecrow. He got his nickname for a reason, selling stuffed mutants. We've warned him before, but all for nothing. So can you do a good deed for Greenpeace?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7">
		<text>Kill the stalker called Barin. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7_descr">
		<text>Kill the stalker called Barin, chief quartermaster of the Duty faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7_text">
		<text>A cad, bootlicker, hypocrite and coward... that's stalker Barin for you. As you can see, a man with a marvellous character, which helped him get to the top of Duty. Currently supplies the faction with supplies and foodstuff, though he takes part in raids from time to time. We need to get rid of him, especially since all the clues regarding Duty logistics lead to Barin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_monster_part_1">
		<text>Bring a boar's leg</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_monster_part_1_descr">
		<text>Bring a boar's leg to the dinner party in honor of Bob Marley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom_monster_part_1_text">
		<text>We're planning a dinner party to celebrate Bob Marley's birthday. So why don't you get us some delicious ham? The more the better! Jah will never forget you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager">
		<text>Уничтожить логово кровососа.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager_descr">
		<text>Охотник просит зачистить логово кровососа в деревне возле военных складов, в награду обещает редкий артефакт.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager_text">
		<text>Ты кровососа встречал? Жуть, правда? А я вот давеча пошел в деревню возле военных складов, думал артефактами разжиться. И представь себе – вижу кровососа, черного такого, весь в рубцах. Сидит над трупом, меня не видит. Я испугался, и как дал оттуда деру… Зря я побежал, он меня услыхал и давай за мной, и сразу вой такой поднялся вокруг… тут я и понял что он не один был. Думаю логово у них там. Если бы ты смог прогнать их оттуда, я бы тебе отдал один редкий артефакт, который пару дней назад нашел.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_stalker">
		<text>Kill the stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker">
		<text>Убить предателя.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker_descr">
		<text>Лысый просит убить одного сталкера, который смылся с очень редкими артефактами.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker_text">
		<text>Я недавно с одним сталкером за артефактами ходил, около самого выжигателя искали. Столько всего нашли, даже нашли пару артефактов, которых я вообще еще никогда не видел, даже на фотографиях. Так вот этот сукин сын меня подставил. На последней ночевке куда то слинял и заныкал самые дорогие артефакты. И еще мне втирал что типа они сами исчезли. А пару дней назад увидел один тот самый редкий артефакт у бармена. И такая злость меня взяла…. Вообщем сталкер, если сможешь найти его – передай ему от меня свинцовый привет. А может заодно узнаешь где у него тайники и найдешь второй артефакт. Он того стоит, поверь мне.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mercenary_kill_stalker">
		<text>Убить сталкера мастера.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mercenary_kill_stalker_descr">
		<text>За убийство каждого мастера, наемник готов хорошо платить. Чем меньше мастеров, тем легче наемникам.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mercenary_kill_stalker_text">
		<text>Мы не заинтересованы в том, чтобы в Зоне бродили ходячие танки: вооруженные до зубов сталкеры в экзосклетах. Работа от этого становится только сложнее и опаснее. И чем их меньше – тем нам лучше. Убьеш одного такого – получить награду.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monster_part">
		<text>Get a part of a monster body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker">
		<text>Уничтожить сталкера Свободы.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker_descr">
		<text>Один сталкер, бывший долговец, который знал много информации о важных объектах на Припяти, недавно переметнулся на сторону Свободы, нужно убить его, пока он не наболтал лишнего.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker_text">
		<text>Слушай сюда. Есть у нас карты Припяти, не современные, а старые, военные, сделанные в начале девяностых. Самое главное на них – это обозначения всех военных объектов: подземные склады, бомбоубежища. Сейчас от этого пользы мало конечно, но если вдруг мы найдем дорогу в Припять – эта информация станет бесценна. Проблема вот в чем. Один из офицеров переметнулся к Свободе, и он знал об этой информации. Вообщем надо его уничтожить, пока не наболтал лишнего.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="return_for_reward">
		<text>Come back for the reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="return_for_reward_bring">
		<text>Bring the customer what's been promised.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_find_item">
		<text>Найти усовершенствованный костюм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_find_item_descr">
		<text>Шустрый рассказал о схроне бандитов, в котором они прятали хабар. Просит принести навороченный костюмчик, за награду, разумеется.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="shustriy_find_item_text">
		<text>Пока сидел в плену, слышал что бандиты говорли об их тайнике, где они хабар складывают. Слышал что они куртку там клевую спрятали, и что на следующий день их тайник для себя какой-то монстр облюбовал. Да так облюбовал, что они теперь ходить туда бояться. Принеси мне костюмчик, будь другом, а я уж с тобой рассчитаюсь.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_barman_has_no_job">
		<text>I can't offer anything at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_barman_job_ask">
		<text>And what do you want to talk about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_barman_job_complete">
		<text>Great job, award well deserved!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_barman_job_what">
		<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_barman_list_job">
		<text>Look what we've got now:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_defend_camp_1">
		<text>Прикрыть отряд Долга от атаки бандитов в Тёмной Долине</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_defend_camp_1_descr">
		<text>Прикрыть отряд Долга от атаки бандитов в Тёмной Долине</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_defend_camp_1_text">
		<text>Всё-таки наконец-то удалось мне вдолбить в тупые головы долговцев, что давно уж пора зачистить Свалку от бандитов... И Долг свою территорию расширит, и мне постоянных клиентов реже портить будут. Ну, в общем, дело в том, что командование Долга решило для начала отсечь приток бандитов из Тёмной Долины. Выслали, они, значит, отряд заграждения, и обнаружили, что бандиты этому не рады. Кто бы мог подумать! Так к чему это я - помог бы ты бойцам закрепиться у входа в Долину, а? Отблагодарю достойно.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_dolg_has_no_job">
		<text>There are no jobs available right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_dolg_job_ask">
		<text>What do you want to discuss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_dolg_job_complete">
		<text>Good boy! Job well done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_dolg_job_what">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_dolg_list_job">
		<text>Here's the job update:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_ecolog_has_no_job">
		<text>Sorry, but we don't have any jobs at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_ecolog_job_ask">
		<text>What is the job you would like to talk about? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_ecolog_job_complete">
		<text>You did a great job! Allow me to present you with your reward. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_ecolog_job_what">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_ecolog_list_job">
		<text>Here's what I can offer: </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1">
		<text>Destroy the bandit camp at the Dump.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
		<text>Eliminate the bandits at the Dump who rob stalkers on the way back from the Zone. The trader will be happy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1_text">
		<text>The bandits have rallied lately, getting in the way of honest people trading... So make a beeline for the Dump, I've been told these scumbags have settled down near the scrapyard. You look into this matter, and everyone will be grateful to you, and I'll be generous with the reward. Agreed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2">
		<text>Destroy the bandit camp at the bus station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
		<text>Eliminate the bandits at the factory. Apparently, they're new to the Zone, so the job is gonna be easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2_text">
		<text>The bandits have been hanging around the bus station again. So did you guess already what the job is about? Well then… jump to it! Pass our warmest greetings to them and come back, I'll thank you then. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3">
		<text>Eliminate the bandits by the Agroprom R&D Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
		<text>Eliminate the bandits by the Agroprom R&D Institute. Better stay on friendly terms with the trader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3_text">
		<text>Some bandits turned up by the Agroprom R&D Institute. They're disturbing my diggers when they sort through the rubbish. You solve the problem, I'll owe you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4">
		<text>Зачистить местность от мутантов.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
		<text>Зачистить местность от мутантов.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4_text">
		<text>Дело есть, не очень тяжелое. Тут ко мне тут туриста иностранного привезти хотят. Он деньжат моим корешам подкинул, чтоб на зону посмотреть. Ну и там где водить его будут, надо почистить район от мутантов. Возьмешься?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5">
		<text>Устранить двух бандитов на Свалке.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
		<text>Сделать проход в одно из лучших мест Зоны свободным</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5_text">
		<text>Недавно одно из лучших мест Зоны стало недоступным для любителей прекрасного. На Свалке... Угу, именно на Свалке есть закуток, вроде ничего такого, но тебя покидают все печали, в котором ты забываешь о грязи, о деньгах, о крови... Точнее забывал. Потому что теперь там сидят два грязных урода, которые грозятся пустить кровь каждому, кто не заплатит им за посещение этого края. Устрани их, мне туристов водить некуда.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6">
		<text>Убить кровососа в Темной долине.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
		<text>Убить кровососа в Темной долине</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6_text">
		<text>Говорят, что военные ушли из Темной долины. А после изо всех щелей попёрли монстры. Сталкеры уже видели там кровососа, причём необычного - он не боится открытых пространств. В общем, когда слух докатится до учёных - они обязательно захотят исследовать этого кровососа. И я хочу быть тем человеком, который продаст ученным труп. Твоя задача - убить кровососа, а дальше я все беру на себя.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_1">
		<text>Find the Jellyfish artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_1_descr">
		<text>Find the Jellyfish artifact formed in the Springboard anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_1_text">
		<text>Some guy from the Big Land asked for a Jellyfish. It's not a lot of money, but it's a milk run. Take it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_2">
		<text>Find the Stone Flower artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_2_descr">
		<text>Find the Stone Flower artifact formed in the Springboard anomaly. The pay is supposed to be pretty good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_2_text">
		<text>I have a request for the Stone Flower. The order is from the jewellers, by the way, so let's try to make the pretty ladies happy, eh? If you get it, you'll get the money and a bottle to drink to their health…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_3">
		<text>Find the Night Star artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_3_descr">
		<text>Find the Night Star, a rare and expensive artifact. So what if the request comes from the military! Who cares? Money does not smell…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_3_text">
		<text>There is this one little job... rather unpleasant. Apparently, it's coming from the military, they're working on some new protection. Anyway, there's an order for the Night Star. It's quite a rare artifact, but it provides pretty good protection from bullets... So will you do it? I'll pay you well! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_4">
		<text>Найти артефакт "Ломоть мяса"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_4_descr">
		<text>Найти заживляющий раны артефакт "Ломоть мяса"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_artefact_4_text">
		<text>Есть заказ на артефакт, нужен такой чтоб раны лечить мог, называеться "Ломоть мяса"! Клиника у них вроде какая то. Достанешь - и сам денег получишь и людям поможешь.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_item_1">
		<text>Find the unique suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_item_1_descr">
		<text>Find a unique suit with some astonishing properties. And as the offered amount suggests, asking the bandits politely for it will not be sufficient.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_find_item_1_text">
		<text>I heard that the bandits got hold of a rather curious suit. They say the loser that thought of bringing it to the Zone got caught in an anomaly... the Witches' Jelly was it? Nevermind. It seems that the suit acquired some rather uncommon properties after being exposed to the anomaly. If you bring it to me, I'll make sure you get more than your fair share. So what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_freedom_has_no_job">
		<text>There's no job right now, really…</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_freedom_job_ask">
		<text>So what is it that you want to discuss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_freedom_job_complete">
		<text>Here's a fine young man! Excellent job, here's your money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_freedom_job_what">
		<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_freedom_list_job">
		<text>Here's what I've got:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_hunter_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_hunter_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_hunter_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_hunter_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_hunter_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_job_nothing">
		<text>It's alright. Some other time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_job_refuse">
		<text>I refuse to do this job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1">
		<text>Kill the bandit leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1_descr">
		<text>Kill the bandit leader who crossed the trader. Most likely he won't be alone... Tough job, but the pay covers it all. The Dark Valley is the place to look for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1_text">
		<text>You'll have to finish off this one dandy, one of the bandit leaders. The other day the bandits, by his order, intercepted my courier and shook him up and I don't waste words with those who touch my people... In a word, if you get it done, I'll return the favor. So are you up for it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2">
		<text>Kill the trader stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2_descr">
		<text>Kill a stalker… Well, that's not the best job, lifting a hand against a fellow worker. But the pay is pretty good, and this may be what matters the most.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2_text">
		<text>I'm having a confrontation with this one trader. Well, if he doesn't want to cooperate, the hell with him! But I won't let anyone start filthy rumors. In short, he needs to be wasted so the others don't get out of hand. Let them all know who's the boss here... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3">
		<text>Kill the rookie stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3_descr">
		<text>Finish off a rookie stalker, who may not be a rookie at all… Then who is he? Ah, who cares! As long as the job's not messy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3_text">
		<text>There's this one guy here loafing about, pretending to be a rookie, but he's rather weird… So anyway, if he suddenly disappears, you'll be doing me a great favor. You know what I mean? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4">
		<text>Kill the stalker called Fiend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4_descr">
		<text>Eliminate one of the trader Sidorovich's rivals, a stalker called Fiend. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4_text">
		<text>The Fiend, aka Oleg Gusarov... used to serve in Spetsnaz. As long as he minded his own business, I had nothing against him, a loner is a loner. But I hear he's mustering a gang to crush down the cordon and take control over smuggling operations from the Zone. Now this is a major problem and it has to be solved quick. So will you do it? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5">
		<text>Kill Father Diodor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5_descr">
		<text>To kill a man preaching in the Zone against gathering and selling artifacts? Exactly. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5_text">
		<text>I always said business and religion can't go together, they can never cross, and should never ever meddle in the other's affairs! It's just this padre, Lord forgive me, Diodor... well... he just can't see this simple truth. He keeps raving about artifact hunting, says that trading in them drives people to sin not just in the Zone, but in the whole world, on and on along those lines. Get this, he preaches the destruction of artifacts altogether!! See what he is up to? The worst bit is that he's actually got some converts! I've tried to approach this Diodor this way and other, but he just keeps at it. Here's the deal: you're going to send him upstairs wher he can preach all he likes... you get the point, right? And I'll give you a cool artifact. So, we've got a deal? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6">
		<text>Убить "торгового представителя"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6_descr">
		<text>Убить "торгового представителя". Торговец следит за своей репутацией</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6_text">
		<text>Прикинь, тут недалеко крутится какой-то чудак, который представляется моим торговым представителем, пользуется, значит, моей репутацией, а потом толкает некондиционку! Сломанные стволы, разваливающуюся броню, просроченые консервы... У меня тут уже было пару разборок с недовольными. Короче, мне нужен человек, который пообщается с "торговым представителем". Вплоть до некондиции.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_lisiy_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_lisiy_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_lisiy_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_lisiy_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_lisiy_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_Mercenary_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_Mercenary_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_Mercenary_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_Mercenary_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_Mercenary_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_monster_part_1">
		<text>Принести челюсть кровососа</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_monster_part_1_descr">
		<text>Зуб кровососа притягивает удачу? Посмотрим повезет ли кровососу</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_monster_part_1_text">
		<text>Слышал поверье, что зуб кровососа притягивает удачу? Будто бы того, кто на шее носит такой зуб, аномалии отпускают, и артефакты сами в руки идут? В общем, это всё фигня, но есть болваны, которые верят и готовы платить хорошие деньги. Принесешь челюсть кровососа, я тебе хорошо заплачу.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_monster_part_2">
		<text>Притащить хвост псевдособаки</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_monster_part_2_descr">
		<text>Притащить хвост псевдособаки</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_monster_part_2_text">
		<text>Зима скоро. А что зимой там, на большой земле, бабы носить любят? Правильно! Меха носить они любят. Вот и пошла мода новая, из хвостов псевдо собак аксессуары всякие делать. Шерсть там какая то особенная! Короче, есть заказ на такой хвост. Возьмешься?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_petrenko_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_petrenko_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_petrenko_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_petrenko_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_petrenko_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_reward_job">
		<text>I'm here for the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_seek_job_abandon">
		<text>I'm not interested in that kind of jobs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_seek_job_no">
		<text>Some other time. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_seek_job_yes">
		<text>I'm up for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_seek_new_job">
		<text>I need a job. Do you have something for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_trader_has_no_job">
		<text>There's no job right now. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_trader_job_ask">
		<text>What job do you want to talk about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_trader_job_complete">
		<text>Job done… and here's the reward!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_trader_job_what">
		<text>What about the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_trader_list_job">
		<text>Here's something to do:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_shustriy_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_shustriy_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_shustriy_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорарчик!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_shustriy_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_shustriy_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_wolf_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_wolf_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_wolf_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_wolf_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_wolf_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_zastava_commander_has_no_job">
		<text>На данный момент ничего нет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_ask">
		<text>Насчёт какого задания ты хочешь поговорить?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_complete">
		<text>Задание выполнено... а вот и гонорар!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_what">
		<text>И что там с заданием?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tm_zastava_commander_list_job">
		<text>Есть кое-что:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1">
		<text>Уничтожить логово кабанов</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
		<text>Кабаны устроили догово, аккурат рядом с тем местом, где Волк с другом схрон сделали. Волк просит зачистить логово, обещал щедро наградить.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1_text">
		<text>Это, у нас с другом схрон тут недалеко был, аккурат за АТП, там еще деревья погуще растут, то что надо короче. Так вот там недавно кабаны логово себе устроили. И получается что до схрона нам теперь не добраться. Помоги - убей кабанов, а я тебя отблагодарю, и за себя, и за друга.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2">
		<text>Уничтожить мутантов на ферме</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
		<text>Волк просит зачистить ферму от мутантов, хочет организовать там перевалочный лагерь.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2_text">
		<text>Тут хоть и граница Зоны, но новичкам и здесь несладко. Бандиты то еще пол-беды, они хоть русский язык понимают. А вот мутанты - с ними совсем худо. Устроили себе логово на заброшенной ферме, единственное хорошее место для перевалочного лагеря заняли. Если сможешь очистить ферму от мутантов - с меня причитается.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager">
		<text>Зачистить логово собак</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager_descr">
		<text>Возле Южной заставы на Баре обосновалась стая собак. Начальник заставы просит зачистить логово, обещал наградить.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager_text">
		<text>Несмотря на наши усилия некоторые монстры все таки прорываются со стороны Свалки. Да ты наверное и сам видел стаю собак к югу от нас. Убьешь их – получишь награду.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
