<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_1">
        <text>This is the road inside the Zone. Trader can be found in the cellar beyond the village near the army post. I donТt advise you to poke your nose in the army post, cos soldiers are directed to fire on sightЕ Killing soldiers isnТt allowed, only if worst comes to worst, trader will pay off on his own and he wonТt be satisfied with that. Packs of blind dogs on the plains, perilously for the newbies. Mutants visit it now and then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_2">
        <text>And what is further to the north?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_21">
        <text>Dump is there. Gloomy place. Garbage even makes it impassable in some areas.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_attack_0">
        <text>LetТs go and smash some gangster muzzles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_121">
        <text>So what? We are damn ready to fight.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_2">
        <text>And you stalker, where did you pop up from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_22">
        <text>I popped up from Wolf here. He sends you his best regards from hell. Provided you know what I'm talking about.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_222">
        <text>We are in the picture.What's needed?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_2222">
        <text>Wolf sent me to reinforce you. We're gonna assault.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_22222">
        <text>Right now?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_222222">
        <text>Yep. Go attacking.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_222223">
        <text>A bit later. Let you know when.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_3">
        <text>A pretty good shooting session it was. Hopefully this will leave Wolf satisfied.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_0">
        <text>Now, gentlemen, what would you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_1">
        <text>All standing. Bandits are still at the ruins. Few people plus sentry on the first floor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_11">
        <text>I suggest attacking the factory altogether.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_111">
        <text>No way we will have felt this on our own skins. But donТt think that weТre afraid of. We arenТt scared at all. Unless occasionallyЕ maybe itТs a bit scary nowЕ well, okay, we are afraid. And wonТt you be afraid of soberly penetrating the factory with the dug in bandits inside? And that sniper there. IТd say that vodka can encourage us, in other way itТs impossible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_112">
        <text>Oh, I see that youТve brought Уfire-waterФ. Well if it continues as it is, weТll not only drive all the bandits away from the factory, but even clear the whole Zone! So, attack?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_1121">
        <text>Well, IТll tell you when. Now take this bottle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_1122">
        <text>Wait a second. УFire-waterФ isnТt for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_12">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_2">
        <text>Ready and waiting. You just give an order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_21">
        <text>Well, fellows! LetТs kick arses! Assault!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_22">
        <text>So be it! IТll return in a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_11">
        <text>At last Wolf has sent help! Okay, listen, weТre going to knock bandits out of the factory, but the 2nd floor is ocupated by one prudent goggleeyed bastard and looks right into our direction. Silence wonТt make any good there. Your task Ц to insensibly infiltrate the factory and give him a beat. As soon as we notice him missing, weТll force our way in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_111">
        <text>Clear. IТm gonna lay him down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_112">
        <text>Maybe it would be better to attack the factory all together?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_1121">
        <text>You chicken out, arenТt you? Me too, IТm not for so long in Zone as well, if you wanna stay alive itТs better not to show yourself. Vodka should be good here, for bravery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_11211">
        <text>Ah, I wish I had vodka now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_112111">
        <text>Perhaps you should visit trader then? If you donТt want to make a silent assault.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_1121111">
        <text>Fine. IТll be back soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_11212">
        <text>IТve got vodka, here take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_112121">
        <text>GoodЕ WellЕ hicЕ lets move out! Stay asideЕ donТt panic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_1121211">
        <text>Lets kick asses!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_113">
        <text>I have to think about it, and look aroundЕ well, you understand. IТll catch up with ya latter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_12">
        <text>Well, have you thought it out? Able to take off that basterd from the 2nd floor? No other chances to approach, I think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_0">
        <text>I got a few questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_1">
        <text>Shoot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_2">
        <text>Fox, tell me where you have been in the Zone. What did you see?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_21">
        <text>Such a story may take a few days to tell, and my time costs a lot. Can only give you a piece of advice. "Dump" Ц located 3 kilometers to the North from where I stand, where all the radioactive trash had been taken to from stations in 86th. Heavy radiation, host of anomalies, and ultimately Ц abundance of artifacts, admittedly not valuable. Beware of the bandits and try not to swear at УDutyФ patrols. Scientific research institute УAgropromФ is to the west from the УDumpФ. Region is quite poor regarding the artifacts, so I donТt go there often. УDark ValleyФ to the east. Sort of weird place. Like itТs rather quiet in there, but bandits and stuff can now and then be met. Yet I sense that not everything is so simple there as it seems. Further beyond the Dump is УRostokФ factory territory Ц stalkership heart. Besides many experienced guys you can come across with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_211">
        <text>What do one have to beware of in these lands?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_2111">
        <text>Hey, Branded One, you look like an experienced guy, but for such foolish questions. Be wary of everything! This is the bloody Zone, canТt you see?! However bloodsuckers appeared at the night on the Dump, they havenТt been seen so far away from the center. Eerie vermins. ItТs quite hard to see them during the day, if not to mention the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_3">
        <text>The Dealer said you may know something about the Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_31">
        <text>Many have been interested in him recently. Truthfully I donТt know him personally. But I do have err.. УcontactФ experience. His grouping has once fired upon my boys. No one was hurt Ц theyТve been probably waiting for the other ones, thus I consider it to me a misunderstanding. Fouled each other over the ravine and left. O, by the way, Grey is waiting for me at the garage at the Dump, IТll send you the coordinates, chat with him. He knows a lot more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flash_dialog_0">
        <text>IТm from the dealer, you have to hand something to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flash_dialog_1">
        <text>Take it, and try not to lose. Important information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_hello_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, IТm waiting for a man here, so youТd better to get out of here sooner the better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_hello_dialog_3">
        <text>Hi.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_0">
        <text>Why canТt I get into the camp?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_1">
        <text>One has to be a total dunce to let a man from the Уdeath truckФ in. First prove that you can be trusted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_11">
        <text>WhatТs the Уdeath truckФ? I canТt remember anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_111">
        <text>I know few, but this few is something really really bad. Ultimately talking on this topic, especially with you, is not what IТm gonna do. Call it superstition if you wish. So begone, Marked, in an amicable way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_12">
        <text>What must I do to make you believe me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_121">
        <text>The trader must examine you, and weТll just get acquainted. If you are a normal one, donТt grip the gun naively and generally familiar with your reason, weТll find common language.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_guard_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Marked, stop, there is no way for you to the camp now!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_guard_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Hi, Marked. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_hello_0">
        <text>Greetings. Wish to sell something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_0">
        <text>You are familiar with majority here. What has this crowd gathered here for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_1">
        <text>Yeah, itТs hard to say unambiguously, from doctors of science to laid-back bandits. Everyone receives the task to its wit. Militaries usually guard the perimeter, rarely entering the Zone. Bandits are settled on the stalkersТ paths. May bereave of bribe or even life. Scientists are set somewhere deep inside it, searching for the bloody truth, idiots! There are several stalkersТ clans, but thatТs another matter. People here in the camp are rather quiet and peaceful this is understood Ц freshly, anxious newbies. Unless the УWolfФ is familiar in here. This one has seen a lot, but to my mind heТs a bit freaky with stalkership and all, he wants to cut off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_2">
        <text>YouТve mentioned some stalkersТ clans. Can you give more specified information?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_21">
        <text>You see, itТs really hard to survive in the Zone by yourself. So such clans are gathering here and there. Some for convictions, some for money. But there are lots of free stalkers, as I am. Everyone is free to chose: join someone or act alone on own hazard and fear. Concerning groupings I can give roundup on the УDutyФ, УMercenariesФ and УMonolithФ</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_3">
        <text>Concerning the bandits. Why not to perish them once and for all? Admittedly everyone has weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_31">
        <text>Well, generally weТre trying to do that. But if ones are shot, another come.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_4">
        <text>Tell me about the УDutyФ grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_41">
        <text>These consider themselves to be Zone hags. They think that the Zone is the malignant growth on the Earth body, and going to clear the Earth from the Zone and its inhabitants, havenТt yet decided how indeed. Thus shot all the mutants without distinction.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_5">
        <text>Tell me about the УMercanariesФ grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_51">
        <text>Generally those have gathered there are not satisfied by the war in the Уouter worldФ. Extreme Zone conditions shooting enthusiasts. Ready to fulfil any, even the most dirty work. Well equipped, by occidental weapons in majority.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_6">
        <text>Tell me about the УMonolithФ grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_61">
        <text>Why theyТre kind of strange ones. DonТt gather artifacts. DonТt make any liaisons. DonТt trade. Believe in some crap like aliens and evolutional module inside the center of the zone, which shall change the civilization on the earth for good. But these are rumors. I havenТt had personal contacts with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_611">
        <text>And do you yourself believe in something? WhatТs in the center of Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_6111">
        <text>I believe that even the most intimate dreams are granted in the center of the Zone. But I donТt have a clue whatТs in there. I trust that some day I will be able to make it there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_novice_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hi, Marked. How can I be useful?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_novice_start_dialog_3">
        <text>How did you get here!? You mustnТt be at the camp!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_dynamite_done_0">
        <text>Take this present. Sorry that it isnТt packed properly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_dynamite_done_1">
        <text>Hehe. Thanks. My compliments with splendid fireworks. Take the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_hello_11">
        <text>Well, hi. Whatcha want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_hello_12">
        <text>Hello. I was told that you had saved one of ours from mere death. Thanks, man. Take this artifact as the sign of our gratitude. You can exchange it at TraderТs on weapons, shell or food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_hello_13">
        <text>How did you pass the guards!? You canТt go inside the camp, Marked! Leave, while youТre alive!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_0">
        <text>Got a few questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_1">
        <text>Shoot. IТll do my best to help ya.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2">
        <text>What do you know about the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_21">
        <text>Well, quite a lot. What do you particularly need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_211">
        <text>WhatТs inside the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2111">
        <text>This is the very question, which I wanted to find the answer to last two years. But the safe path to the center of the Zone hasnТt been found yet. Several times I tried to break through with my friends. I have hardly made it to return, my friends havenТt. If you ask how we got there, IТll tell ya that we were seeking for the dream, for the wish master.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_21111">
        <text>Why do you think that the dreams are to come true there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_211111">
        <text>There is a stalkersТ legend of the Уwish masterФ. A place located in the center of the Zone, where all, even the most incredible, wishes come true. But you know what IТll tell ya, I do know that there is the mere death in the center of the Zone, and that УmasterФ is noteworthy. So, donТt run risks in vain.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_212">
        <text>Where has the Zone come from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2121">
        <text>Well, something boomed in 2006. Then it came. I know that this is barely an answer, but believe me that the truth is clear to very few.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_213">
        <text>What has led you inside the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2131">
        <text>You unprofitable mine has been closed in 2008. Insufficient money. Then the rumors came about the Zone to give a chance to grow rich. I had no lack of army experience, so I ventured to do it. I canТt say that I an extremely rich now, but IТve got a fair bit of brass behind my back. Typical story, as well as many others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_214">
        <text>WhatТs the most dangerous in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2141">
        <text>Well, itТs hard to say. There are so many things still dangerous and unknown that IТve hardly seen the whole enchilada. My body is the vivid example of the ZoneТs dangers: bit off toe, thinned hair over the radiation, right hip burnt in УZharkaФ, bloody thing by the way. Anomaly which isnТt standing on the same place, but flying. Had a face to face contact with the bloodsucker once. I dread even recollecting it. Basically we can talk it through and through, but if you havenТt felt it on your skin Ц you wonТt understand. Just one advice Ц be careful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_3">
        <text>Have you heard anything about the Gunslinger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_31">
        <text>Kind of tough stalker to my mind. Not really familiar with him. However IТve been wandering at the center of the Zone too long ago, and here to the boundsthere are quite a lot of newbies. You ought to talk to somebody working in the depth of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_4">
        <text>What do you know about the Уdeath trucksФ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_41">
        <text>I donТt know anything at all. Sorry, I see that youТre from there. But itТs too mystified. But working a bit in the Zone makes you superstitious indeed. Corpses in the body, dead men at the wheelsЕ Who they are? Where have they come fromЕ Hope not from the other side.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_0">
        <text>Listen, Sidorovich said something about making a little raid on the local ramapgers.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_1">
        <text>Could be well worth making, yeah. However you stand no chances alone. Listen here. Nearby the factory under the bridge my scouts keep an eye on these rascals. Go to see them and tell that I sent you as reinforcements for the factory assault. Should they not believe, send my "greetings from hell". It's the password.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_11">
        <text>Deal. And what's your interest in the whole affair?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_111">
        <text>Firstly, the guys will have it safer to walk around. Secondly, I was expecting a dynamite crate to be delivered, but due to bandits it was never delivered. This crate I promised to serious people, so the whole situation didn't look well at all. If you deliver it to me, I'll repay. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_1111">
        <text>It's a deal. Get the money ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_11111">
        <text>Excellent, awaiting you and the cargo.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_1112">
        <text>I'll overstrain myself with this heavy box, go pulling it yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_11121">
        <text>Well, if you don't want the money, I won't be forcing you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_12">
        <text>No way, deal with it yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_121">
        <text>WhatТs up, too scared? Well itТs okay, IТm not offended.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_2">
        <text>There is nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_bandits_killed_0">
        <text>Phew... It was hot. We did the bandits in with the Wolf guys. Awaiting the promised award.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_bandits_killed_1">
        <text>No bloody problems. Here's your money. Well deserved.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_artefact_0">
        <text>Here is your artifact! Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_artefact_2">
        <text>Yeah, sure. Client will be satisfied.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_blockpost_box_0">
        <text>Done. Take this case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_blockpost_box_2">
        <text>Well done, thanks a lot. Not that you can be stuffed with the mere УthanksФ. Weeell, 1000, no let it be 500 rubles and weТre done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_0">
        <text>Here is what Fox handed to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_1">
        <text>Perfect, not everything is much clearer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_11">
        <text>WhatТs so important in there? Frankly speaking I understood nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_111">
        <text>Well cut it off. The time will come and youТll get everything. Can only admit that I need a УspecialФ man for the УspecialФ job. DonТt you know such guy? Hehe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_2">
        <text>Sydorovich, donТt waste your timeЕ close to the case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_21">
        <text>Generally speaking, УAgropromФ handed the thing I really need to the army post. White plastic case. It has to be stolen. Just be careful. When miliraties resent they make so much noise here, that even rats scatter. If I were you I would try to make it at night and as quiet as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_211">
        <text>What kinda case is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_2111">
        <text>Nothing special in it. Plastic white grip-sack. Why I do need the very thing inside it. These documents Ц preliminary report on the military expedition to УAgropromФ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_21111">
        <text>Ok. I'll try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_211111">
        <text>Well bring the case first, then we'll deal with money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_21112">
        <text>No, I don't agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_211121">
        <text>As you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_0">
        <text>Well okay, take my first artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_1">
        <text>Marked, listen to my messages carefully next time. Thanks for the artifact but wounded needs your urgent help. Take this medikit and don't you lose it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_1311">
        <text>empty text</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_2">
        <text>Okay then. Goods shouldnТt be wasted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_3">
        <text>Marked!!! Move it to the trailer nearby the road. You'll find wounded stalkers who were returning from my mission. Why a hell did they put fire on that helicopter... now they call SOS all the time... Hand this medikit, move it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_0">
        <text>What kinda work have you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_10">
        <text>This is what's happening. Nearby here, at the factory bandits have encamped. And they go pinching stalkers who go to me with artefacts, so you understand how detrimental it is for sales. And not only for me. Here in the camp they are disliked similarly. So you can join forces to cleanse the Cordon from these bastards. Naturally, I'd owe you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_11">
        <text>’мм... причитаетс€ говришь... Ћадно, пойду зачищать территорию.  то мне в лагере помочь может?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_111">
        <text>¬олк, лидер новичков. ѕодойди к нему, он тебе окажет посильную помощь.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_12">
        <text>No, nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_13">
        <text>Ќе до сук мне сейчас —идорович, дела есть, извини не могу.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_131">
        <text>Ћадно, но ты не сильно задерживайс€. Ѕез теб€ этот гадюшник разгребут - на бобах останешьс€.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_15">
        <text>Okay then. Anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_2">
        <text>All as usual. First of all I need artifacts. I pay usual price not more, not less.\n Sometimes I need specail people for special work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_212121">
        <text>»звини, ошибочка вышла. Ќет сейчас заказов.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_22">
        <text>Ќет ли спецзаказов?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_221">
        <text>Ќет, пока заказов не поступало.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_222">
        <text>ƒа, есть кое-что.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_22221">
        <text>’мм. јга, вот. ≈сть заказ на артефакт "выверт". ќн хоть и недорогой, но зачем-то понадобилс€ нашим толстосумам.  стати, оплата вдове превышает его рыночную цену. ј найти его можно.... дай-ка сюда карту, € отмечу место, где он бывает.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_222211">
        <text>Ћадно, если найду - об€зательно принесу.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_22222">
        <text>’мм. јга, вот. ≈сть заказ на артефакт "кровь камн€". ќн хоть и недорогой, но зачем-то понадобилс€ нашим толстосумам.  стати, оплата вдове превышает его рыночную цену. ј найти его можно.... дай-ка сюда карту, € отмечу место, где он бывает.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_222221">
        <text>Ћадно, если найду - об€зательно принесу.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_22223">
        <text>’мм. јга, вот. ≈сть заказ на артефакт "медуза". ќн хоть и недорогой, но зачем-то понадобилс€ нашим толстосумам.  стати, оплата вдове превышает его рыночную цену. ј найти его можно.... дай-ка сюда карту, € отмечу место, где он бывает.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_222231">
        <text>Ћадно, если найду - об€зательно принесу.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_3">
        <text>Deal. Well if I find something, IТll try not to forget and bring it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_4">
        <text>Maybe youТve got a special work for a special person?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5">
        <text>Got an order on УGravityФ or УTwistФ anomalies. I donТt really care where you find it, but I can aim ya: there is an accumulation of Gravity anomalies to the north from the factory, artifacts may be often found somewhere there. By the way if there will be no artifacts, just wait until someone traps into the anomaly, dog of human, doesnТt matter. Anomaly will make artifact out of him in a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_51">
        <text>Generally speaking, УAgropromФ handed the thing I really need to the army post. White plastic case. It has to be stolen. Just be careful. When miliraties resent they make so much noise here, that even rats scatter. If I were you I would try to make it at night and as quiet as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_511">
        <text>What kinda case is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5111">
        <text>Nothing special in it. Plastic white grip-sack. Why I do need the very thing inside it. These documents Ц preliminary report on the military expedition to УAgropromФ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_53">
        <text>Well, has just appeared. IТm conducting kind of investigation. Tell you later. Well, you must contact the person, whoТs carrying important information. HeТs called Fox. He doesnТt want to be put on view here, so meet him at the khutor behind the bridge. IТll send you the coordinated. By the way, Marked. He isnТt a newbie so far so you can ask him on your matter. ThatТs it. Move out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_531">
        <text>IТm off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5311">
        <text>Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_532">
        <text>AhaЕ dream onЕ Breakneck pace. Am I a pushover or what? Another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5321">
        <text>Do as you wish, but I thought that it was really important for you to know about yourself, who you are and what has happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_55">
        <text>¬ общем этот отчет скоммуниздить у во€к надо, € так пон€л? ѕосчитаем: разглашение государственной тайны, грабеж, нападение на солдат при исполнении, сопротивление при задержании, веро€тнее всего несколько убийств. ”читыва€ реалии военного времени - расстрелов на п€ть пот€нет.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_555">
        <text>ћеченый, не строй из себ€ девочку. ћожно втихар€ дело провернуть, а кроме того там есть и другие сталкеры, они помогут. “о, что оплата будет особа€, € думаю, ты понимаешь, да и в случае чего спр€чем теб€, если кипеж подниметс€. ¬ общем решайс€ - да или нет?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5555">
        <text>Ѕлин, пошла рубаха рватьс€. Ћадно, но ты со мной по приходу не расплатишьс€.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_55555">
        <text>ќ, слова не мальчика, но делового человека. ѕритащишь €щик - буду ждать в любое врем€ суток.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5556">
        <text> огда € найду более экзотический способ самоубийства, € может быть и соглашусь на твое предложение, а пока жить мне еще не надоело.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_55561">
        <text>Ќу ищи-ищи. ќдумаешьс€ - приходи, поговорим.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_6">
        <text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_61">
        <text>Okay, IТll try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_7">
        <text>No, I donТt want.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_71">
        <text>No, I donТt agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_8">
        <text>Deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_81">
        <text>Well, bring it first, then weТll dole out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_9">
        <text>You pick.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_91">
        <text>As you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_0">
        <text>¬от € тебе кое-что притащил.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_111">
        <text>Ќу-ка, ну-ка. јга, гл€нь, выверт он приволок. ћолодец ћеченый, держи заработаные деньги.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_1111">
        <text>’орошо, при€тно с тобой иметь дело.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_121">
        <text>Ќу-ка, ну-ка. јга, гл€нь, кровь камн€ он приволок. ћолодец ћеченый, держи заработаные деньги.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_1211">
        <text>’орошо, при€тно с тобой иметь дело.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_131">
        <text>Ќу-ка, ну-ка. јга, гл€нь, медузу он приволок. ћолодец ћеченый, держи заработаные деньги.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_need_artefacts_1311">
        <text>’орошо, при€тно с тобой иметь дело.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_171">
        <text>So, brought it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_181">
        <text>Branded One, what YOU are doing here? Did I not say clearly Ц rush to the cabin!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_2">
        <text>To make it short, Marked, IТve saved you and I wonТt play dignified. Conduct some tasks for me and weТre done. Besides weТll see how fast will your head restore from amnesia, and IТll try to find about your case. A hell knows why do you need that Gunslinger, I donТt care of the outside problems. If you want to kill him, then there is the reason.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_21">
        <text>closer to the point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Oh, I like it that way. \n Now choose how shall I treat with you. Either I should wash newcomersТ brains or IТll treat with you like with skilled stalker Ц received the task, carry out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_31">
        <text>Let it be like with the newcomer. I remember nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_32">
        <text>Better like with skilled, while it isnТt effaced from the memory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_321">
        <text>ќ! ThatТs how we do that. Listen then: \n There is the УMincerФ anomaly field nearby. And the artifact in the center. Local novices from the camp are afraid to poke in there. Well itТs scattered somewhere there for about a week. ItТs written all over your face that youТre not a newbie, although you remember nothing. So even in such condition youТll manage to bag it. Okay. Get to the job. IТve sent the coordinates of that place to your PDA along with the information on the Mincer and its artifacts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_3211">
        <text>ItТs all settled.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hi, Marked. Glad to see you alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Hi, Marked. How is it going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Listen, Marked, I've told you everything, now get to your job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_0">
        <text>I need answers on several questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_1">
        <text>Shoot, but I know few. You see, IТm stuck here for the eternity, while the real life is outside in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_10">
        <text>Thanks for the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_2">
        <text>What are the militaries doing in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_21">
        <text>Military guard it, what else can they do. The one thing I donТt get is whether they protect outside world form the Zone, or Zone from the outside world. Yep, I still don`t get it. Military expeditions sometimes come here. Must be searching for something. But I tell you, military men do not respect the Zone, and Zone pays back the same. Lots of then found they dead end here. Yep, dead.\nWhat, tell more? Well, those guys look down on us all, like some kind of supreme beings. Don`t give a damn about stalker laws, never help, even in the worst possible situation. No, lying, they can soot you, but not out of pity. Its just runs in their blood: Shoot first, think later. But I and they deal pretty well. Vodka, men magazines, in exchange for my private peace. So I advise you not to bother them in vain.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_31">
        <text>Zone... is not just a peace of territory 40 kilometers in diameter, with its center near the nuclear plant. Zone is really strange being. I don`t think there is a person in this world who can give you a definite answer on your question. Because Zone is something not from this reality. I think it`s another world. Dangerous, strange, but, damn, it`s attractive. It`s like Eldorado, there even the most miserable bum can became very, very rich. And the deeper you go into the Zone, the closer you come to your fortune.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_311">
        <text>And whatТs so dangerous in this Уother worldФ?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3111">
        <text>He, he. Nothing dangerous, besides that you can die any second. And not from the bullet of stupid military, by the way there are a lot of this guys lately. Must also tell, that be killed with a shot is the nicest death here. Really nice, compared with dying in anomaly - invisible death is the scariest one. Even mutants try to avoid them. Mutants, yes, УchildrenФ of the Zone. \nNasty creatures, tell ya. So you better don`t go to the Zone without a gun. And talk to stalkers, they are good advisers as for the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_312">
        <text>Rich? I would like to know more about getting rich...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3121">
        <text>Dude, don`t tell me you know nothing about artifacts. They are the source of your wealth. People outside pay good dough for these souvenirs form the Zone. They are more dear then gold and diamonds. Because no gold can draw aside bullet that heads right into your belly. And artifacts do this, and many other funny and useful things. You can get most common ones even here, but to find a treasure, you`ll have to go to heart the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_313">
        <text>And what lies there, in the heart of the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3131">
        <text>People tell a lot, if interested, ask other stalkers. But I don`t believe in this mystic staff. I do believe that in the center of the Zone lies an Eldorado, a place rich in artifacts. But I met no people who could either confirm, or deny it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_4">
        <text>Any ideas of what happened to me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_41">
        <text>Son, you ask hell of questions. Everything is shady about it. You where found in the death truck - vehicles loaded with corpses sometimes appear from the center of the Zone. Where they head to, no one know. You truck crashed Ц bad luck, but you stayed alive. This is the most intriguing fact to me. Stalkers often find broken death trucks, but never found any survivals. Sorry, have nothing more to tell. You`ll have to figure it out yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_5">
        <text>Who is Gunslinger? You know this guy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_51">
        <text>I think I heard of this stalker. Rumors tell he is one of few, who got to the center of Zone. Well, there are a lot of legends about Уstalker who made it to the center and backФ. So, can`t guaranty the story is true, I personally had no business with him. Maybe he works with other dealers. Want to find him, ask stalkers, maybe some of them will tell you a way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_6">
        <text>Spectral stalker, heard of him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_61">
        <text>Its another legendary man. Not heard about him for a long time. He must have died somewhere deep in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_1">
        <text>Suburbs of the Zone, military cordon. In general it is usually calm and quite here, just military guys have fun sometimes. Stalkers only pass by, only freshmen linger on, and sometimes forever, hehe. There is the novicesТ camp set nearby me in the village. They can pull the trigger sometimes though. No worthy loot here. Abandoned factory by the road. Farm remnants to the North, blockpost to the South. By the way, militaries has set landmines in some places, watch it. There has been the bridge in the center, but in has been ruined. That`s it, I guess.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_10">
        <text>Okay, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_2">
        <text>Tell me more on the army post.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_21">
        <text>Few dozens of soldiers, they are allowed to shoot on sight. So you better pass them by. When military guys are too worried, start calling help from special forces. Those fellows are really tough. After their visits I have no clients for months. So you better not to disturb them. I know their commander a little. He is a total drunkard. Only thanks to his I`m still here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_3">
        <text>Tell me more about the ruined bridge.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_31">
        <text>300-400 meters to the North. You canТt miss it. It was once an expensive bridge, but had been destroyed during the surge. Militaries like to lie in wait for stalkers, returning with the bribe there. So youТd better avoid that embankment, if not crucial.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_4">
        <text>Give me the picture on the factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_41">
        <text>As you cross the road, youТll notice it. Ruined brick building. Everything that could be stolen, has already been stolen, so the only half-tumbled down core remains. The favorite bandits place. I am not aware if theyТre still there, but in any case stay prudent. YouТve still got nothing to take away, but do you really need it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_5">
        <text>Give me a wrap-up on the farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_51">
        <text>What a boring one you are. Simple farm as every other one. Pigs pegged out until the Perestroika.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_tutorial_wounded_end_0">
        <text>Ќу, что скажешь, старик?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_tutorial_wounded_end_1">
        <text>¬ общем, ты вроде как адекватен. я передал в лагерь - они теб€ теперь будут пускать.  стати, тебе там товарищ должен был передать флешку с информацией. √де она?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_tutorial_wounded_end_11">
        <text>¬от она, держи.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_tutorial_wounded_end_111">
        <text>— каждым часом ты мен€ радуешь все больше, ћеченый. „то ж, давай говорить как серьезные люди, делающие как серьезные дела.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_tutorial_wounded_end_12">
        <text>Ќет у мен€ ее.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_tutorial_wounded_end_121">
        <text>ћне жаль ћеченый, но пока ты ее мне не принесешь - серьезного разговора не будет.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_0">
        <text>How are you, alive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_1">
        <text>Oh, damn, IТm bleeding. Hand a first-aid please!?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_2">
        <text>Have it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_21">
        <text>Thanks bro. I wonТt forget it. IТll pass it to the Wolf, he is senior in the village camp. HeТll appreciate it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_3">
        <text>Sorry bro, IТm all out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_31">
        <text>Search the corpsesЕ Guys from our grouping must have had it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_4">
        <text>YouТll kick the bucket anyway why should I spend kit on you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_41">
        <text>What kind of bastard are you, donТt you understand that next time you can be in my shoes?</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
