<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_0">
        <text>What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_1">
        <text>And how do you think?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_2">
        <text>Searching for the artifacts?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_21">
        <text>You can put it that way. Everyone seeks for the artifacts, but not every knows where they truly can be found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211">
        <text>What do you know about that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_2111">
        <text>Of course, I know, otherwise what will I be doing in the place that lacks artifacts? I got the info on where you can learn about how to break through to the Zone’s center. I can sell if you’re interested. Two grands will do. You understand, that there are far enough artifacts in the center so you could reimburse it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_21111">
        <text>Okay, I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211111">
        <text>Deal. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211112">
        <text>Deal. But be careful, don’t put your ass under the fire. Hehe. I appreciate people with the sense of humor. Take a grand back. And buy water proof pants, ha ha.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_21112">
        <text>No thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211121">
        <text>Well, you choose.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_3">
        <text>Wandering?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_31">
        <text>You’re really funny indeed. We’re working here and they – having sweet time on vacations. Recently “worked” with the militaries. If you set too many questions – we’ll “work” with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_4">
        <text>Put your asses under the fire?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_41">
        <text>Ha ha. Yeah, I see that you’re kind of a guy with the sense of humor. I welcome that. I meet such guys too seldom. The other ones are too morose I say, afraid of the death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_5">
        <text>I don’t have a clue.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_51">
        <text>You don’t say so, you don’t know. If you were to the Zone for the same time I did you’ll understand what are people doing here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_start_0">
        <text>Well, whatcha want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_0">
        <text>Whatcha doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_1">
        <text>Putting our asses under the fire. Talk to Mole for details. He’s in chief here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_stalker_start_0">
        <text>Gosh, what a stir, I won’t wish it to my worst enemy. Those militaries are too impudent indeed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_0">
        <text>Put a picture of this place for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_1">
        <text>This is the “Agroprom” institute. The structure itself is situated in the south-west. And the large factory on the North – this is the institute’s production and technical base. Building have been abandoned long ago, and people have stopped thinking about it, cos there is nothing left to steal. But recently militaries started to search something there. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_2">
        <text>Give me more specific information on the institute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_21">
        <text>Rumors say that until the accident in 1986 it was the single Gramineae selection and genetics institute building. Also there were experimental fields at the factory place. After the accident institute has been closed and the fields were burned. And then remembered, whitewashed the building, fenced in and built barracks. Constructed factory on the fields place. I don’t know what were they doing in that institute, but it’s obvious that they spent money left and right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_3">
        <text>Give me more detailed info on the factory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_31">
        <text>Factory has been built at the end of 80th. Supposed to construct and mend the machines, which can treat the radioactively infected soil. But as far as I know, no one has seen such a machine. Now it’s totally tenantless. Only stalkers like to stay at there. It’s said that it’s rather safe place, if not to peep into the dark corners.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_4">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
