    <string id="agr_journal_cache">
        <text>Well, a cache gave out me further direction of search. I found flash-drive, which was used by the \ngroup of Gunslinger, as a kind of «log-book». There were not many reports, but it was enough to \nunderstand - Ghost and Fang were in the group of Gunslinger, except himself. It was mentioned \nsome «common acquaintance», but whether he entered this group is unknown. The fact is he gave \nconsiderable help the group of Gunslinger. After that, according to Ghost's report, Fang perished, \nwhen they got in an ambush. So we have the name of a man which knows Shooter exactly - it's \nGhost. At last something concrete. According to correspondence,I should search Gunslinger \nsomewhere in northlands of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_journal_krot">
        <text>Well, meeting with Mole was productive - apparently cache of group it's reality and it is lockated in \nthe catacombs of Agroprom... i'm going to make way in caves. What is waiting for me there- it's \nunknown. I hope this cache will open my secret too.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_krot_secret_info">
        <text>Get down the spiral stairs to the room with columns. Walk through the room and approach the exit, find yourself in the large room with the pipes on the ceiling, \nproceed to the second exit, enter the pipe and turn left. In the end you'll find the path to the right. From the small room you move straight to the exit and turn \nright. Search for the hole in the wall, near the inscription "Warning! High voltage!". This is the entrance to Gunslinger's cache.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_krot_secret_info_name">
        <text>Gunslinger's cache location description</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_military_case">
        <text>For administrative use only. To “VERITY” leader KGB Colonel Kruchelnikov. From “Search-2” leader \ncaptain Maksimenko. Report. Our group of 3 agents incorporating with SBU special task force unit \nfrom 12.05.2012 till 25.05.2012 has been investigating the blocks of the former scientific and \nresearch institute on contaminated lands of “Agroprom” research institute. Most of the equipment and \nfiles are missing, however few evidence found allows us to make following conclusion: institute was \nnot conducting any scientific researches on agriculture activities from 2005 till 2008. The results of its \n“functioning” reported to Ministry of Agriculture and eventually trumped up. Equipment, consumables \nand financing assigned for state programs were concurrently passed by institute in the person of its \nhead P. D. Strizh by forged invoices to some X-18 lab to carry out experiments in the secondary \nhousehold of the institute. A group of agents involved in this case are likely to use some code name \nbecause there's no lab with such number in database. According to the documents found we can \nassume that it lies in one hour driving distance from “Agroprom”. We suppose it to be a highly secret \nlab and that's why I require our analytics department to take part in this search. There's no possibility \nto clarify what this lab was actually engaged in relying on information available. Found documents \nrefer to notorious professor Chubko. I'm deeply convinced that this time we have got end of thread \nand the analytic department will start working on it. There's an archived file in the attachment \ncontaining invoices on equipment and consumables for secondary household of the institute and a \npassage from Strizh and Chubko correspondence. Captain Maksimenko Prof. Chubko. From Dr. \nStrizh, Head of research institute. Dear Vadim Michailovich, as agreed upon I send you regular set of \nequipment and consumables for you experimental household so you could proceed with your highly \nimportant researches of agricultural sphere. These experiments are financed as natural experiments \nin the field of our institute, so there will be no problems with Ministry. So how are the tests going on? \nI'm still impressed by what you've shown me last time. Yours sincerely, Strizh. Dr. of Agriculture \nStrizh. Thanks a lot, Petr Danilovich, we've got the delivery. My guys are frantic about the laser \nspectrometer and if it were not for your help I would have procured this model through my channels \nfor ages. As to Ministry of Agriculture, it will be glad to get OUR results...you've made me, an old \nman, laugh heartily. The experiments take it normal course and what you've seen last time is nothing \ncomparing with our current achievements. Come to visit us more often - we are always glad to see \nyou. Especially that it takes only one hour to get to our “experimental household” by car. Almost \nforgotten, I have news for you: next Monday I'll discuss your candidacy with the Group. I'm sure they \nwill support me. Yours sincerely, Prof. Chubko. Prof. Chubko. From Dr. of Agriculture Strizh, Head of \nresearch institute Agroprom. Vadim Michailovich, thanks for your trust. I'm deeply touched and will \ndo my best to justify it. I'm sure that every scientist is looking forward to take part in such an \nexperiment and I will be very happy to become a part of the Group. Yours sincerely, Strizh. P.S. I \nhave managed to secure two brand-new Japanese broadband oscillographs in Ministry and will \nhandle them to you as soon as opportunity occurs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_military_case_name">
        <text>Report by investigating group.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_nii_fab_mil_task">
        <text>Operation "Agroprom"\nTasks:\n 1. Clear factory of stalkers\n 2. Join the group dislocated on the territory of the Agroprom RI \n 3. Protect staff and papers till futher instructions.\n The staff is situated on the second floor of the main building of the institute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_nii_fab_mil_task_name">
        <text>Operation "Agroprom"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_nii_security_plan">
        <text>There are patrols, guards and towers marked on the plan. On the second floor is a staff. Papers are \nthere too. In the day-time territory is guarded. At night there are less patrols. After eleven evenings \nthere is changing of guard, at this time in the main building almost nobody is present. If you want to \nget through on the base, I say: you will not pass through the gates, the most \nreal way is - through these damned catacombs.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_nii_security_plan_name">
        <text>"Agroprom" Scientific Research Institute patrol plan</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_nii_security_shedule">
        <text>"Agroprom" Scientific Research Institute territory patrol schedule\n Wake up 6:00\n Dismiss 21:00</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_nii_security_shedule_name">
        <text>Military schedule at Agroprom RI</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_rats_n_soldiers_text">
        <text>Militaries are harassed by rats, which come from the collectors. Delinquent militaries are dispatched to the collectors.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_task_case">
        <text>Trader: When you steal case from former Agroprom SRI territory, bring it to Barmen. He manages a \nstalker bar named "100 Rontgen", it's on the former plant Rostok territory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="article_agr_krot_sos">
        <text>SOS, militants are trying to kill our stalker brother, men, everyone who can hear me-help!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="article_agr_krot_sos1">
        <text>Mole: "Help! I'll de taken down!"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_gunslinger_cache_info">
        <text>We've found the entrance to Gunslinger's stash. There was nothing interesting. Go look there yourself if you like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
        <text>Received from Ghost: \n \n Gunslinger, I've got a bad news. Fang passed on. We were awaited in the village nr the Warehouses. And it seems like for a really long time. Threesome. Looked like common neutrals. Fang has sensed them somehow. You know, he had the senses all the best. We croaked two of them - newbies, while the third one turned out to be wiser - he camped in 100 meteres armed with Vintorez. Well, Fang has ceased to be. Though, next time we'll go to the Center together. And one more thing: Those two had our descriptions. I don't give a damn to whom could "order" us. Although there are a lot of people who have grudge against us. The third one has fleed. It seems that he was one of the mercenaries. Severe scar on the face. Fair eye. I'll try to find him.\n That's the way the cookie crumbles. Stay alert and Good luck.\n Ghost \n \n To Ghost \n \n "Hi matey. \n I leave you the info. Although I don't contact you. Noticed the shadowing.\n Mate, I've gone to the North... Where we have been...I'll try to slip through alone... Sorry, but I've got no time to wait you... I'll explain later. \n And that idiot who dare to kill Fang will regret poking his ass in it... I'll cut his throat... You should find out who is he, I'll return soon - we'll deal there then. \n Meet at out mutual friend. You know which one and where.:)\n Good luck. \n Gunslinger" \n \n To Gunslinger. \n \n "Hi. I've been there. While I haven't met you. You shouldn't have gone to the center alone. Although you're your own man. I know where and how to find you :) \n Ghost"</text>
    </string>
