<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="pri_followers_dlg_0">
        <text>Talk our chief. He knows better the matter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_dlg_1">
        <text>OK</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_11">
        <text>Hi, Branded One. We are going to break through to the station. It's said that there are lots of nice stuff there. We can do good money. We have a map and I \nknow the safe way, are you going with us?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_111">
        <text>OK, what do I have to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_1111">
        <text>Well, here it is. I'm leading the group. Don't run forward, or we won't be able to cover you. Watch your back and what's more important cover our rocketeer \nSasha. He is our last hope in case of big troubles. Communication only over the radio. Plus, we have hacked the wave of militaries - it will be \npossible to hear them out. And one more thing. If you go from our group too far - you will have to proceed on your own. Is that clear?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_11111">
        <text>Clear. Lets move.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_112">
        <text>No guys, I'll cope alone somehow.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_21">
        <text>Move along the street. If something happens - cover us.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_211">
        <text>Îê.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_31">
        <text>Thank you Branded one for a help. This was a heavy fight. We will rest here.\nIf you go farther, I tell you about this place. If you turn back along a transition and go to the right, \nyou'll reach a bus terminal. But there is too opened and unsafe place.\nIf you pass ahead, you appear in front of a hotel. There is a base of monolith on the right of it. Those \nboys without a roof.\nBehind a base there is a stadium. We planned to make ourway to station through it. That is all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_311">
        <text>Thanks</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_4">
        <text>Take near the box grenades for grenade cup discharge, it can be usefull on our way</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_41">
        <text>Well, let's move</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
