    <string id="documents_1">
        <text>Staff report. A week ago the decision was made to increase the radiation intensity on the tested. After the experiment they behaved calmly, but several days afterwards weird metamorphosises were registered. Their skin started to flake, while the behaviour changed for much more agreesive. I continue the observation. Burnov A.N., Senior Laboratory Assistant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="documents_2">
        <text>Staff report. The tested have become virtually fully bold. Their agressiveness augmented incrementally. Yesterday, while feeding, laboratory assistant Gorenko N.B. was bitten in her hand. The suffered was rendered assistance. Burnov A.N., Senior Laboratory Assistant. \n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="documents_3">
        <text>Staff report. The tested have changed drastically. Their skin has virtually completely departed, their teeth considerably grew, they became dangerous. Yesterday guard Glebov G.R. threw them a lump of meat out of fun. This meat was torn apart and eaten by them in split-second. I ordered, due to that, to give air guns to the staff working directly with the tested. Burnov A.N., Senior Laboratory Assistant. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="documents_4">
        <text>Staff report. Yesterday in an experiment on the tested there was psy-emission of new modulation applied. My impression is that thay have been simply burnt their brains out. I can hardly imagine what impact such emission may have on human. Attached are all the materials on the yesterday experiment. Burnov A.N, Senior Laboratory Assistant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="documents_5">
        <text>Staff report. The tested have simply gone mad. They break the cages and attack the laboratory personnel. Their agressiveness level exceeds all the limits, while their self-preservation instinct is completely absent. I ordered the guards and staff to apply weapons against the tested in case of need. On my part, I'll do my best to collect all the documentation possible, take several of the calmer tested and evacuate the laboratory personnel. Burnov A.N., Senior Laboratory Assistant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="pass_to_1st_door">
        <text>Excellent, Vasilyev. I'm glad you received the 2nd level access. Finally you will know what our laboratory does. You will enjoy waking up from nightmare dreams, which will haunt you at day as well. By the way, I was asked to pass you a code to the lock. Here it is - 1243. Kalugin Petr I., Deputy Chief, Laboratory X-18. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="pass_to_2nd_door">
        <text>You will come to reservoirs daily in the evening at 19:00 and 23:00 to check their condition. Report everything directly to me. The code to command centre is 9524</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_borov_flash_info">
        <text>These zombies from the Monolith Base need men. Allegedly for some experiments, I didn't get the picture fully. They pay back with artefacts, the expensive ones. Should you be sending them captives, tell your boys that that pass is NUCLEAR WINTER. I described your uniform to the Monolith gang, so make sure you wear the suits when going there. Otherwise they take you for damn intruders and take up arms. \nShould I specify who exactly to deliver the award to for this information?  \nZmey.</text>
    </string>
