    <string id="bar_ecolog_research_normal">
        <text>... as it turned out the radiation first of all influences on the highest regions of thinking. The experiments indicated that only the human and the animals with the highly organized thinking, like dogs, horses, are sensible to such radiation. Out of the abovementioned only the man can be fully subjected to the influence of falling into trance condition, laboratory animals suffered only the effect within the limits of deep fear. Regarding these presuppositions it's possible to make a conclusion about the specialization of the influence solely on the human brain. Positive experiments on "volunteers" affirmed that the trance effect can be removed with the pharmacotherapy. Moreover we've gathered experimental devices, which protect the human brains from dosated radiation influence. According to our calculations the source of radiation is situated in the center of Yantar lake, most likely the nature of the source if artificial and it can be possible to disconnect it. Furthermore there is an endangerment that some undesirable elements can receive an access to the source of radiation and attempt to take it under control.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_research_corrupted">
        <text>I, professor Kruglov, in the name of science and humanity delete the reports of our researches. 
        Dangerous knowledge mustn't reach the hands of malevolent elements, who won't hesitate to use them in criminal pursuits. The one who reads this entry should know that our group has been knocked down above the "wild territory" by Freedom's anarchists, under the command of famous cutthroat Wolfhound. 
        And consider that most likely we're dead now.</text>
    </string>
    
    <string id="rostok_tunel_gordon_diary">
        <text>12.01.2012 \n
        Damn those big B. I doubt they can give me the rest. "Black Mass" came first, then an obscure city in Russia.
Now again: go, old butt Gordon, to the boundless steppes of Ukraine. And don't forget to take the crowbar for successful fling. \n
        \n
        20.03.2012 \n
        Got into the Zone. How curious that there are no bears here. Whom shall I fight with then?
        In general it requires a deep breath to get acquainted with everything here. The fact is that everyone recognizes me in America and I'm even treated with burgers for free.
        While in here I had to give my crowbar for the tinned meat. \n
        \n
        26.04.2012 \n
        The blowout began. Barkeep said that I should have hidden my American bum deeper without any attempts to blow the cover. Drove several rats out of the abandoned tunnel. I hope I can wait the foul weather here through.</text>
    </string>
