<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="rad_chief_start_dialog_0">
        <text>Hello there!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_chief_start_dialog_100">
        <text>Hi!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Where is the money for the task?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_100">
        <text>Find my assistant and you'll have the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_1000">
        <text>Fine, but no tricks this time!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Who are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_10">
        <text>Alex "Jawbone" is my name! And these vagabonds are my team!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_100">
        <text>What are you and your guys doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_20">
        <text>My guys and I are resting here! As soon as we're done, we'll advance to Prypyat!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_0">
        <text>What do you know about Prypyat?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_10">
        <text>I know that this is old abandoned town of the communism epoch! This is mainly from history. I believe that it is now aswarmed with monsters and the crowds of monolithians! The ones who went there haven't returned!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_100">
        <text>Do you think it's very dangerous there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_20">
        <text>No doubts, as for now those who went there haven't yet returned.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_0">
        <text>Have you seen militaries somewhere nearby?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_10">
        <text>No, no militaries in view, it has been a long time I haven't seen any militant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_100">
        <text>Maybe you've met any military stalkers?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_20">
        <text>Rumors say that they've appeared somewhere on the very Radar base, well right near the antennas! Once they were deactivated, a lot of people rushed to Radar and further to Prypyat! We've been stuck here for day, but no one yet poked a nose in here. Perhaps, someone blocked off the road here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_200">
        <text>You think the path to Radar is blocked off by the militaries?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_30">
        <text>I don't think so, it's been a long time I haven't seen them, but the military stalkers could for sure! They don't play jokes, they are really tough guys, acting swiftly and well-coordinated, I wonder why haven't they blocked the road up earlier!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_300">
        <text>Why haven't they gone to Prypyat or haven't blocked off the road there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_40">
        <text>I dunno, maybe they are afraid and or preparing to something, we have only to guess what they have on mind.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_0">
        <text>Maybe you have a task for me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_10">
        <text>Well, I've got one, but it's not of easy ones, will you take it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_100">
        <text>Yes, I'm not afraid of such wordings!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_101">
        <text>No, drop it, I've got no time!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_11">
        <text>I see, but I'm scared too, I prefer to spend some money and send someone instead of me and my guys!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_20">
        <text>Well, good! The task is as follows, find my scouts, Crowbar and Log! They went to Prypyat, while I decided not to go headlong into the tiger's jaw, thus I've sent the best of the best there! Find them alive and get them there, and if they perished bring me their guns! Once you fufil the task and you'll receive 2000 dough!!!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_200">
        <text>Okay, deal!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_201">
        <text>Too little money, rise it to 4000 dough and we're done, deal?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_21">
        <text>This is all I can offer for this task!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_30">
        <text>Great, I'll wait you here!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_0">
        <text>Task accomplished!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_100">
        <text>Perfect, give me his PDA!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1000">
        <text>Take it, give me the money!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1100">
        <text>What a cheeky setup, if to consider that he had nothing with him!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1200">
        <text>I'm gonna whack you now!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1300">
        <text>Get into my sight again, I'll do you in!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1400">
        <text>Okay, I see, good luck!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_200">
        <text>I can't give you anything, no money. If you'd like, you could leave me his junk!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_300">
        <text>No money! Dismissed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_2_0">
        <text>I haven't found him yet!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_2_10">
        <text>Find him quicker, if you want to get your money!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_0">
        <text>I've found your guys, they died - here is their weapons!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_100">
        <text>Thanks, then I think that they have perished, thus there is no sense to go to Prypyat yet! The only problem remains, I can't give you money for the task. My assistant has gone with the money!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_1001">
        <text>Good, I'll find him! Tell me where to search for him? And don't even think to chuck me again!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_200">
        <text>I think he couldn't get away long ago, he can be, let me mark it on your map, here or here! When you find him, bring him to me or his pda.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_2000">
        <text>Good, wait for me!!!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_2_0">
        <text>I haven't found them yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_2_10">
        <text>Search for him faster! I cant wait forever!! Good luck!</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
