<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="storyline_fox_flash_info">
        <text>Restricted.\nTo: Leader, “THRUTH” project \nKGB colonel V.Ì. Kruchelnikov \nFrom: Commander, «Search-2» group, \ncaptain D.F. Maksimenko \n\nReport.\n\nIn period from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012 our group incorporating with KGB task force section has been inspecting the facilities of  former “Agroprom” research institute, which researched the problem of farming on lands contaminated  with radioactivity. The very first inspections draw suspicion upon their non-farming activities of the last 2-3 years before the “X” day. \nFurther worse, the first part of collected materials was sent under the escort to Dytyatky army post on May, 16th, but according to the information provided by army post commander lieutenant V.P. Chuguykin no one came for that data. Radio communication with the center is unstable and recently because of the increasing Zone activity communication service is out at all.. We don’t send any other Agroprom materials as the remaining group is reluctant to be split. During the delivery of first part of collected materials two soldiers of the escort died: sergeant R.D. Dubko and ensign K.P. Ivanets. We couldn’t fetch the bodies, since all the bodies were missing. \nColonel, sir, I insistently demand on considering this situation. With all the proper respect sir, we’re at the breaking point. My people are  dying and no one has any mere dealings with  us and our tasks!!!. Where a hell is that damn group of military stalkers I was promised? Or our replacement? Where are the promised air support and rations?!!! For what damn reason an antique tank without any fuel or ammunition was sent here? Yes, it has arrived, inane wonder of engineering… Mutants jeer at it… Stop teasing us!!!.. If the situation doesn’t change, I’ll take my men away from the Zone on my own… Got that?\n\n28.05.2012.                                           KGB captain Maksimenko D.F.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
