<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_0">
        <text>d1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1000">
        <text>d2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1001">
        <text>Help... Help...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1002">
        <text>Whoa... Yeah, Mr. Soldier, I see you've been damaged fair much...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1003">
        <text>Screw you, scoundrel!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1004">
        <text>Are you the... hum... monolithian? I've he-e-ard... colonel called you so..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1005">
        <text>If I were one of them, you would have no chance to talk now... I am Branded one, stalker. And what kind of nut are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1006">
        <text>Me... corporal... Johnny Luckless...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1007">
        <text>Yeah, well I see that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1008">
        <text>Who... who else has survived?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1009">
        <text>Not likely. Damn, I should have a medical aid from the doctor not from the medikit. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1010">
        <text>Apparently, it's my time to go... with comrades...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1011">
        <text>Hush for a while. Sooner or later we'll all be there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1012">
        <text>Well, I'm not holding you back.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1013">
        <text>Thanks, man... Colonel told...that you all had to be some kind of inhuman brutes here... kh... whilst you seem to be pretty adequate...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1014">
        <text>You certainly can find some brutes here. Tell me more, who did it to you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1015">
        <text>No, my friend. I'm not really adequate - it just looks to be so. I'm going to fry you and eat... in fact, forget the fry stuff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1016">
        <text>Like total newbies... hem... There was a radiochemical reconnaissance... conducted by the copters... they had too much confidence in those ones... and \nwhere obliterated in a jiffy... And then you column was blocked up... and as well was screwed... Only I made it.. to... knock a couple of foes off..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1017">
        <text>Fighting-cocks.. It took a few seconds for you to appear here! The radar has just shut down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1018">
        <text>A month here... two steps from here, on the border of the zone we were... fully prepared.. Battle.. the battle still there?..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1019">
        <text>This is the case in point. Someone was really noisy there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1020">
        <text>Maybe someone of us, alive... could settle there... We had... a task - to capture the path to Sarco... hk... khe... Sarcophagus... if something happens - we must \nwait for reinforcements..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1021">
        <text>Reinforcements?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1022">
        <text>Our pop... colonel told that there should be merely no rebuff there... just beasts... few monstrosities...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1023">
        <text>So what's with the reinforcements?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1024">
        <text>There is the task force... as well, once we have failed, they'll begin... I though we'll make a skirmish there... keh... a bit... and the battle broke out here... Don't \nwalk straight the road...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1025">
        <text>Goofy! What was it about the task force?... Look at me! Don't close your eyes, well!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1026">
        <text>A-a-a, it hurts!.. Oh, take me home... no chance to break through without the copters...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1027">
        <text>Sergeant?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1028">
        <text>Yes... sergeant Luck Lessy... The enemy has minimum three machine-gun dots, several snipers... Man, you'd better not.. don't go there... keh..</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1029">
        <text>Few more seconds, sergeant! When a hell... When this cursed task force arrives?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1030">
        <text>Huh?.. Stalker... task force... we were knocked out, it... now....</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1031">
        <text>Now? Oh my gosh...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1032">
        <text>Kh... And you... what have brought you here... kh...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1033">
        <text>I wanted to get to the Monolith, but there you are...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1034">
        <text>I would... also like to glance at it... but, apparently it's not my fate... take my PDA... keh... there is a sarcophagus assault plan...\nAll our groupings... are indicated ... Perhaps, you will be lucky ... to break through... and Monolith will... grant your wish...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="aes_sergeant_diallog_1035">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
