	<string id="agr_journal_cache">
		<text>Well the stash provided me with a new direction to follow. I found a flash drive, which Sharpshooter's group appears to have used as some sort of log. There weren't that many entries in it but it was enough for me to work out that except for Sharpshooter there were 2 others in his group: Ghost and Fang. The log also mentioned a "mutual friend" but I don't know whether he was part of the group. He definitely helped them though, that's for sure. According to Ghost's entry Fang died when they were ambushed. So, at last, I have something specific: the name of someone who definitely knows Sharpshooter - Ghost. As for Sharpshooter himself, according to the journal he really is somewhere in the north of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_journal_krot">
		<text>Well, meeting Krot paid off - it seems that the group's stash really exists and it's located in the catacombs below the Institute...I'm gonna have to go there. What awaits me in those dark tunnels I do not know...but I hope this stash helps me solve my own puzzle...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_secret_info">
		<text>Follow the spiral staircase down into the room with the columns. Move across the room towards the exit and enter a large room with pipes on the ceiling. Go down to the second exit, enter the tunnel and turn left. There will be a right turn at the end. Go directly to the exit from the small room and turn right. Look for a hole in the left wall next to the words "Don't enter - you'll die". That's the entrance to Sharpshooter's stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_secret_info_name">
		<text>Sharpshooter's stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_military_case">
		<text>\nInvestigation report.\n For official use only.\n To USS Colonel V.M. Kruchelnikov, head of project "TRUTH".\n From Captain D.F. Maksimenko, \ncommander of "Search-2" group.\n\n Memo.\n Our group consisting of 3 investigators and a squad of USS Spetsnaz conducted searches at Agroprom, the former R&D Institute for agriculture on radiation-affected soil, from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012. Most of the equipment and documentation was missing however the few things we were able to find allow us to come to the following conclusion: over the period from 2005 to 2008 the Institute did not conduct any research in its official fields of study. All the results of its "work" received by the Ministry of Agriculture were faked. Simultaneously the Institute's management, specifically Petr Danilovich Strizh, continued to receive state financing, equipment and consumables and transferred them to a laboratory designated X-18 using forged consignment notes, which provided cover for the operation by indicating that the materials were being transferred to an auxiliary facility for experiments. X-18 appears to be a code name adopted by the group of people implicated in this affair, since our database contains no mention of this laboratory. Judging by an analysis of the documents we found, this laboratory is located within an hour's drive from the Institute. It is likely to be a clandestine facility so I would request the involvement of our analytical department. The lab's field of research is not clear and available documents contain no helpful information in this regard but do make references to the infamous professor Chubko and also mention some "Group". It is my firm belief that we have come to the end of the line and the analytical department will now have plenty of work to do.\n\n Attached is an archived file containing consignment notes for consumable materials and equipment transferred to some auxiliary facility and an extract from correspondence between Strizh and Chubko.\n\n Captain D.F. Maksimenko 26.05.2012\n To professor V.M. Chubko. From P.D. Strizh, Head of Agroprom R&D Institute, Doctor of Agricultural Sciences. Dear Vadim Mikhailovich, As agreed, I am sending the next batch of consumable materials and equipment to our experimental facility to help you with your research, which is so essential for agriculture. I arranged financing for the experiments by describing them as pilot experiments in fields studied by the Institute so there won't be any problems at the Ministry. How are the experiments progressing? I am still deeply impressed by what you showed me last time. Sincerely yours, P.D. Strizh DAS To P.D. Strizh Please accept my gratitute, Petr Danilovich, we've received everything. My team is very impressed with the laser spectrometer - if not for you, it would take me eons to acquire this model through my channels. Of course the Ministry of Agriculture will be happy to receive OUR results...you really made an old man laugh with that one! The experiments are continuing normally and the things you saw last time are dwarfed by our latest achievements. You should visit more often - I am always happy to see you and it's only an hour's drive to our "experimental facility" by car :) I almost forgot, I have news for you: next Monday I will be discussing your candidacy with the Group. I think they will support me. Sincerely yours, professor V.M. Chubko To professor V.M. Chubko From P.D. Strizh, Head of Agroprom R&D Institute, Doctor of Agricultural Sciences Dear Vadim Mikhailovich, thank you for your trust. I am touched and will do my best to prove you right. I think every scientist dreams of participating in an experiment like this and I will be absolutely delighted to be accepted into the Group. Sincerely yours, P.D. Strizh P.S. I managed to get two of the latest Japanese broadband oscilloscopes from the Ministry and will send them over at the earliest opportunity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_military_case_name">
		<text>Investigation report</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_nii_security_plan">
		<text>The chart details the patrols, sentries and guard towers. The HQ is on the second floor of the Institute. That's where the documents are kept. By day the area is infested with patrols. There are less of them at night and the guards are relieved at 11pm. There are few people in the main building at this time. If you want to get into the base you should take the catacombs, the gate is not an option.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_nii_security_plan_name">
		<text>Agroprom R&D Institute guard chart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_rats_n_soldiers_text">
		<text>The army is annoyed by rats which climb out of the collectors. They punish soldiers by sending them into the collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_task_case">
		<text>Trader: "As soon as you steal the briefcase from the Institute take it to the Barman. He runs the business in "100 roentgen" - the stalker bar. It's located in the area of the former Rostok factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="article_agr_krot_sos">
		<text>SOS, the army is killing a fellow stalker! Guys, if you can hear me - help! </text>
	</string>
	<string id="article_agr_krot_sos1">
		<text>Mole : "Help me, I'm gonna get killed!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="article_agr_krot_sos_name">
		<text>Meeting Mole</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_operation_agroprom">
		<text>The Agroprom operation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_gunslinger_cache_info">
		<text>We found the entrance to Sharpshooter's stash under the factory but there wasn't anything interesting there. Go take a look yourself if you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
		<text>Received from Ghost: \n \n Sharpshooter, I got some shitty news. Fang is dead. They were waiting for us in the village by the Warehouses, three of them and it seemed like they'd been waiting for a while...they looked like normal neutrals. Fang sensed them somehow, you know how good his gut feeling was. We took two of them down - they were obviously just thugs but the third one was clever, he waited about 100 metres away with a Vintorez and that was the end of Fang. So there will only be two of us next time we go to the Centre. And one more thing: those two had our descriptions. I've got no clue who put a contract out on us. Then again, there are plenty of people with an axe to grind. The third one got away. I think he was one of the mercenaries. He had a big scar on his face and light eyes. I'll try to find him. \n That's about it. Be alert and good luck. \n Ghost \n \n To Ghost \n \n "Yo man. \n I'm leaving you some info. Can't make contact right now - I'm being followed. \n Man, I've gone North... To that place where we were before... I'll try to make it on my own... Sorry but I can't wait for you... I'll explain later. \n The bastard who killed Fang will regret ever being born... I am going to cut him to pieces... You just find out who he is for now. When I get back we'll deal with him. \n Meet me at our mutual friend's place. You know which one :)  \n Good luck. \n Sharpshooter" \n \n To Sharpshooter \n \n "Hey. I went there but didn't find you. You shouldn't have go to the centre alone but it's your business, man. Yeah, I know whose place you mean :) \n Ghost"</text>
	</string>
