<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11">
        <text>Halt, stalker. You can't proceed any further!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111">
        <text>And why that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111">
        <text>Farther lies our territory - the base of Duty faction. And we're indeed eager to find a quarrel in the straw when choosing the ones to let into our residence. If you have no significant deals with our leaders, we are not letting you in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11111">
        <text>Okay, I'm gonna go. For now. But I'll be back!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111111">
        <text>Please, do. Any time day or night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11112">
        <text>I have business with the bartender. I believe you know him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111121">
        <text>Even if I do, the pass costs a sum. Shell out half a grand and we'll let you in. Or you can render us some service. Choose.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111211">
        <text>I'll better be giving you money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11112111">
        <text>Perfect, now pass, and you'd better have a really substantial concern to the barman. But there is quite a number of anomalies in the passageway, stay cautious.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111212">
        <text>What kind of service?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_11112121">
        <text>Hah, trifles in general. There is a boars nest nearby. It would be nice if someone cleared it away. I'll show you the its location. Clear it and consider the due to be paid.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111121211">
        <text>Deal. I'm gonna switch to the hunt now, make a toast of dairy boar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111212111">
        <text>Good luck, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_111121212">
        <text>What if I go and make some money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_1111212121">
        <text>Yeah, you might find empty bottles right here at the garbage, collect them, maybe you'll make enough money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_22">
        <text>So, how are the boars doing?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_221">
        <text>Doing... still.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_2211">
        <text>When you start undoing them, bring me one toast please.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_222">
        <text>Sorry, all toastes were spent, by me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_2221">
        <text>Joker, darn... Alright, you may pass, but be sure that the toast will be reminded.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_33">
        <text>When you see the barkeep, send my greetings to him. Oh, and dont forget about lots of anomalies in the passage, be careful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_0">
        <text>Can you tell anything about the Garbage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_1">
        <text>Well, there is nothing special in here. Garbage like any other garbage. The northern road to the "Bar" is guarded by the "Duty"'s militants. You'd better stay away from dealing with them, Duty has got many obscure guys in it. To the right - passages to the Dark Valley, but there is a really fierce radiation there. Little bit closer - "Grimpen Mire", swamps full of anomalies. It's said that it can be useful in finding artifacts, but it definitely can help in finding troubles. The only thing is settled - at least there is no hound of the baskervilles on the bogs.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_2">
        <text>Maybe you know anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_22">
        <text>Interesting information, thanks, I'll consider it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_3">
        <text>Well, one more point. There is a cache to the right, where the bogs lie. When you see the metal edifice, which streches above one of the puddles. Anyway, right under it you'll find the cache. I'd hidden it in my time, but you saved my life and I think, you require it more than I do. So use it on your own.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_4">
        <text>Thanks, mate. I won't forget it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_0">
        <text>Thanks, my friend, you've helped me a lot. I'll remember that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_1">
        <text>Next time try to avoid such scrapes. You'll save your nerves and my bullets.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_11">
        <text>Until you are taken ill with sclerosis. I know, I know. Well, so long.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_2">
        <text>It's not as easy as it may seem to be. My friends are waiting now for the bandits' raid nearby, so as to stop them. If the bandits manage to obtain control over this garbage, nobody will have the access to the center of the Zone. I'm struggling for the stalkers' future. Talk to our commander, he has settled close by the graveyard with his soldiers. I'm gonna visit him, join me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_21">
        <text>Hem... Get him, Superman in the diapers. Save yourself first of all.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_211">
        <text>Oh, cut the crap. Anyone could be caught on the way like this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_bandits_damaged_0">
        <text>Hi, glad to see you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_bandits_damaged_1">
        <text>Likewise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_0">
        <text>Hello to you too. You need help as far as I understand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_1">
        <text>Bandits fell in here recentlly. Previously they resided at Agroprom, away from the main road inside the Zone, and now roamed in here. If they manage to take control over this territory, the way further in the Zone will be obstructed. While this we can't allow to happen. We've suffered a skirmish half an hour ago; they've been driven away, however we had casualties as well. Some part of them retreated, and several men slightly impaired broke through headed for the Dark Valley. So be careful, you can poke right into them on your way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_11">
        <text>And how can I help? Do you think that the militaries won't beat them out, if they become really impudent?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_111">
        <text>Desperately need it. Bandit gang is trying to gain control over the Garbage. Half an hour ago there was a brawl here. We did in three of the bastards. The rest of the gangsters retreated, but are likely to return with reinforcements any minute. We are few, so any extra barrel would come in handy. If you help us eliminate their reinforcements, I will repay as due. \n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_1111">
        <text>Okay, I'm gonna stretch my legs before the long walk...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_11111">
        <text>Perfect. We'll make an ambush, so you stay away of firing too soon. They'll approach from the Agroprom direction, westerly. And don't try to kick the pricks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_111111">
        <text>I'll act under the circumstances.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_1112">
        <text>This is not my business and I won't risk my skin.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_11121">
        <text>As you want, but you'll be whipping the cat, when paying the due to the freaks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_111211">
        <text>Let me deal with this myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_1113">
        <text>Steam not, old man. I have spoiled them a bit. So the reinforcement can reinforce the mere dead ones.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_11131">
        <text>Oh, you are cool. But I'll better secure myself. What of it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_quest_111311">
        <text>Good luck there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_0">
        <text>Yeah he's likely to be alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_1">
        <text>When I have free time, I'll be happy to help you with your affair. People like you typically don't go for nothing. Besides I know quite enough and can share some info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_11">
        <text>Information is good, but you cannot feed on it alone. And besides, I could well do with some healing, buy up some ammo and so forth.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_111">
        <text>I can pay with money, you will make use of it. Here you go, right for your healing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_1111">
        <text>Now we are talking. Consider us settled.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_12">
        <text>No, thanks, this battle is mine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_121">
        <text>Do as you want, but I won't be waiting for you for the whole life, you must be not a fair maiden.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_1211">
        <text>Guess I'm not seeking mariage with you. See you, old man.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_13">
        <text>Tell me about yourself at first.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_13111">
        <text>I'm Dimon. I've come here three years ago. As the majority in here - I'm the runaway. I've got two murders and heavy bodity on my back. Several years ago my friend has been maliciously hammered in the outside region. He has been gathered by particles in the resuscitation unit. Hence we had to make a visit of gratitude. When the cops zoomed up to arrest me, I had to croak one of them and jump off the second floor. Since then I wander in there. Yet my collection of articles on the back has been decently increased. And here I struggle with the chaos as I can. As at the Big Land. Train and organize the youth, teach them how to survive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_131111">
        <text>Why aren't you joining the Duty with these humanistic gospels?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_1311111">
        <text>The Duty is struggling against the Zone, while I'm struggling for humans. Besides, they're closely connected with our government and army. I'm not burning with the desire to wake up in the detention cell in one shiny morning.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_13111111">
        <text>Well good luck to you, crusader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_14">
        <text>What kind of place is that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_141">
        <text>Garbage. Place, where we'll find the righteous place for us. Do you see the piles of trash? You'd better not wander there, there are radioactive wastes, Geiger's counter trills away like a nightingale. Here is the only convinient passage into the center of the Zone. And recently bandits started to take advantage over this territory. Farther, whereto the experienced stalkers roam, is the Duty's territory, they are afraid to poke in there. While bozing here, shagging out the novices - common cause. Though if anyone don't care a damn about this, we'll have to take up arms once again.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_1411">
        <text>Yeah, I see you need it the most.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_14111">
        <text>No, this is called the life stand point. You'll have to remain humanlike everywhere, and especially here, trying not to be brute with the only goal of the craving of bean.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_141111">
        <text>Oh come on, I didn't want to offend you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_141112">
        <text>Good, old man, and what else can you tell me about the Garbage?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_1411121">
        <text>There is a large abandoned hangar in the center, and it's pretty quiet there. At the worst you may spend the night there. If you go to the West, in the direction of Agroprom you'll find the bandits camp, whence those freaks were comming, but I believe that it's not the end.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_14111211">
        <text>Oh, thanks, this information is right enough to start working.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_dialog_thanks_15">
        <text>Thanks, we don't need anything from you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_in_battle_0">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_11">
        <text>Greetings to you, stalker. You're right on time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_21">
        <text>I have nothing to do with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_211">
        <text>As you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_31">
        <text>Thank you, friend, you've helped us. How are you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_41">
        <text>The business is still undone, leave the talks for the later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_411">
        <text>Хорошо.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_hellcar_start_51">
        <text>Hello.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_11">
        <text>Friend, help me. Please!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_111">
        <text>And what happened?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_1111">
        <text>My friend and I located a nice place with artefacts here. We went on a couple of times in this tunnel to bring back a decent loot. But lately bandits have encamped here, we dropped into the tunnel to find hiding there. After the Blowout though many anomalies showed up and my friend got entrapped in anomaly there, inside the tunnel. And now I cannot make it out, there are bandits there, while sitting here is a certain death. Stalker, help out, I'll be grateful for ages.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_11111">
        <text>Well, fancy I agree to help. What this help will be about?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_111111">
        <text>Pick off the bandits on entrance, and I'll make it fine back home on my own.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_1111111">
        <text>Alright, if you can't protect yourself on your own, I will do it. Sit still and don't move until I call you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_111113">
        <text>They are a feed for crows now. So you may well stroll back home safe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_11112">
        <text>Sorry, buddy, I'm too busy today. Can't help really.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_22">
        <text>Oh how I wish I could make it to a safe place shortly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_33">
        <text>I'll make it on my own from this point on. I can't imagine what to thank you with really. Here grab the money, unfortunately that's all I have with me. But life costs more. Should you need something from me - feel free to ask.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_333">
        <text>You didn't disappoint me. Be good. Never cough and stay away from the night Zone at full moon, when the forces of evil enjoy complete domination.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_3333">
        <text>It doesn't seem there are other forces to reign here at any other time. Alright, thanks, I'll make it on my own from here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_44">
        <text>Gesundheit! Glad to see you in one piece.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_newbie_in_tonnel_444">
        <text>Thanks, likewise.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_0">
        <text>Well now have you got time to talk down calmly?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_1">
        <text>Yes, for the time being. Where have you poked out?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_11">
        <text>I've been talking to Fox recently. He says that you've got information on the Gunslinger's grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_111">
        <text>Well supposedly, but considering yor almost gratuitous help I'll tell you. I'll be awaited by one of the guys, former Digger, called Mole. He has digged out the Gunslinger's cahce and took out to the light the documents, which enlighten many things. But inasmuch as he got bandits chasing him on his back, he didn't take the documents with him - only remembered the place. But as I'm hunted now, I'll preferably go into shadow now. Take these coordinates of the meeting and tell him that you're from me. This flash-drive has also got some materials in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_1111">
        <text>Thanks. Your grey bacon has been saved not in vain. Good luck, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_11111">
        <text>Ok, I'll wait right here, my comrades will be here soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_11">
        <text>Darn it, cut the crap. You'll find only the bullets here talking to you. Help us to defend ourselves and then we'll probably have a chat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_22">
        <text>Gosh, that was hot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_33">
        <text>Hi, mate, there has been a nice gaiety in here, damn it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_44">
        <text>Find your path by the anomalies through the artifacts, stalker-boy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_55">
        <text>Buzz off, buddy, the war is blooming!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seryi_about_garbage_0">
        <text>Listen, buddy, what's interesting to be found on this dump here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seryi_about_garbage_1">
        <text>Ass-kicking troubles galore here. But if you are so full of pioneer's zeal, listen here. To the east there is a small forest, there's nothing interesting there, however packs of dogs frequent there. Be careful. If you follow these rails, they will lead you to a tunnel. Many anomalies are there, maybe there's something interesting left there, I don't know, I didn't explore it thoroughly. I think you know about the army post of Duty in the north. That's basically it of what I know about this level. \n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seryi_about_garbage_11">
        <text>Thanks, this has been helpful, will take into account.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_stalker_about_level_0">
        <text>Can you tell me anything about this place?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_stalker_about_level_1">
        <text>Well listen then. We're now located at the huge stinky garbage dump. Since 1986 it has been the place to store the radioactive trash, cranes, worn out machinery. In general the trash is all way around you, besides there is quite a number of anomalies among the debris. Artifacts appear, although not superior enough. That's why it is the place mainly dedicated for the novices. And hence the novices bring bandits with them. So you'd better not stay here for long. There are lots of radioactive hotbeds to the East, going here without the protection suits can be fatal. If you proceed to the South, you'll exit to the border of the Zone. If North - you'll find the abandoned Rostok factory, and stalkers' bar in it. Dark Valley to the East - dark, gloomy and foggy place. Agroprom research institute to the West. I'll mark the spots on the map for, to make you path more safely.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_0">
        <text>Don't kill me, stalker, I beg you. I'm feeling awful as I am.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_1">
        <text>Well it depends on what you can be useful with. For example, what is this pilgrimage from Egypt, pshaw, I meant Agroprom, for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_11">
        <text>We got the base firstly at Agroprom... then we heard the stir that "epaulets" are going to visit it. Someone went to the Dark Valley, but many has stayed here. Well, to think narrowly, they'll make a ransack and go away. But more was coming. They haven't merely come, but arrived at APCs. At that they've made a really thoroughgoing cleaning, perhaps desired to supply their retirement. Lots of you guys has been slaughtered. They were just shooting off everyone they see. There was a group of neutrals - even they were exterminated. They've organized a base there and it produced an impression that the institute had as an important meaning as it was worth eliminating the whole city.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_111">
        <text>Hmm, interesting news. Okay, just relax here for a while. Brute death to the brute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_1111">
        <text>Some day you'll find your deathbed too. And will also beg for help. I wish I could see this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_112">
        <text>Lets consider that you've bought the right to live with this information. Take this kit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_wounded_bandit_1121">
        <text>Thanks. I see that you are human at all.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
