<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1">
        <text>I've got a mission.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11">
        <text>Hm. And what a mission? What are you looking for? Or maybe you have found already? I've heard \nthere are piles of goods here...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_111">
        <text>I'm sorry, but I can't tell you, besides I've got no time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1111">
        <text>Wait up there, buddy. You'll have your chance to run later... So what have you found? After all I'm not just wandering here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11111">
        <text>What I found is mine.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11112">
        <text>I have found documents X18, barmen promised to pay good reward for it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_112">
        <text>No, I haven't found anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2">
        <text>I don't know, how did I get here I should fade away as soon as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21">
        <text>Haven't you found anything worthy of note? It's said, that information on experiments can be found somewhere here. It's paid good...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_211">
        <text>Nope, I haven't found anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2111">
        <text>Yeah?.. Think better! Are you trying to hide something from me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21111">
        <text>No</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21112">
        <text>What kind of talk is that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21113">
        <text>Are you threatening me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_212">
        <text>Damn all this information, I've made it out merely alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2121">
        <text>Okay, go on with you. If you find anything - I'll be nearby.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_25">
        <text>Listen here, in this very Zone I have gone through fire, anomalies, thick and thin monsters, but I'm \nstill alive, as you may see! So, don't give instructions to me of what I should say and what I \nshouldn't. I'm here for the documents. And I won't leave without them. If you have these documents, I \nadvise you to give them to me, otherwise you will stay in this hole forever! Got it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_251">
        <text>Got... it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2511">
        <text>If you're lying to me - you will have problems, if you have any ulterior motives - you will have troubles, if you palm off some crap to me - you will have troubles. Shortly, you have one big problem and you have to do your best to solve it! And now once again for the slow-witted personally - have you found the documents?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_252">
        <text>Take it easy, buddy. I told you, that I had found nothing. I swear!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2521">
        <text>That's more like it and next time - watch your tongue. And now go. If you find anything - I'll be nearby...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_253">
        <text>The talk is over and get out of my way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_26">
        <text>I have no documents.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_27">
        <text>Well, yeah, I've found some information, but there seems to be nothing important.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_271">
        <text>That's better, dummy! And now give me all the information that you found. Everything till the very last document. And mind you don't joke with me - or it will be your last joke.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_51">
        <text>Halt, I said! I'm not just wandering in this hole. Don't play dumb, take out what you've found. We'll share, perhaps...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_511">
        <text>I'm not gonna share anything with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5111">
        <text>Well, get a hell out of here... But here is my advice - watch your feet, try not to stumble, stalker!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_512">
        <text>Do you threaten me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5121">
        <text>Okay, okay.. don't be so nervous... I was just curious and you grip the gun at once! No more questionnaires. Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_61">
        <text>Documents you say.... This is right what I have come here for, to your consideration. And now you will give them to me and take off. You got that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6111">
        <text>I'll have something to offer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6121">
        <text>Listen, bro, don't make my head spin. Lets make a deal. I'll give you fair money, you won't regret that.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6131">
        <text>Listen, I really need these documents. We'll see what you've got - and I think we'll make a deal...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8011">
        <text>It's dark here, pitch-dark. Burers are around there... And why have you agreed? How did you get here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8021">
        <text>Follow your way, stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8031">
        <text>I can't stand when my natter is interrupted. In short, I've come here for important documents. If you found anything - take it out, otherwise you'll have many troubles. If you found nothing, get lost and don't waste my time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8041">
        <text>I hate, when the talk is interrupted! Take out the documents, if you don't want to stay here forever.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_9">
        <text>Ok</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_91">
        <text>Oh, damn it, take them. These are not really important documents.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dar_explorer_dialog_92">
        <text>Bye.</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
