    <string id="bar_arena_actor_afraid">
        <text>The battle is cancelled. Candidate is startled and haven't arrived to the arena.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_10">
        <text>10 seconds have passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_20">
        <text>20 seconds have passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_30">
        <text>30 seconds have passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_40">
        <text>40 seconds have passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_50">
        <text>50 seconds have passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_60">
        <text>A minute has passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_70">
        <text>A minute and 10 seconds passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_80">
        <text>A minute and 20 seconds have passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_90">
        <text>A minute and a half passed!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_begin">
        <text>The battle has begun!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_bloodsucker">
        <text>Attention everyone! The new round begins soon on the Arena! Blood-thirsty and always hungry Bloodsucker in the left corner! And, is it a man in the right corner? \nOh, yes it is! Everyone calls him Branded one!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_burer">
        <text>Attention everyone! The new round begins soon on the Arena! He is familiar with kung-fu, he can bend the spoons, he's Burer! And a hero, whos pursue will never \nend! Everyone calls him Branded one!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_dead">
        <text>And so! The opponent has defeated the candidate. That was worth seeing!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_lose">
        <text>And so! The contender managed to knock down the enemy, but failed to fit in the time given and therefore lost!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_pseudodog">
        <text>Attention everyone! The new round begins soon on the Arena! A warm and fuzzy, but extremely spiteful Pseudo-dog in the left corner! And the came-from-nowhere \nand going-to-nowhere man in the right corner. Everyone calls him Branded one!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_savage">
        <text>Attention everyone! The new round begins soon on the Arena! You know him, and you love him. While he hates you. The Beast in the left corner! And in the right \ncorner, still alive, Branded one!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_snork">
        <text>Attention everyone! The new round begins soon on the Arena! An expert of matrial arts and proper nurition Snork in the left corner! And a man without the past. \nEveryone calls him Branded one!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_timeout">
        <text>Time is up! The contender has lost, but is still struggling for his life!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_arena_fight_victory">
        <text>And so! The candidate was in time to knock down the opponent and won the match!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_attack">
        <text>As you wish!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_crush_attract_actor">
        <text>Stalker, pal, I pray you don't leave! Help us! The mercenaries taken down our copter, and now finish us off they will... There are wounded among us and we need you help!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_crush_heli_down">
        <text>Ha… That's it, no more of puny chopter! Now your turn, governmental rats!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_crush_start_heli">
        <text>Well okay Wolfhound that's it. The military copter is comming here. Now they'll crush you like dummies!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_escape">
        <text>Guys, ecologist has run away! All after him, c'mon!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_hit">
        <text>Branded One, stop them, will ya?!?!? They'll do us in!!!!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_spam_1">
        <text>Shove it, jackass! Finish the school first, then set ultimatums!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_spam_2">
        <text>If you attack, I'll destroy the information! Keep yourselves off my works!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_spam_3">
        <text>If you don't want me to destory the research records, keep away!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_ecolog_spam_4">
        <text>Wolfhound, shepherd your dogs away, before lose their tails!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_attack">
        <text>Enough, this talkie is over! Seize him!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_attack_attract_actor">
        <text>Buddy, get over here, I've got a job for you. Together we'll polish off governmental rats!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_attack_spy">
        <text>Branded one. You, son of a bitch, will pay for that setup-trap.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_chase">
        <text>They're going for us! Branded One, stop them!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_spam_1">
        <text>Damn it you egghead jerk! Either you gimme the records or you'll leave here in a coffin!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_spam_2">
        <text>Kruglov, I'm not familiar with Latin but I AM with weapons! Should I ask them to beg you, or you will give up info yourself?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_spam_3">
        <text>Hey, dean, you're a clever person! Give us the information and get lost!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_freedom_spam_4">
        <text>Kruglov, didn't you understand? We've knocked down your flying blighter, and we need the info you're carrying! After you hand it over to us, you and your lads can cheese it! This is your last chance to get out of here! Gimme the flash-drive and get lost!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_psih_come">
        <text>Urgently rush here! Near the Radar my guys have caught a crazy stalker, now trying to interrogate him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_dolg_1_hit">
        <text>Branded one, are you off the hook? Stop shooting immediately! This is an order!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_dolg_2_hit">
        <text>Branded one, stop firing right now! If you disobey the order, you are dead!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_dolg_3_hit">
        <text>Branded one. You are banished from the grouping for violating the code of Duty. From now on you are our enemy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_dolg_kill">
        <text>Branded one, you just disobeyed the order! Now you die! The Duty never forgive it!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_nodolg_1_hit">
        <text>Stop firing! On the territory of Duty shooting is prohibited! The disobeying will be punished!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_nodolg_2_hit">
        <text>Attention! For violating the law on weapon usage on the territory of the Duty, Branded one has been proclaimed a criminal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bar_territory_nodolg_kill">
        <text>Attention! A murderer has been found! Everyone within the Duty perimeter is ordered to eliminate the murderer!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_1">
        <text>Сталкер, помоги! На нас напали наемники, половина наших погибла. Помоги нам, мы в долгу не останемся.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_2">
        <text>Help us break through the ambush near the factory, I've sent you the data. Stay alert, Wolfhound with his cutthroats are near the chopter</text>
    </string>
