<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="Ammo">
        <text>Ammunition</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Weapons1">
        <text>Weapons</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
        <text>11.43x23 FMJ</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
        <text>11.43x23 Hydro</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
        <text>12ı70 Buck</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
        <text>12x76 Dart</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
        <text>12x76 Zhekan</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
        <text>5.45x39 AP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
        <text>5.45x39 FMJ</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
        <text>5.56x45 AP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
        <text>5.56ı45 SS109</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
        <text>7.62x54 7h1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
        <text>7.62ı54R 7Õ14</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
        <text>7.62x54 AP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
        <text>9ı18 FMJ</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x18-pbp">
        <text>9x18 PBP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
        <text>9ı18 PMM</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
        <text>9ı19 FMJ</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
        <text>9x19 PBP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
        <text>9x39 AP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
        <text>9ı39 PAB-9</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
        <text>9ı39 SP5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-gauss">
        <text>Gauss Packs</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-m209">
        <text>M209</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-og-7b">
        <text>OG-7B</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-vog-25">
        <text>VOG-25</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ammo-vog-25p">
        <text>VOG-25P</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
        <text>Base cartridge for Colt1911, Sig220, USP Compact, Desert Eagle. It has plane core with tunicary bullet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
        <text>It is so called "Hydroshock". Cartridge has improved characteristics for Colt1911, Sig220, USP Compact, Desert Eagle. \nExpansive strong stop effect.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x70-buck">
        <text>Shooting cartrige. For shot-guns “ŒZ-34, BÃ-12, Winchester-1300,SPAS-12. Effective range up to 30 meters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-dart">
        <text>Plumose bullet. For shot-guns “Œ«-34, ¡Ã-12, Winchester-1300,SPAS-12. Effective range up to 150 meters.Increased \nrange and armour-piercing effect. It's an expensive cartrige.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-zhekan">
        <text>It's cartrige with hevy bullet. For shot-guns “Œ«-34, ¡Ã-12, Winchester-1300,SPAS-12. Effective range up to 100 \nmeters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-ap">
        <text>Armour-piercing cartrige for mashine-guns ¿Í-74, ¿Í-74”. Inproved armour-piercing effect and decreased stop effect.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
        <text>Basic cartrige for machine-guns ¿Í-74, ¿Í-74”.Plane core with tunicary bullet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ap">
        <text>Armour-piercing bullet . For storm rifles L85, LR300, Sig550, G36, FN2000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
        <text>Standard NATO cartrige well known under belgium index SS109. For storm rifles L85, LR300, Sig550, G36, FN2000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
        <text>Cheap in production modification of the sniper cartrige. For sniper rifles SVD, SVU-¿C and PKM machine-gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
        <text>Sniper cartrige. For sniper rifles SVD, SVU-AC and PKM machine-gun. Improved accuracy and range. Expensive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-ap">
        <text>Armour-piercing bullet. For sniper rifles SVD, SVU-AC and PKM machine-gun.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-fmj">
        <text>Basic cartrige for pistols PM, PB, Fort-12. Plane core with tunicary bullet. Slight armour-piercing effect.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pbp">
        <text>\nCartrige with improved characteristics for pistols PM, PB, Fort-12. The perfect combination of the armour-piercing and \nstop bullet effects.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pmm">
        <text>\nCartrige with improved characteristics for pistols PM, PB, Fort-12. Due to more high start speed of the bullet it is much \nmore effective as common 9x18 FMJ. Slightly improved armour-piercing effect.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-fmj">
        <text>\nBasical cartrige for pistol HPSA, Walther P-99, Beretta92FS and pistol-machinegun HK MP5. It's common tunicary bullet. \nSlight armour-piercing effect.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-pbp">
        <text>\nCartrige with improved characteristics fror pistol HPSA, Walther P-99, Beretta92FS and pistol-machinegun HK MP5. It is \nvery effective cartrige. The bullet is expansive with armour-piercing core. It's an expensive ammunition.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-ap">
        <text>\nArmour-piercing cartrige for machine-guns "Groza", "Val" and special sniper rifle "Vintorez". Its speed is subsoniÒ , but \ndue to special bullet construction pierced the most kind of flak jackets at 300 meter range.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-pab9">
        <text>The cartrige for machine-gun "Groza", "Val" and spesial sniper rifle "Vintorez". It's later and cheeper in manufacturing \nversion of the armour-piercing cartrige. Its speed is subsonic but due to special construction pierce the most types of \nflak jackets upto 300 meter range.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-sp5">
        <text>Sniper cartrige for machine-gun "Groza", "Val" and special sniper rifle "Vintorez". Its speed is subsonic but due to heavy \nbullet (lead core) of special construction pierce the most types of the flak jackets up to 400 meter range.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-gauss">
        <text>Energetic capacities with finished destructive elements in the magazine for Gauss rifle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m209">
        <text>Grenade for under barrel grenade cup discharge M203 (LR-300, G36, Sig550, L85) and for integrated grenade cup \ndischarge FN2000.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-og-7b">
        <text>Grenade for RPG-7V</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25">
        <text>Grenade for under barrel grenade cup discharge GP30 (AK74) for integrated under barrel "Groza" part and for revolver \ntypeof grenade cup discharge RG-6.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25p">
        <text>Grenade for under barrel grenade cup discharge GP30 (AK74) for integrated under barrel "Groza" part for grenade cup \ndischarge of revolver type RG-6. Right before the explosion grenade VOG-25P jumps one meter increasing defeating \nability.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-f1">
        <text>Hand defensive grenade. Defeat splinter range is up to 100 meters. You should fire it out of the cover.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-gd05">
        <text>Smoke grenade.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-rgd5">
        <text>Atacking hand grenade. Splinter defeat radius is up to 25 meters.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan">
        <text>This is the weapon of the russian army elite. It has been developed to replace fusty Ak74. There are not only inner \nmechanisms agile but also the hole barrel box with barrel itself. So the shooter feels recoil only after second bullet going \nout. As a resut more acccuracy by aiming. Only expierenced stalkers can afford this weapon. Magazine capacity 30 \ncartriges. Ammunition 5.45x39 FMJ, armour-piercing bullet 5.45x39 AP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
        <text>Grenade cup discharge for AK-74. Ammunition for under barrel compartment VOG-25 and VOG-25P.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
        <text>Crenade cup discharge for Sig550, LR300, G36, L85A2. Ammunition for the under barrel compartnent are grenades \nM209.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74">
        <text>Kalashnikov machine-gun 5.45 mm gauge. Kalashnikov machine-gun was developed according the doctrine of that time-\nas mich as possible cheap, reliable and simple, at the same time handling and firing accuracy was a little bit poor. It is the \nweapon of the middle level in the zone. Magazine capacity 30 cartridges. Basic ammunition 5.42x39 FMJ, armour-piercing \nbullet 5.45x39 AP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u">
        <text>For its size and weight AKS-74U is close to pistol-machine-gun but due to the bullet and mechanism it is consider to be \nshorten machine-gun. As merits of AKS-74U it can be noticed high mobility in the cabined conditions, ability of the secret \nwearing, high bullet piercing ability. Disadvanteges are shot aiming distance not remarkable bullet stopping ability, high \nprobability of the overheating. Magazine capacity 30 cartridges. Basic ammunition-5.45x39 FMJ, armour-piercing \ncartridge 5.45x39 AP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta">
        <text>American army and many other military and law-enforcement formation as well in the USA as in other countries are armed \nwith beautiful Beretta. Gauge is 9mm. Magazine capacity 15 cartridges. Basic ammunition 9x19 FMJ, ammunition with \nimproved characteristics 9x19 PBP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16">
        <text>Very little damage.\nPoor accuracy.\nNegligible rate of fire.\nStrong recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: you have to reload to often, but fire buck.\nCommon hunt rifle. Nothing special. One of the wide spreaded novice's weapon. Ammunition: 12x70 Buck - case-shot, \n12x76 Zhekan - heavy bullet, 12x76 Dart-plumose bullet for long range fire.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt1911">
        <text>Medium damage.\nNot bad accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nStrong recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: slow but powerful weapon; small magazine.\nOld good Colt. Came across the hole century with honor, and celebrate its centenary in the Zone. The most long-living \narmy pistol. Gauge is 0.45 ACP. Magazine capacity 7 cartridges. Basic ammunition 11.43x23 FMJ, ammunition with \nimproved characteristics 11.43x23 Hydro.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-desert-eagle">
        <text>Great damage.\nNot bad accuracy.\nVery low rate of fire.\nTERRIBLE RECOIL.\nPoor reliability.\nFeatures: small magazine, expensive cartriges. \nFeatures: This pistol is heavy but youcan hunt for deer with it :).\nThis hero was carried in the Zone by big things lover. Somehow not in its elefant hunting version 0.50 gauge but in 0.44 \ngauge Magnum variant. So it was transfered into simple army guns rank, instead of extra-large. Its disadvantages are \ngreat weight and poor reliability. It looks very solid-it's the fact. It is the weapon of the amateur stalker, but reach one. \nMagazine capacity 8 cartridges. Basical ammunition 11.43x23 FMJ, ammunition with improved characteristics 11.43x23 \nHydro. \n\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fn2000">
        <text>Very bad damage.\nGood accuracy.\nVery high rate of fire.\nVery small recoil.\nPoor reliability.\nFeatures: Integrated grenade cup discharge and optical sight x 1.5 perfect balance.\nMachine-gun, grenade cup discharge complex with computer controlled sight-module of fire management and 40mm \ngauge grenade cup discharge. Magazine capacity 30 cartridges. Basic ammunition - 5.56x45 SS109, armour-piercing \ncartridge 5.56 AP. Ammunition for under barrel discharge grenade M209. It is the weapon of the veteran and master.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort">
        <text>Poor damage.\nPoor accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nWeek recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: one of the best pistols for this type of cartridge but loses more simple samples in reliability.\nPistor of police department ukrainian manufactured repaced morally and phisically archaic PM of the Soviet times. Medium \nreliability. It is more accurate as PM, magazine capacity 12 cartridges and more comfortable handle. Basic ammunition \n9x18 FMJ, ammunition with improved characteristics 9x18 PMM and 9x18 PBP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36">
        <text>Very bad damage.\nGood accuracy.\nVery high rate of fire.\nReliable.\nFeatures: integrated optical sight x1.5\nStorm rifle G36 is the first class model of the modern german weapon. It is light weighted, reliable and comfortable. \nMagazine capacity 30 cartridges. Basic ammunition 5.56x45 SS109, armour-piersing cartridge 5.5645 AP. Ammunition for \nunder barrel discharger - grenades M209. It is the weapon for veteran or master.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss">
        <text>Enormous damage.\nPerfect accuracy.\nVery low rate of fire.\nWeek recoil.\nReliable.\nFeatures: this kind of weapon requires special accouterments\nSniper rifle, created inthe Zone. Almost noiseless, requires artifact energy to fire. Very seldom and useful thing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza">
        <text>Great damage.\nGood accuracy.\nResonable recoil.\nHigh rate of fire.\nGood reliability.\nFeaturess: very comfortable and mobile weapon, only 20 cartridges in the magazine. Machine-gun grenade cup \ndischarge complex "Groza" OC-14. It is very comfortable variant of the storm rifle. Compact, powerful, universal, \nreliable. It is the weapon of the experienced stalker-novice hardly got enough money for it. This weapon is very popular \nby military stalker. Magazine capacity 20 cartriges. Basic ammunition 9x39 PAB-9, armour-piercing cartridge 9x39 PAB-9, \n9x39 SP5-sniper cartridge. For grenade cup discharge VOG-25 and VOG-25 grenades are suitable.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hpsa">
        <text>Little damage.\nBad accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nResonable recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFatures: recoil is a little bit sharp.\nIt is an expierenced stalker weapon. Brauning High Power condsider to be one of the best pistols of the 20th century. \nReliable and powerful, with good accuracy. Magazine capacity 13 cartridges. Basic ammunition 9x19 FMJ, ammunition \nwith improved characteristics 9x19 PBP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-l85">
        <text>Medium damage.\nGood accuracy.\nMedium rate of fire.\nStrong recoil.\nVery bad reliability.\nFeatures: optical sight in basic version.\nAfter Great Britain changed this rifle to german G36 in 2008, it appeared on the black market in great quantity. It isn't \nraritet in the Zone. The only merit of this rifle is good accuracy of the first shoot and basic optical sight of x4 zoom. It is \nnot reliable. By firing a burst a barrel leads away. Magazine capacity 30 cartriges. Ammunition - 5.56x45 SS109, armour - \npiercing cartridge 5.56x45 AP. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-lr300">
        <text>Medium damage.\nGood accuracy.\nHigh rate of fire.\nresonable recoil.\nPoor reliability.\nFeatures: none\nLR-300 it is a development of AR-15. LR-300 means light rifle of 300 meters effective fire range. One of the reason of \nhigh fire accuracy is perfect soft sear. High mobility and handling provides fast aiming. Dirtying is its enemy. It is the \nweapon of the expierenced stalker. Magazine capacity 30 cartriges. Basic ammunition -5.56x45 SS109, armour-piercing \ncartridge 5.56x45 AP. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5">
        <text>Very small damage.\nVery poor accuracy.\nVery high rate of fire.\nWeek recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: very light-weighted mobile weapon.\nOne of the best pistol-machine-gun in its class. It is the weapon of  S.W.A.T.s, army and police in many contries. After \nreplacing planty of it appeared in black markets. It is comfortable weapon in the Zone for close combat. Magazine \ncapacity 30 cartriges. Basic ammunition 9x19 FMJ, ammunition with imroved characteristics 9x19 PBP.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pb">
        <text>Very small damage.\nVery poor accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nVery week recoil.\nSatisfactory reliability.\nFeatures: the weight of the muffler slightly reduces jumping of the barrel but also makes it less mobile. The pistol with \nintegrated muffler. The weapon of the USSR S.W.A.T.. Moraly archaic. Magazine capacity 7 cartridges. The only merit is \nsilent shoot. Basic ammunition 9x18 FMJ, ammunition with improved characteristics 9x18 PMM and 9x18 PBP.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pm">
        <text>Very small damage.\nAlmost lack of accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nWeek recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: one of the cheapest and reliable pistols.\nThe most spreaded pistol of the Soviet epoch in the Zone. Reliable, comfortable, cheap with magazine capacity of 7 \ncartridges. Not enough power, and not satisfactory accuracy. It is the weapon of the novice-stalker. Basic ammunition \n9x18 FMJ, ammunition with improved characteristics 9x18 PMM and 9x18 PBP.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg-6">
        <text>Specific weapon. Revolver grenade cup discharge. For special missions such as mopping-up mutants of a great territory, \nkilling especially hardy creatures, atack the  enemy grouping  base. Ammunition VOG-25 and VOG-25P \ngrenades. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rpg7">
        <text>The old grenade cup charge of the soviet times. There is planty of it on the military wearhouses. It from here grenade \ncup discharge is taken to the Zone. It's not common weapon for stalkers. Great weight, dimensions and very specific use \nmake it unpopular. Though, for special missions such as mopping-up mutants of a great territory, killing especialy hardy \ncreatures, attack enemy grouping base, this weapon can be useful. Ammunition SG-7V  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig220">
        <text>Medium damage.\nNot bad accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nNormal recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: small magazine.\nSigSauer P220 appeared in 1975. Reliable like swiss clock. Due to the  perfect characteristics it is admited in the whole \nworld. Gauge is 0.45ACP. Magazine capacity i7 cartridges. Basic ammunition 11.43x23 FMJ, ammunition with improved \ncharacteristics 11.43x23 Hydro </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig550">
        <text>Medium damage.\nVery good accuracy.\nHigh rate of fire.\nVery week recoil.\nNormal reliability.\nFeatures: none\nOne of the latest swiss storm rifle for NATO cartridge 5.56 gauge. its accuracy, soft recoil and high reliability confirmed \nby swiss armourer reputation. Magazine capacity 30 cartridges. Basic ammunition 5.56x45 SS109, armour-piercing \ncartridge 5.56x45 AP. Ammunition for grenade cup discharge M209. It is the weapon of master or veteran.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-spas12">
        <text>Very great damage.\nPoor accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nStrong recoil.\nNormal reliability.\nFeatures: it can shoot with case-shot.\nSmooth-bored rifle SPAS-12 was developed in end of the 1970th as universal weapon for police and military. SPAS-12 ie \nremarkable for its high reliability, flexability in use, but this weapon is heavy and comlex in mechanisms, and as the result \nhigh price. It is the best weapon in the Zone for close combat. Maazine capacity 8 cartridges. Ammunition: 12x70 Buck-\ncase-shot, 12x76 Zhekan-heavy bullet, 12x76 Dart plumose bullet for long range shooting. \n\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd">
        <text>Very heavy damage.\nPerfect accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nVery strong recoil.\nGood reliability.\nFeatures: it is hard to fire in motion.\nSVD used to participate in all special operations in the Soviet and Russian armies, and consider to be reliable and \ncomfortable model of the weapon. It is prefered by "Duty" grouping in the Zone- mutant's hunters. It is not cheap by \nTrader. You can get it also by duty of the perimeter control  tower. But there are few bolds. Basic ammunition 7.62x54 \n7H1, armour-piercing cartridge 7.62x54 AP, sniper ammunition with improved characteristics 7.62x54 7H14. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu">
        <text>Very bad damage.\nExcellent accuracy.\nLow rate of fire.\nVery strong recoil.\nReliable.\nFeatures: it's not easy to fire in motion.\nIt is modern variant of the Dragunov's rifle performed in bull-pup scheme. It is very comfortable to travel along the Zone \nwith, compact model of the powerful automatic sniper rifle. It's to complicate to get it.The only way to take it from a \nmilitary stalker in the battle. Magazine capacity 10 cartridges. Basic ammunition -7.62x54 7H1, armour-piercing cartridge \n- 7.62x54 AP, sniper ammunition with improved characteristics 7.62x54 7H14.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-toz34">
        <text>Common hunt rifle. Nothing special.One of the most widespread weapon among novices. Ammunition 12x70Buck-case-\nshot, 12x76Zhekan-heavy bullet, 12x76 Dart-plumose bullet for great range fire.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-usp">
        <text>It is grand gun for veteran stalker. German quality. Powerful, reliable and expensive. It is a variant with 0.45ACP gauge. \nMagazine capacity 8 cartridges. Basical ammunition 11.43x23 FMJ, ammunition with improved characteristics 11.23x23 \nHydro.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val">
        <text>It was created on the base of the noisless sniper rifle "Vintorez", the main difference is folding rifle butt. It is intended for \nuse in special operations in conditions where noiseless and flameless shooting is needed. Both of these guns are \nworthwhile. Magazine capacity is 20 cartrdiges. Basic ammunition 9x39 PAB-9, armour-piercing cartridge 9x39 AP, 9x39 \nSP5 - sniper cartridge.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez">
        <text>\nSpasial sniper rifle. Intended for noisless and flameless fire. Contains integrated muffler. It is 'respectable' gun in the \nZone. Pierces any body armour, which can be worn without outside help from the distance of 400 meter almost noiseless. \nIt's the weapon of the expierienced stalkers and veterans. Basical ammunition - 9x39 PAB-9, armour-piercing cartrige \n9x39 AP, 9x39 SP5 sniper cartrige.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-walther">
        <text>The new workmate for James Bond. P99 is a perfect gun remarkable for its reliability and accuracy, especially in 9mm \nmodification. The magazine capacity is 16 cartriges. Basical ammunition 9x19 FMJ, ammunition with improved \ncharacteristics 9x19 PBP</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-wincheaster1300">
        <text>American smoth-bore pump gun. It is constructed to be used in the most difficult conditions, that's why perfect fits the \nZone. It includes ati-corrosion parts and under barrel magazine for six cartriges. Ammunitions: 12x70 Buck-case-shot, \n12x76 Zhekan-heavy bullet, 12x76 Dart-plumose bullet for great range shooting.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="grenade-f1">
        <text>\nF1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="grenade-gd05">
        <text>\nGD-05</text>
    </string>
    <string id="grenade-rgd5">
        <text>\nRGD-5</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-abakan">
        <text>\nAN-94 "Abakan"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
        <text>\nGP-30</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
        <text>\nM203</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-ak74">
        <text>\nAK-74</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-ak74u">
        <text>\nAKS-74U</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-beretta">
        <text>\nBeretta 92FS</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-bm16">
        <text>\nBM-16</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-colt1911">
        <text>\nColt 1911A1</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-desert-eagle">
        <text>\nIMI Desert Eagle</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-fn2000">
        <text>\nFN2000</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-fort">
        <text>\nFort-12</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-g36">
        <text>\nH&K G36</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-gauss">
        <text>Gauss rifle</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-groza">
        <text>OC-14 "Storm"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-hpsa">
        <text>FN HPSA</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-l85">
        <text>L85A2</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-lr300">
        <text>ZM LR300</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-mp5">
        <text>H&K MP5A3</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-pb">
        <text>PB</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-pm">
        <text>PM(Makarov)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-rg-6">
        <text>RG-6</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-rpg7">
        <text>RPG-7B</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-sig220">
        <text>SigSauer P220</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-sig550">
        <text>SiG 550</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-spas12">
        <text>Franchi SPAS12</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-svd">
        <text>SVD "Dragunov"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-svu">
        <text>SVU-AC</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-toz34">
        <text>TOZ-34</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-usp">
        <text>H&K USP Compact</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-val">
        <text>This string was added automatically</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-vintorez">
        <text>This string was added automatically</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-walther">
        <text>This string was added automatically</text>
    </string>
    <string id="wpn-wincheaster1300">
        <text>This string was added automatically</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
