	<string id="bar_arena_actor_afraid">
		<text>The fight is cancelled. The challenger got scared and didn't come out to fight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_10">
		<text>10 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_20">
		<text>20 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_30">
		<text>30 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_40">
		<text>40 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_50">
		<text>50 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_60">
		<text>1 minute has elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_70">
		<text>1 minute and 10 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_80">
		<text>1 minute and 20 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_90">
		<text>1 minute and 30 seconds have elapsed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_begin">
		<text>The fight has started!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_bloodsucker">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena! In the left corner - the bloodthirsty and ever-hungry Bloodsucker! In the right corner - a man? Yes, a man! They call him the Marked One!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_burer">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena! In the left corner - Buhrer, the spoon-bending Kung-Fu master. In the right corner - the man whose search will never end! They call him the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_dead">
		<text>So the challenger has been killed! What a surprise!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_lose">
		<text>So the challenger killed his opponent but didn't do it in time! He loses the fight!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_pseudodog">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena. In the left corner -  the white, fluffy but unbelievably angry Pseudodog! In the right corner - the man who came from nowhere and is heading in the same direction. They call him the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_savage">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena. In the left corner - you know him, you love him. But he hates you! It's the Beast! In the right corner - the Marked One and he's...still alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_snork">
		<text>Attention! Attention! A new fight is about to start in the Arena! In the left corner - the martial arts and healthy lifestyle specialist - Snork! In the right corner - the man with no past. They call him the Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_timeout">
		<text>Time's up! The challenger lost but he's still fighting for his life!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_victory">
		<text>So the challenger killed his opponent in time and won!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_attack">
		<text>As you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_attract_actor">
		<text>Friend, please don't go! Help us! The anarchists shot down our helicopter and are coming to finish us off. We have wounded here, we need your help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_heli_down">
		<text>Ha-ha, there it goes. No more chopper for you government rats. You're next!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_start_heli">
		<text>You've really done it this time Wolfhound. A military chopper is coming to make mincemeat out of you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_escape">
		<text>The professor escaped! Find Kruglov immediately! He couldn't have got very far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_hit">
		<text>Marked One, help me!!! They're killing me!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_1">
		<text>You wish, dog! Go back to school before giving ultimatums. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_2">
		<text>If you attack I'll destroy the information. You'll get nothing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_3">
		<text>If you don't want me to destroy the research documents, stay away!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_4">
		<text>Wolfhound, take your dogs and get out of here while you can still walk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack">
		<text>OK, the time for talk is over. Here comes the shooting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack_attract_actor">
		<text>Hey man, come here! Let's finish these government rats off together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack_spy">
		<text>You bastard, you're gonna pay for setting us up. Mark my words, Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_chase">
		<text>They're following us?! Stop them, Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_1">
		<text>You scientists are all stupid. I'm gonna make it simple: either you give me the documents or you leave here in a plastic bag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_2">
		<text>Kruglov, I don't know Latin but I'm fluent in violence. Would you like me to speak that to you or are you going to give me the information I need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_3">
		<text>Professor, you're a clever man. Give me the information and you're free to go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_4">
		<text>Kruglov, you don't get it do you? We shot down your stupid chopper and we need the information you are carrying. Once you give it to us you can take your mates and get the hell out of here. This is your last chance: give me the flash drive and piss off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_psih_come">
		<text>Get over here, quick! My boys picked up a crazy stalker by the Radar. We're trying to get some info out of him right now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_1_hit">
		<text>Marked One, are you crazy? Stop firing NOW! That's an order!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_2_hit">
		<text>Marked One, stop firing NOW! Do as I say or you're a dead man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_3_hit">
		<text>You are expelled from the group for breaking the Duty Code, Marked One. You are now our enemy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_kill">
		<text>Marked One, you disobeyed an order! You're a dead man - Duty does not forgive things like this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_1_hit">
		<text>Stop firing! Firing on Duty territory is not permitted! Those who break the rules will be punished!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_2_hit">
		<text>Attention! The Marked One has been declared a criminal for breaking the law and firing inside Duty territory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_kill">
		<text>Attention! There is a killer on Duty territory. Find him and destroy him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_1">
		<text>Stalker, help us! We were attacked by mercenaries and half of our team were killed. Help and I promise you won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_2">
		<text>Help us fight through the ambush by the factory, I transferred the co-ordinates to you. Be careful, Wolfhound and his cutthroats are by the helicopter.</text>
	</string>
