<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="Agroprom">
        <text>Agroprom</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Ameba">
        <text>Ameba</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Anomalies">
        <text>Anomalies</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Artifacts">
        <text>Artifacts</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Bald">
        <text>Spring-board.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Bar">
        <text>Bar</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Darkdolina">
        <text>Dark Valley</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Darklab">
        <text>Darklab</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Deadcity">
        <text>Dead city</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Electra">
        <text>Electra</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Escape">
        <text>Escape</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Fuzz">
        <text>Fuzz</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Garbage">
        <text>Garbage</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Gravi">
        <text>Gravi</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Lift">
        <text>Lift</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Locations">
        <text>Locations</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Meat">
        <text>Merry-go-round</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Military-loc">
        <text>Army base</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Phenomena">
        <text>Phenomena</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Pripiat">
        <text>\nPripiat</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Radar">
        <text>\nRed forest and Antens</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Radioactive">
        <text>Radioactive hotbed</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Rostok">
        <text>Rostok</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Rusty">
        <text>Rusty hair</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Stancia">
        <text>\nChernobyl Atomic Power Station</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Story-2006">
        <text>year 2006, April 12, 2:33 pm.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Story-2008">
        <text>year 2008</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Story-2010">
        <text>year 2010</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Story-raid">
        <text>Large-scale breakthrough into the Zone</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Surge">
        <text>Surge</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Surge-story">
        <text>Surge story</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Time">
        <text>Time machine</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Yantar">
        <text>Yantar</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Zharka">
        <text>Fryer</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Zone">
        <text>Zone</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Zone-story">
        <text>Zone stories</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-ameba-mica">
        <text>Mica</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-ameba-slime">
        <text>Slime</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-ameba-slug">
        <text>Slug</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-blood">
        <text>Stone blood</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-cristall">
        <text>Crystal</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-cristall-flower">
        <text>Crystal flower</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-drops">
        <text>Drops</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-dummy-battery">
        <text>Battery</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-dummy-dummy">
        <text>Dummy</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
        <text>Glass-beads</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
        <text>Pellicle</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-dummy-spring">
        <text>Spring</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-electra-flash">
        <text>Flash</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-electra-moonlight">
        <text>Moonlight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-electra-sparkler">
        <text>Sparkler</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-fireball">
        <text>Fireball</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
        <text>Kolobok</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-gold-fish">
        <text>Gold fish</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-gravi">
        <text>Gravi</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-medusa">
        <text>Medusa</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-mincer-meat">
        <text>Meat</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-night-star">
        <text>Nightstar</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-rusty-kristall">
        <text>Crystal thorn</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
        <text>Sea-urchin</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-rusty-thorn">
        <text>Thorn</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-soul">
        <text>Soul</text>
    </string>
    <string id="af-vyvert">
        <text>Twist</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_ameba">
        <text>The nature of this medusa-like vermin jumping out of the ground is not investigated. By contact injures like strong acid \nburn. It generates such artifacts as "af-ameba-slime", "af-ameba-slug", af-ameba-mica"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_bald">
        <text>This anomaly was found one of the first in the Zone in 2008. It delivers a blow with its gravity force like air-blast by \nexplosion. She resides in the same place average once a week. During its life time it changes force of effect, which varies \nfrom bruise to instant death "launching body on the orbit". It can be recognized by distorted air above it, whirling leaves \nand typical red-drown spots; these are places of loser's and stupid novice's starts. Can be well discovered by all kind of \ndetectors and by throwing different metal things into it. Randomly generates tree kind of artifacts "Medusa" "Crystal Flower" \nand "Night star"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_electra">
        <text>This anomalous formation accumulates static electricity in some area in radius of 40 feet. Disturbed anomaly explodes \nwith dozen of lightning. Electric shock almost always is fatal. Typical feature of this anomaly is visible bluish mist over it. It \ncan be well disclosed by any kind of detectors, and by throwing different metal things into it. Randomly generates such \nartifacts as "Electra", "Electra flesh" or "Electra moon light".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fuzz">
        <text>It's anomaly vegetation. By approaching it egests cloud of particles which injures human like stinging sell. It generates \ntree \ntypes of seed-artifacts: "Thorn", "Kristal thorn", "Sea urchin".</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_gravi">
        <text>This an anomaly of gravity nature. It's like little black hole. It absorbs with enormous strength everything appeared in radius \nof 30-40 feet into its center. It's very important not to miss the beginning of absorption and don't get into the zone of \nmaximum effect. In this case you won't get only bruises- this anomaly is always fatal dangerous. The anomaly squeezes a body \nin some clod, breaks ones bones and after accumulating some critical mass, in moment of nucleus discharge, tears this body \napart. In this moment anomaly throws about products of compression, forming new artifacts. During its life time this \nanomaly doesn't change location and slightly alternates power of effect. It resides on one place ca. one week. One can reduce \nits influence carrying on the belt such artifacts as УMedusaФ, УCrystal flowerФ and УNight starФ Can be recognized by seeing \ndistorted air above it, whirling leaves, dismembered animal corpses and typical dark spot in the center on the ground. This \nanomaly can be disclosed only by special detectors, or by throwing any metal things into it. It usually generates tree types of \nartifacts УVyvertФ, УGravityФ and УGolden fishФ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_lift">
        <text>It is harmless anomaly. It allows for some time to forget about terrestrial gravity. In some local place of several feet \nterrestrial gravity greatly decreases. Constant drifting in it allows getting out. The only unfavorable moment is that, you can \nbe easily shot by opponents. It generates УDummy pellicleФ artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_meat">
        <text>The funny name of this anomaly is determined by its effect. When any living being got into it the anomaly lift it up, rotate \nand tears out all extremities. It is extremely dangerous. The nature of this vortex like anomaly isn't clear yet. It can be \nrecognized by noticing light dust vortex and body members of animals and people around it. It's very important not to miss \nthe beginning of absorption and don't get into the zone of maximum effect. It usually generates tree types of artifacts \nУMincer bloodФ, УMincer MeatloafФ and УMincer soulФ. All of the artifacts of this over-nature killing mincer mystically \ninfluence human vital forces.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_radioactive">
        <text>It is the area of high radiation level. It usually higher then 50mR/h. Mostly they are shown on maps. The only advice is to \navoid long presence in it.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_rusty">
        <text>Mutations of these plants led to the appearance of these liana-like spiny plants. By approaching injures.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_time">
        <text>This anomaly surely can be called a miracle. In the radius of several feet the time is slowing down. It doesn't effect the \nhealth but you spend a lot of time to get out from there. You can also smart lure enemies into it and give a flight to your \nimagination. Usually in the center there is an spiral-like artifact "Dummy-glassbeads". You can deactivate this anomaly by \nmeans of it. Subsequently this temporal mine can be very useful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zharka">
        <text>It is slightly visible in inert condition cloud of hot air. By getting any living being into it, it arises a compact burning zone \nwith the temperature of 1500k. Everything within УZharkaФ instantly burns, and mostly dies. The danger of this anomaly is \nbecause of it constant motion by random routes. The positive moment is it disclosures of other anomalies so you can follow it \nwithout surprise. This anomaly can be disclosed only by special detectors, or by throwing any metal things into it. It generates \nsuch artifacts as УZharka dropsФ, УZharka fire ballФ and УZharka crystalФ.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
        <text>It is an artifact produced by "Kholodets" anomaly. It is semi transparent jelly-like formation. this artifact can instantly \nsatiate any person, who puts it on his belt. Moreover it almost in a trice absorbs all radiation out of a bearer and \nimmediately stops bleedings. As side effect can be noticed reinforcement of the fire, electricity and chemical damages. \nThe price is high. Scientific organizations show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
        <text>It is an artifact produced by "Kholodets" anomaly. It is semi transparent jelly-like formation. \nThis artifact mysticaly satiate any organism with nutrition elements at the same time reinforcing common, fire, electricity and \nchemical burns. \nIt is also promotes blood coagulation. Moreover it absorbs all radiation bit by bit out of a bearer's organism. \nThe price isn't high. Scientific organizations show interest in it. \n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
        <text>It is an artifact produced by "Kholodets" anomaly. It is semi transparent jelly-like formation. \nThis artifact mysticaly satiate any organism with nutrition elements at the same time reinforcing common, fire, electricity and \nchemical burns. \nIt is also effects any wounds spopping the bleeding. Moreover it absorbs all radiation out of a bearer's organism. \nThe price is medium. Scientific organizations show interest in it. \n\n\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УMarry go roundФ anomaly. It is ugly reddish formation of compressed polymerized fairy curved \nrests of plants soil and bones. By carrying it on the belt mystically fastens wounds healing, and stops bleeding. Stalkers \nbelieve \nthis artifact contains the power of deceased in this anomaly people. During the healing human's flesh becomes soft and \ntemporarily becomes open to injury. Furthermore healing requires a lot of nutritious substance it makes you hungry. The price \nisn't high because of its wide expansion. Scientific organizations first of all medics and different religious cults show interest \nin \nit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
        <text>Its name accurate describes its appearance. It is a big glancing reddish crystal. Stalkers say it can stop any bleedings, at \nthat making a person hungry and exhausted. Moreover it makes a bearer tolerant to fire but very open for chemical burns. \nThe price is high. The probability of appearance is low. Scientific organizations show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УSpring boardФ anomaly. It's a beautiful formation with glancing surface containing impregnation. \nIt is compressed fairy curved rests of plants and everything that appears in the direct zone of effect of anomaly. By wearing \non one's belt it increases bullet-proof effect. It is radioactive. The price and likelihood of appearance is average. Scientific \norganizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УZharkaФ anomaly. It's drop-alike formation with choppy glanced surface. Stalkers say it stops \nbleedings, at that making a person hungry and exhausted. Moreover it provides a bearer with some tolerance to fire but \nopen for chemical burns. It decreases endurance. The price isn't high. Collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
        <text>The origin of this artifact is unknown. It is a finned shining formation. Very useful artifact for its bearer. It maintain \nbearer springtly and active taking away fatique and hunger. It protects agaist electric discharge. The price is very \nhigh. Scientific organization show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
        <text>The origin of this artifact is unknown. It looks like two hard discs fastened together with slime. Protects a bearer in a close \ncombat against bullet reducing damages. The price is\nhigh. Scientific organization show interest in it.\n\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
        <text>Very rare artifact of unknown origin. It looks like fancy curved spiral sown with shining perl-drops. Reduces hunger and \nnourishes the orgfanism. Every person who carry it on his belt can dispense without food and water endless long time. \nThe artifact reinforces the radiation effect on the human organism. Everybody show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
        <text>Rare artifact of unknown origin. Superfine pellicle of the glass-alike substance with unusual refracting properties. It is \nradioactive. It protects against chemical affection and makes bearer more enduring.The price is high. Scientific \norganization, collectors, jewelers and show business.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
        <text>The origin of this artifact is unknown. It looks like two hard discs fastened together with slime. Protects a bearer in a close \ncombat against bullet reducing damages. It also decreases damage effect delivered by gravitation natured anomalies. \nThe price is very high. Scientific organization show interest in it.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УElectraФ anomaly. It is semi-transparent amorphous sparkling formation, shining from within \nwith small rays of light. It slightly increases endurance and gives some tolerance to the electricity. Besides it reinforced a little \nbit radiation effect on organism. The price is average. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УElectraФ anomaly. It is semi-transparent amorphous sparkling formation, with shining core. It \ngreatly increases endurance, and invulnerable to electric discharge. Besides it reinforced a little \nbit radiation effect on organism. As a result even weak radioactive anomaly turns very dangerous. The price is high. It is \nradioactive. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УElectraФ anomaly. It is semi-transparent amorphous sparkling formation. It slightly increases \nendurance and gives some tolerance to the electricity. Besides it reinforced a little \nbit radiation effect on organism. The price isn't high. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers \nshow interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УZharkaФ anomaly. Its semi-transparent reddish ball shaped formation.Stalkers say it can stop \nany bleedings, at that making a person hungry and exhausted. Besides it grants to the bearer fire tolerance at that making \nopen to chemical burns. The price is average. Collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
        <text>It is rare artifact of unknown origin. It looks like a ball orange size hard and warm by touch. By carring on the belt it gives \nhuman ultranatural tolerance to fire and electricity. However side effect a bit reinforced radiation influence on organism. \nThe price is high. Scientific organization first of all medics show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
        <text>It is an artifact rarely formed by УWhirlpoolФ anomaly. It's a beautiful formation with glancing surface. It is compressed fairy \ncurved rests of plants and everything that appears in the direct zone of anomaly discharge. By wearing on one's belt it \ndicreases harm of animal bites and hits. It is very radioactive. The price is very high. The likelihood of appearance is low. \nScientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
        <text>It is a beautiful artifact formed by УWhirlpoolФ anomaly. It is compressed fairy curved rests of plants and everything that \nappears in the direct zone of effect of anomaly. By wearing on one's belt it dicreases the harm of pokes, hits and bites. It is \nradioactive. The price and likelihood of appearance is average. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest \nin it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УSpring boardФ anomaly. It is compressed fairy curved rests of plants and everything that appears \nin the direct zone of effect of anomaly. It provides minor bullet-proof effect, decreasing the damage degree. It is radioactive. \nThe price isn't high because of its wide expansion. Scientific organizations show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УMarry go roundФ anomaly. It is ugly yellowish formation of compressed polymerized fairy \ncurved rests of plants soil and bones. By carrying it on the belt mystically greatly fastens wounds healing, and stops \nbleeding. Stalkers believe this artifact contains the power of deceased in this anomaly people. During the healing human's \nflesh becomes soft and temporarily becomes open to injury. Furthermore healing requires a lot of nutritious substance it \nmakes you hungry. It is radioactive. The price and likelihood of appearance is average. Scientific organizations first of all \nmedics and different religious cults show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
        <text>It is an artifact rarely formed by УSpring boardФ anomaly. It's a beautiful formation with glancing surface and color \nphosphoric impregnations. At night illuminates everything all around in radius ca 3-6 feet. It is compressed fairy curved rests \nof plants and everything that appears in the direct zone of effect of anomaly. By wearing on one's belt it works like strong \nprotective field that decreased shooting weapon damage. It is very radioactive. The price is high. The likelihood of \nappearance is low. Scientific organizations and militants show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by "rusty hair" anomaly. It is a crystal of foggy dull stone covered with crack. By carrying on the \nbelt it purifies the organism of radiation. Hunger reinforcement is side effect. During usage of this artifact it can happen \nnose and mouth bleeding. It also increases protection against chemical burns and radiation, at that making open to fire \nand electricity. The price is average. Scientific organisations, collectors and jewelers show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by "rusty hair" anomaly. It is light-weighted gray sphere, dense covered with not sharp thorns. By \ncarrying on the belt it almost instantly purifies the organism of radiation but mekes to feel great hunger. During usage of \nthis artifact it can happen bleeding all over the body. It also makes its bearer almost invulnarable chemical burns and \nradiation, at that making open to fire and electricity. The price is high. Scientific organisations, collectors and jewelers show \ninterest in it.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by "rusty hair" anomaly. It is a piece of rust ball shaped with needles around. It is calm by touch. \nBy carrying on the belt it slowly but surely purifies the organism of radiation. Hunger reinforcement is side effect. During \nusage of this artifact it is probabgility of nose and mouth bleeding. It also increases protection against chemical burns \nand radiation, at that making open to fire and electricity. The price is low. Scientific organisations, collectors and jewelers \nshow interest in it.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
        <text>It is rare artifact formed by УMarry go roundФ anomaly. It is ugly red-yellowish formation of compressed polymerized fairy \ncurved rests of plants soil and bones. By carrying it on the belt mystically in several seconds recovers human's health, and \nstops any kind of bleedings. Stalkers believe this artifact contains souls of deceased in this anomaly people. At the same time \nthe body of a bearer becomes open to injuries and requieres a lot of nourishing substance. It is radioactive. The price is very \nhigh. The likelihood of appearance is low. Scientific organizations first of all medics and different religious cults show interest \nin it.\n</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
        <text>It is an artifact formed by УWhirlpoolФ anomaly. It is compressed fairy curved rests of plants and everything that appears in \nthe direct zone of effect of anomaly. By wearing on one's belt it slightly reduces harm of pokes, hits and bites. It is \nradioactive. The price isn't high because of its wide expansion. Scientific organizations show interest in it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_agroprom">
        <text>It is strange place. If you move deep down you appear on a radioactive valley and find a little rusty lake. The whole lake \nis filled with cars remains - it is a big pile of a rusty trash slightly covered with water. You can also find an old institute and \na factory it became overgrown with some mutated vermin. Besides, militants appear very often there recently. It is \nsomething interested for them in this insitute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_bar">
        <text>Grouping "Duty" cleared a place on the outskirts of "Rostok" plant, for own base and for brother stalker can have a rest. \nIt is so to speak oasis in the desert. There are neither anomalies nor monsters. At the local cafe you find stalker bar. \nHere gather stalkers from the whole Zone. Local trader is a bartender there, one might say he keeps this facility. Go \nthere if you want to trade, communicate and get some interesting mission. Well, fresh news you also get there. By the \nway there is a military base to the North, and a dump to the South.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_darkdolina">
        <text>This is the dark valley, it is always darkly and foggy. It rains often. You can find good artifacts there and you can also \neasy kiss you life good-buy. You will meet veterans by all means, they earn money there, pulling artifacts right out of the \nbum. I heard they talk about Sluggers band, they say they appeared again. As a matter of fact who knows may be they \nwere all shot. There's an entrance into the laboratory, but no one returned out of there, so I don't advise to go there... \nMay be dwarfs or may be something worse...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_darklab">
        <text>ѕодземна€ лаборатори€ мрачное местечко, говор€т что там хран€тс€ документы, открывающие тайны «оны, но скорее всего это просто какой-то документальный хлам. Ћежит он на нижних уровн€х лаборатории, там по слухам целые завалы документов, которые когда-то не успели сжечь. Ќу и конечно здесь обретаютс€ одни из самых мрачных представителей подземелий - бюреры и кровососы...  арликов почти никто никогда не видел, говор€т что справитьс€ обычным оружием не получаетс€, пули отскакивают... ¬от, и вроде как кидаютс€ т€желыми булыжниками и металлическими арматурами при помощи странных сил.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_deadcity">
        <text>It is mysterious place. I wasn't there personaly but they say it's a small town lost in the Zone. Thre are such anomalies \naround it nobody can even approach it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_escape">
        <text>This is a  threshold, military border. Novices walk around there growing roots in the Zone. Behind the village in the cellar \nyou find  the trader. I advise not butt into the blockpost and stike a soldiers eyes, they have an order to shoot without \nwarning. But some of them become kinder as they see money. In general if there's no command they can even let you \nthrough...when you're lucky. You cannot kill soldiers, only in emergency. For each killed trader must pay and he is not \nhappy by that kind of things. \n  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_garbage">
        <text>It's a big foul damp after meltdown in 1986 it was filled with piles of radioactive trash-broken crans and machinery. One \ncan find old buildings remains. One can meet mutants. Mostly novices walking around here and bandits. You can find \nminor artifacts but it's better not to stay for a long time here. You can reach other interesting places from here. If you go \nto the North you reach the Rostok plant,the passage to the Dark Valley is to the West and to the East is the road to the \nAgroprom institute. You cannot go to the Dark Valley without radiation protection. The dose of radiation there kill you \nduring one day.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_military-loc">
        <text>It is lost army base old village and little lake there. This village is a terrible place. It teems with different monsters there is \nno end to Bloodsuckers only. On the whole stalkers don't butt into it more often walk round. Terrorists from " Freedom" \ngrouping settled down on the military base territory. If you go furthe into the Zone find yourself in Red Forest and Brain \nBurner which close the way to Prypyat and APP.     </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_pripiat">
        <text>This is the city built long before first meltdown. It wasn't small town, I'd say. It was built specially for the station- the \nplace where workers and engineers could live. But now nobody live there of corse, exept vermin like zombie and \nmutants. Though I wasn't there you cannot go there Brain Burner bars the way. That one who is near the Red Forest \nand Antens, have you heard it? </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_radar">
        <text>It's terrible place. It is not worth to die there, even when you got deep into the Zone. Those antettas called Brain \nBurner. It is so because everyone who approach it goes crazy and wander after that like restless zombie. It remains only \nhuman covers. It is so long nobody came back out of there, fellow, I don't advise you to butt into there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_rostok">
        <text>It's a gloomy plant I'd say. There are many our people lied down...there's no words. There aare a lot of vermins as if they \ngathered there from the whole Zone. But they say there's something important in this plant, something vitally \nnecessary... They butt into it recently because of "Duty" grouping and all died, only cryes could be heard the day long \nint he neighbourhood.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_stancia">
        <text>The station who doesn't  know about it! It is real heart of the Zone its source. Accordind to legends  somewhere in the \nforth energy block situated the thing which can make any of your  wishe true. It is called Monolith, may be you've heard \nit? There's so many legends about the station, one can write a book. ChAPP is the main myetery of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_locations_yantar">
        <text>the legendary Yanter lake, of corse I know! It is dryed out long time ago. It is bad place-death is there. You cannot go \nthere- everyone who butt to deep into goes crazy. Zombie-shallows walk around and as they see you run after, so you \nhave to flee. Mant stalkers died near this lake, and there are only shallow men wander around... If you manage to walk \nround the lake and zombies you will find scientific camp there. They study something there. They were brought by \nhelicopter which regulary delivers provision for them, they digged good in, in general. You can talk to them, they bye \nartifacts and can even give you a mission. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_phenomena_surge_general">
        <text>„ерез равные промежутки времени по «оне проход€т волны выброса гравитационного рода в сочетании с резко повышенным психотропным воздействием. ¬о врем€ этой активности, нахождение в «оне смертельно опасно, по всей территории проход€т невидимые волны, человек без спецоборудовани€ гибнет в считанные секунды, начинает тр€стись земл€, затем следует сери€ вспышек. ярко свет€щеес€ небо и черно-белый мир, глаза не выдерживают слеп€щего солнца. ¬о врем€ выброса можно увидеть фантомные образовани€ и марево на местах гравитационных аномалий.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_phenomena_surge_surge-story">
        <text>√улкое землетр€сение и вспышки молний освещают черные кип€щие облака. —талкер еле успевает забежать в дом - начинаетс€ выброс. ѕрот€жный подземный удар сотр€сает дом. ѕоднимаетс€ пыль, валитс€ с полок мусор. „ерез разбитое окно комнату освещает вспышка неверо€тно €ркого света. ћир тер€ет цвета и сереет. „ерез открытый дверной проем видна улица и лежащий на асфальте почерневший труп слепого пса. ”раганный ветер несет мусор, начинаетс€ самый т€желый момент выброса. «емл€ встает на дыбы, все заливаетс€ мертвым светом. ѕо€вл€етс€ многоголосый гул и грохот, вспышки молний. Ќа полу тр€сутс€ упавшие вещи. —талкер, забившись в угол, прикрывает слепнущие глаза. » вот наступает пик выброса. ѕроисходит последний, самый сильный и страшный удар. ќн дергает землю, ломает деревь€. Ќа мгновение становитс€ темно, а потом свет и свист, сошедшей с ума «оны, вырубает сознание у сталкера...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2006">
        <text>Chernobyl zone was illuminated by brightest intolerable light. On the silver because of light sky clouds were evaporating. \nAfter the instant of full science came rumbling and earth quake. People fell on the groung closing bleeding eyes and ears. \nThe shining appeared above huge territory. Everybody who could run saving his life. It looked from the side as if \nenormous deposits of atomic fuel blown up tearing apart APP and neighbourhood. The governmental troops encircled the \nZone along toward evening. The explosion epicentre is in one kilometer of the APP. Admittedly the whole stuff died in the \nfirst instants. Many people got into the hitting zone. It was impossible to organize some resque operation on account of \nthe electric disturbance which was fataly danger for researchers. In several months after meltdown the crisis situation \nappeared-the Zone proliferated gulfing five kilometers area around it.The most part of governmental troops and \nresearchers instantly died. The panic begun. The residents of the neighbour villages and towns were quickly evacuated. \nThe whole world was threatened with danger, the scale of which one couldn't even imagine.    </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2008">
        <text>It's been two years after dreadfull meltdown happened-the Zone exploded and radioactive clouds covered vast \nterritories. Incredible number of died and missed people, dead animals, blackened buildings distorted woods. Thirty \nkilometers of the territory is encircled by the army, scientists can't give any explanations to what was happened. The \nZone is spreading there weere many anomalies detected in it which cause death-invisible force tears peoples apart, \ninjuries badly producing streaming bleedings. Rare expeditions came across mutated animals, which couldn't appear in \nthe Zone randomly. Disaster, mutants, contamination is a result of some weird phenomenon...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2010">
        <text>First expeditions can go deep into the Zone for several kilometers without fatal danger. Amateur researchers, marauders  \nand pochers appeared in the Zone. They all were called "stalkers". Stalkers travel along the Zone searching for different \nanomalous formations (artifacts) and get money for it from underground traders.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-raid">
        <text>The accurate date is unknown. Army detachements, headed by military stalkers groups, came as big expedition into the \nZone. The purpose is to breack through to the epicenter and destroy the reason of the fatal anomalies appearance or at \nleast find the reason and results of these actions. At the beginning of the game the last army unit, suppotred by the \naviation and armoured machinery went deep into. Almost the whole army expedition, in number of ca. 1000 persons \ndied, the rest settled down in the Zone territory without any hope for salvation...  </text>
    </string>
</string_table>
