<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="general_help">
        <text>Help me!!! I need medikit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_new_task">
        <text>New tasks received.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
        <text>To talk to someone point sight at him and press ‘E’ button.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
        <text>To activate PDA, press 'P' button.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
        <text>To activate map press 'M'.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
        <text>Find artifact in the place pointed on the map and bring it to the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
        <text>Search dead bodies, you may find some useful staff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
        <text>Hand a medikit to this dunce.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
        <text>Press Contact (Ñ). In and on minimap on the screen other stalkers with activated PDA will appear. Their attitude to you will also be stated on the screen. Be careful if you see enemies on the screen. However bandits and, heh, monsters usually don’t use PDA, so you better watch out in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
        <text>Watch out! You’re nearby anomalies. Use bolts to define their borders.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
        <text>Marked, watch out. Next time it may be you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wounded_start">
        <text>Hey, Marked, one stalker just returned from deep raid into Zone. He is wounded and can't move anymore. Help him, may be he know something about Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_help">
        <text>Hey, Marked. There is a badly wounded stalker not far from you, he was coming back after a trip deep inside the Zone. Help him, he may know something about the Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
        <text>Hey, there is some kind of action near you. I send coordinates to you. Check, what are going there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_killed">
        <text>Well, Marked, it’s up to you. This way or another, you’ve passed the examination, but deal with Wolf and his team on your own. Generally I’m waiting for you, got some job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_helped">
        <text>Well done, Marked. If it continues, you’ll acquire many friends. Come into mine, we’ll have a chat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
        <text>empty text</text>
    </string>
	<string id="gar_dolg_warning">
		<text>Stalker, you’ve have intruded territory under Duty control… Any assault attempt on our people will be punished by the mere death.</text>
	</string>     
</string_table>
