<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="no" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="Antirad">
        <text>Anti-rad medications</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Arm-heavy">
        <text>Heavy stalker equipment</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Arm-light">
        <text>Light stalker equip</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Arm-medium">
        <text>Medium stalker equipment</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Binocul">
        <text>Binoculars</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Bread">
        <text>Bread</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Conserva">
        <text>Canned meat "Tourist's breakfast"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Detect1">
        <text>Anomaly detector (DA-2)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Devic">
        <text>Devices and gadgets</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Equipment">
        <text>Equipment and food</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Food">
        <text>Foodstuff</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Kolbasa">
        <text>Sausage "Dietary"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Medi">
        <text>Medications</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Medkit">
        <text>First-aid kit</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Sci2">
        <text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
    </string>
    <string id="Vodka">
        <text>Vodka "Cossacks"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="bandage">
        <text>Bandage</text>
    </string>
    <string id="device-pda">
        <text>PDA</text>
    </string>
    <string id="device-torch">
        <text>Flashlight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
        <text>Protective suit. Costs 530 rubles. Weights 18 kg. Features: Special covering, which protects from aspic and burning fuzz. The thorax and back is protected by \ninner bio-metallic plates. Protects the body from anomalies and damage. Waterproof metal-plstic helmet. Has two oxygen tanks. Specifics: on continous usage \nbecomes worthless - breaks and tears.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
        <text>Protective suit. Costs 140 rubles. Weights 8 kg. Features: Protects the body from week anomalies and light damages. Has an oxygen mask.\nSpecifics: becomes past repair in continous usage - is damaged and breaks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
        <text>Protective suit. Costs 310 rubles. Weights 12 kg. Features: covering, which protects from aspic and burning fuzz. Protects the body from anomalies and \ndamages. Waterproof helmet. Has an oxygen tank. Specifics: becomes past repair in continous usage \n- is damaged and breaks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
        <text>Protective red colored suit with waterproof helmet. Costs 220 rubles. Weights 11 kg. Features: Protects from fire, acid, gases, from various anomalous \ninfluences and Burning fuzz. Increases the defense agains the physical damage. Has two oxygen tanks. Specifics: becomes past repair in continous usage \n- is damaged and breaks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul1">
        <text>Army portable binoculars.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
        <text>Device, which detect the anomaly fields and disturbances, upon the positive reaction produces sound signals. Required to be activated by placing it on the \nbelt.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda1">
        <text>Personal digital assistant. Crucial device in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
        <text>Flashlight with rather powerful lamp. In the conditions of illumination deficit in the Zone appears to be a helpful mate.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
        <text>It remains unidentified who is in charge of baking long loafs in the Zone, however they aren't infected and edible. In any case, not a single stalker has \ncomplained so far.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
        <text>Canned mead from the plundered by stalkers warehouse of foodstuffs of army troops. Hasn't yet been expired.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
        <text>For want of something better this sausage - breakfast, launch and supper of the common stalker.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
        <text>Tasteful and nutrient vodka manufactured by "GSC" corporation. Reduces the influence of radiation, but should not be abused.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
        <text>Reduces the influence of radiation on the ogranism.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
        <text>Wound textile. Indespensable with bleedings.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
        <text>Universal medical set. Allows to cure the wounds of various difficulty degree (injuring, burns, poisoning, etc.)</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
