	<string id="esc_direction_fire">
		<text>Do not attack before I give the order - no itchy trigger fingers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fanat_victory">
		<text>Victory!!! If you're alive, on me! Marked One, get over here - we need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_return_dv">
		<text>Great, Marked One. I'm glad you're alive and decided to pay us a visit. Come over and we'll have a chat. There's a little something coming up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tutorial_end">
		<text>Excellent, your task is complete. Safe to say you've learned the basic skills OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_thanks">
		<text>Marked One, the way to the camp is now open to you. Come over and we'll talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_fox_quest">
		<text>About Sharpshooter, Marked One. Some stalker just came back from a long raid. Fox he's called. Looks like he had a pretty rough time - he's asking for help. Some weird creatures followed him all the way back, he says he won't hold out much longer. I reckon the fella will know a bit about Sharpshooter. You might wanna hurry up though, here are the co-ordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_stalker_death">
		<text>You screwed up, Marked One. The boys died although that ain't your fault. These things happen in the Zone. Anyway, you passed the test so get back here and we'll talk business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_stalker_helped">
		<text>Good man, Marked One. You carry this on and you'll make yourself a few friends. Pay me a visit and we'll talk business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_stalker_killed">
		<text>Well, that wasn't a smart move, Marked One. You passed the test but you're gonna have to deal with Wolf and his goons on your own. Anyways, I'm waiting for you, we got some work to discuss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
		<text>Marked One, the military dug up some cool stuff in Agroprom research institute. I'm interested in it and you probably are too. Get the info and take it to the barman in the stalker's bar. Get to work!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
		<text>Careful! You're right next to the anomalies. Use your bolts to work out their exact location and shape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
		<text>Press Contact ($$ACTION_CONTACTS$$). You can see people within 250 metres of you who have turned their PDAs on in contacts and on your visor minimap. You can also see their attitude towards you. Pay attention if enemies appear although bandits and mutants (ha-ha) don't normally turn their PDAs on, so watch it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
		<text>To activate the map press '$$ACTION_MAP$$'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
		<text>To activate the PDA press '$$ACTION_ACTIVE_JOBS$$'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
		<text>To talk to someone aim at them and press '$$ACTION_USE$$'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
		<text>Find the artifact in the area marked on the map and take it to the trader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
		<text>Marked One, pay attention - it could be you next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
		<text>Give this moron a medkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
		<text>Marked One! Forget the artifact, drop it off later. Run to the trailer by the road, my boys need help there. The idiots had the great idea of shooting at a passing chopper. I've sent you the co-ordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
		<text>Search the bodies - you might find something useful.</text>
	</string>
