<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description">
		<text>Traditional outfit of a bandit - a leather jacket with kevlar elements. It slightly increases bullet and splinter protection. It does not protect from anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name">
		<text>Bandit jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description">
		<text>Produced by one of Kiev's defence research institutes and commissioned by the Duty faction. It is as simple and reliable as the standard PSZ-9 model, but due to the new materials, it provides good protection from bullets and splinters, as well as from weak anomalies. It has no breathing protection system, so its level of radiation protection is low.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9d Duty Armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>A wonderful protective suit for the Zone. It combines excellent anomaly-proof and bullet-proof qualities. It includes the PSZ-9d suit, a closed cycle breathing system and an integrated system of anomalous field suppression. It provides good bullet and splinter protection. It has an average level of anomaly protection and a high level of radiation protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>PSZ-9Md Universal Protection</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_description">
		<text>A SSP-99 chemical protection suit specially designed for the Zone conditions. It is used by scientific expeditions and the eco-stalkers who cooperate with them. It has an integrated air-filtering and air-conditioning system. It is heat and electricity resistant, provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments. It is not designed for combat, so it provides neither bullet, nor splinter protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99 Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>A military exoskeleton prototype. It never went into serial production, because of extreme cost and some design flaws. It is however produced in small batches in small illegal factories outside of Ukraine. This is a third generation exoskeleton. The design defects which used to decrease its mobility were eliminated and the armor was reinforced. It provides excellent bullet and splinter protection. It has a low level of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit from the Merc faction. Its design is based on the suit used by the special forces of the Western armies. Due to a special treatment, its fabric provides better heat and radiation protection. Its protective properties are slightly better then those of the PSZ-7 military bulletproof suits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name">
		<text>Merc suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_description">
		<text>This Skat-9M military suit is designed for assault operations in areas of increased anomalous activity. It includes a PSZ-12p heavy military bulletproof vest, an integrated compensation suit and a Sphere-12M helmet. It provides perfect protection from bullets and splinters and it doesn’t decrease the soldier’s mobility. It has a balanced system of anomaly protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_outfit_name">
		<text>Military armored suit </text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit from the Monolith faction. The producer is unknown. Its protective properties are slightly worse then those of the PSZ-9a military bulletproof vest. Its structure is similar to the popular neutral stalker suit which combine a bulletproof vest and a radiation protection suit. It provides good protection from gunfire. Its level of anomaly protection is low due to the absence of an air filtering system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolit_outfit_name">
		<text>Monolith suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_description">
		<text>An ordinary thick jacket, one of the many. It slightly increases bullet and splinter protection. It does not protect from anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_name">
		<text>Leather jacket</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_description">
		<text>Modified SSP-99 suit. It provides increased body protection from bullets and splinters. It is designed for the guards working with scientific expeditions. It is heat and electricity resistant, provides good protection from radiation and biological anomalies. It is resistant to chemically aggressive environments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_name">
		<text>SSP-99M suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This suit was produced by one of Kiev's defence research institutes and represents an excellent alternative to stalker hand-made suits. It is an excellent combination of an bulletproof vest, a closed cycle breathing system and an integrated system of anomalous field suppression. Due to the perfect choice of the materials, it is the best suit in its class. It provides average bullet and splinter protection. It has an average level of anomaly protection. The only disadvantage is its price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>SEVA suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_description">
		<text>A Berill-5M special forces suit modified for the Zone environment. It includes a PSZ-9a military bulletproof vest with beryllium coating and a Sphere-08 helmet. It is designed for assault operations in areas with high background radiation. Its level of anomaly protection is low.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specops_outfit_name">
		<text>Berill-5M armored suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>Stalker suit. It is an effective combination of a light military bulletproof vest and of a rubberized fabric suit. It is reinforced with inserted kevlar plates and provides good protection from gunfire. It can also protect from a weak anomaly or radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Stalker suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
		<text>Reinforced stalker suit produced by the gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. It is made up of a medium military bulletproof vest plated with reinforcing zirconium elements which provide good protection from rifle bullets and splinters from medium and long range. The material of the suit consists of two layers: specially treated leather and fabric with asbestos yarn. The suit provides good protection from radiation and weak anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
		<text>Guardian of Freedom suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
		<text>Light stalker suit produced by the gunsmiths of the Freedom faction. It consists of a light military bulletproof vest with reinforcing kevlar elements. It can protect from weak weapons. The fabric of the suit is treated with a special mixture which increases the anomaly resistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
		<text>Wind of Freedom suit</text>
	</string>
	;-----------------------------Уникальные вещи----------------------------------		
	<string id="novice_outfit_name_m">
		<text>Аномальная кожанка</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice_outfit_description_m">
		<text>Эту куртку сняли с трупа одного из сталкеров, умерших в аномалии "кисель". Пролежав долгое время в аномалии, куртка обрела свойство ускорять метаболизм.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_name_m">
		<text>Кольчужная куртка</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_outfit_description_m">
		<text>Обычный слабенький бандитский бронежилет, но в подкладку вшито кольчужное полотно. Под силу это сделать почти любому, но терпения хватит далеко не всем.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Охотничий ПСЗ-9д</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Долговский бронекостюм с улучшенной защитой от укусов и порезов. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Укрепленный комбез</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>В подкладку куртки вшита кольчужная сетка, повышающая защиту от огнестрельного оружия, а также от укусов монстров. В комплект также включен ПНВ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specnaz_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Лечебный Берилл</text>
	</string>
	<string id="specnaz_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Ткань костюма пропитана стрептоцидовой мазью, ускоряющей заживление ран.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Комбинезон Призрака</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Ходят легенды о том, что призрачный сталкер никогда не носит с собой аптечки. Все на нем заживает, как на собаке. Говорят, что у него необычный комбинезон и что он его из аномалии достал.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m2">
		<text>Комбинезон туриста</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m2">
		<text>Бывший хозяин этой вещи был настоящим туристом, и, видать, не раз хаживал в тяжелые, на грани человеческих возможностей походы. Он знал, как правильно распределить вес, который нес и каким вещам отдать предпочтение. Карманы на куртке и грамотно подобраный рюкзак позволяют нести больший вес.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Комбез Свободы М2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="svoboda_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>В комбинизон интегрирована металлическая сетка, защищающая от электрических и магнитных полей. В комплект также включен прибор ночного видения.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Экзоскелет ПНБ-4УЗ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_description_m1">
		<text>Базовый прибор ночного видения заменен на более современную модель с цифровой фильтрацией сигнала.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
