<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="Antirad">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-heavy">
		<text>Heavy stalker equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-light">
		<text>Light stalker equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-medium">
		<text>Medium stalker equipment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Binocul">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Conserva">
		<text>A tin of "Tourist's breakfast"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect1">
		<text>Anomaly detector (DA-2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Devic">
		<text>Appliances and devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Equipment">
		<text>Gear and food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Food">
		<text>Various food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Kolbasa">
		<text>Diet sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medi">
		<text>Medications</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit">
		<text>First-aid kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Sci2">
		<text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Vodka">
		<text>Cossacks vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_desc">
		<text>A detailed map of the Dead City including mercenary positions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_short_desc">
		<text>A map of the Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctors_key_desc">
		<text>The Doctor's key to a secret stash in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctors_key_short_desc">
		<text>The Doctor's key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_documents_desc">
		<text>Detailed information about the activities of mercenaries in recent months</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_documents_short_desc">
		<text>Mercenaries' documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-pda">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch">
		<text>Torch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight - 18kg. Details: protects the body from "jelly", "burning fluff", most anomalies and mechanical damage. The chest and back are protected by built-in bio-metallic plates. The suit is equipped with an airtight reinforced plastic helmet and two oxygen containers. Important: during extended periods of use the suit deteriorates beyond use by tearing and disintegration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
		<text>Protective Suit. Weight - 8 kg. Details: protects the body from weak anomalies and mechanical damage. Equipped with an oxygen mask. Important: during extended periods of use the suit deteriorates beyond use by tearing and disintegration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight - 12 kg. Details: protects the body from "jelly", "burning fluff", many anomalies and mechanical damage. Equipped with an airtight helmet and an oxygen container. Important: during extended periods of use the suit deteriorates beyond use by tearing and disintegration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
		<text>Red SCAPE suit with an airtight helmet. Weight - 11 kg. Details: protects the body from fire, acids, gasses, various anomalies, "burning fluff" and mechanical damage. Equipped with two oxygen containers. Equipped with an airtight helmet and an oxygen container. Important: during extended periods of use the suit deteriorates beyond use by tearing and disintegration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul1">
		<text>Army field binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
		<text>A device for detecting anomaly fields and disturbances. Notifies of their presence by means of a sound. Needs to be fitted to the belt and activated to work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda1">
		<text>Personal digital assistant - indispensable in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
		<text>Torch with a relatively powerful lamp. Quite useful in areas with insufficient light.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m1">
		<text>Torch with a relatively powerful lamp. Battery charging time has been reduced thanks to a modernised transformer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
		<text>"Non-Stop" is an excellent energy drink. Contains caffeine, taurin and a powerful set of vitamins that rejuvenate and provide energy. If you can't take another step it's just the ticket!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
		<text>Nobody knows who manages to bake loaves in the Zone but the bread isn't contaminated and is perfectly edible. At least none of the stalkers have complained about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
		<text>Canned food from an army warehouse raided by stalkers. The best-before period hasn't expired by the looks of things.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
		<text>This sausage, made from a mix of chicken and soya, is, for lack of other options, often a stalker's breakfast, lunch and dinner in one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
		<text>GSC Vodka. Goes down easily, significantly reduces the effects of radiation but should be enjoyed in moderation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
		<text>Reduce the effects of radiation on the body.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
		<text>Bandaging. Helps to stop bleeding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
		<text>All-purpose med kit. Helps to deal with injuries of different kinds and levels - wounds, burns, poisoning etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_name">
		<text>Non-Stop energy drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_short_name">
		<text>Non-Stop energy drink</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
