<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="actor_break_dialog_0">
        <text>See you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_0">
        <text>What’s up?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_1">
        <text>Can’t you see I’m off color? Need medicine kit or at least bandage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_11">
        <text>Take the kit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_111">
        <text>Thanks, bro, I’ll consider this.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_12">
        <text>Take the bandage.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_13">
        <text>Sorry, I’m all out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_131">
        <text>Hiking without medicines? Catch infection and die?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_14">
        <text>Heh, why so bad? Sorry, I won’t give you mine, otherwise I’ll stay quite out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="actor_help_wounded_141">
        <text>You choose, but don’t think it does an honor for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="hello_dialog_2">
        <text>Hi!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="hello_dialog_3">
        <text>Listen, dude, help me!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="hello_dialog_0">
        <text>Hi!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_0">
        <text>What are you doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_1">
        <text>And how do you think?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_2">
        <text>Searching for the artifacts?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_21">
        <text>You can put it that way. Everyone seeks for the artifacts, but not every knows where they truly can be found.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211">
        <text>What do you know about that?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_2111">
        <text>Of course, I know, otherwise what will I be doing in the place that lacks artifacts? I got the info on where you can learn about how to break through to the Zone’s center. I can sell if you’re interested. Two grands will do. You understand, that there are far enough artifacts in the center so you could reimburse it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_21111">
        <text>Okay, I’ll take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211111">
        <text>Deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211112">
        <text>Deal. But be careful, don’t put your ass under the fire. Hehe. I appreciate people with the sense of humor. Take a grand back. And buy water proof pants, ha ha.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_21112">
        <text>No thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_211121">
        <text>Well, you choose.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_3">
        <text>Wandering?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_31">
        <text>You’re really funny indeed. We’re working here and they – having sweet time on vacations. Recently “worked” with the militaries. If you set too many questions – we’ll “work” with you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_4">
        <text>Put your asses under the fire?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_41">
        <text>Ha ha. Yeah, I see that you’re kind of a guy with the sense of humor. I welcome that. I meet such guys too seldom. The other ones are too morose I say, afraid of the death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_5">
        <text>I don’t have a clue.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_about_51">
        <text>You don’t say so, you don’t know. If you were to the Zone for the same time I did you’ll understand what are people doing here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_krot_start_0">
        <text>Well, whatcha want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_0">
        <text>Whatcha doing here?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_1">
        <text>Putting our asses under the fire. Talk to Mole for details. He’s in chief here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_factory_stalker_start_0">
        <text>Gosh, what a stir, I won’t wish it to my worst enemy. Those militaries are too impudent indeed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_0">
        <text>Put a picture of this place for me.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_1">
        <text>This is the “Agroprom” institute. The structure itself is situated in the south-west. And the large factory on the North – this is the institute’s production and technical base. Building have been abandoned long ago, and people have stopped thinking about it, cos there is nothing left to steal. But recently militaries started to search something there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_2">
        <text>Give me more specific information on the institute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_21">
        <text>Rumors say that until the accident in 1986 it was the single Gramineae selection and genetics institute building. Also there were experimental fields at the factory place. After the accident institute has been closed and the fields were burned. And then remembered, whitewashed the building, fenced in and built barracks. Constructed factory on the fields place. I don’t know what were they doing in that institute, but it’s obvious that they spent money left and right.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_3">
        <text>Give me more detailed info on the factory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_31">
        <text>Factory has been built at the end of 80th. Supposed to construct and mend the machines, which can treat the radioactively infected soil. But as far as I know, no one has seen such a machine. Now it’s totally tenantless. Only stalkers like to stay at there. It’s said that it’s rather safe place, if not to peep into the dark corners.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_4">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_1">
        <text>This is the road inside the Zone. Trader can be found in the cellar beyond the village near the army post. I don’t advise you to poke your nose in the army post, cos soldiers are directed to fire on sight… Killing soldiers isn’t allowed, only if worst comes to worst, trader will pay off on his own and he won’t be satisfied with that. Packs of blind dogs on the plains, perilously for the newbies. Mutants visit it now and then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_2">
        <text>And what is further to the north?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_21">
        <text>Dump is there. Gloomy place. Garbage even pesters sometimes.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_attack_0">
        <text>Let’s go and smash some gangster muzzles.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_121">
        <text>So what chief? We are damn ready.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_2">
        <text>You are supposed to be that guy Wolf has been talking about? Well it’s up to you now, basically there are not so many bandits there. Although we can hardly penetrate it together. Sniper has settled on the first floor staring at all passing nearby. If it were not for him – we would punish them swiftly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_hello_3">
        <text>So, will you take out the sniper? In other way we won’t poke a sinlge nose there. At least soberly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_0">
        <text>Now, gentlemen, what would you say?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_1">
        <text>All standing. Bandits are still at the ruins. Few people plus sentry on the first floor.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_11">
        <text>I suggest attacking the factory altogether.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_111">
        <text>No way we will have felt this on our own skins. But don’t think that we’re afraid of. We aren’t scared at all. Unless occasionally… maybe it’s a bit scary now… well, okay, we are afraid. And won’t you be afraid of soberly penetrating the factory with the dug in bandits inside? And that sniper there. I’d say that vodka can encourage us, in other way it’s impossible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_112">
        <text>Oh, I see that you’ve brought “fire-water”. Well if it continues as it is, we’ll not only drive all the bandits away from the factory, but even clear the whole Zone! So, attack?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_1121">
        <text>Well, I’ll tell you when. Now take this bottle.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_1122">
        <text>Wait a second. “Fire-water” isn’t for you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_12">
        <text>Okay.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_2">
        <text>Ready and waiting. You just give an order.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_0">
        <text>Got few questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_1">
        <text>Shoot.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_2">
        <text>Fox, tell me whether you have been to the Zone. What have you seen?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_21">
        <text>Such a story may take a few days to tell, and my time costs a lot. Can only give you a piece of advice. "Dump" – located 3 kilometers to the North from where I stand, where all the radioactive trash had been taken to from stations in 86th. Heavy radiation, host of anomalies, and ultimately – abundance of artifacts, admittedly not valuable. Beware of the bandits and try not to swear at “Duty” patrols. Scientific research institute “Agroprom” is to the west from the “Dump”. Region is quite poor regarding the artifacts, so I don’t go there often. “Dark Valley” to the east. Sort of weird place. Like it’s rather quiet in there, but bandits and stuff can now and then be met. Yet I sense that not everything is so simple there as it seems. Further beyond the Dump is “Rostok” factory territory – stalkership heart. Besides many experienced guys you can come across with.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_211">
        <text>What do one have to beware of in these lands?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_2111">
        <text>Hey, Marked, you look like an experienced guy, but for such foolish questions. Be wary of everything! This is the bloody Zone, can’t you see?! However bloodsuckers appeared at the night on the Dump, they haven’t been seen so far away from the center. Eerie vermins. It’s quite hard to see them during the day, if not to mention the night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_3">
        <text>Trader said that you can know something about the Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flame_dialog_31">
        <text>Many have been interested in him recently. Truthfully I don’t know him personally. But I do have err.. “contact” experience. His grouping has once fired upon my boys. No one was hurt – they’ve been probably waiting for the other ones, thus I consider it to me a misunderstanding. Fouled each other over the ravine and left. O, by the way, Grey is waiting for me at the garage at the Dump, I’ll send you the coordinates, chat with him. We knows a lot more.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flash_dialog_0">
        <text>I’m from the trader, you have to hand something to him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_flash_dialog_1">
        <text>Take it, and try not to lose. Important information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_hello_dialog_2">
        <text>Hey, I’m waiting for a man here, so you’d better to get out of here sooner the better.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_fox_hello_dialog_3">
        <text>Hi.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_0">
        <text>Why can’t I get into the camp?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_1">
        <text>One has to be a total dunce to let a man from the “death truck” in. First prove that you can be trusted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_11">
        <text>What’s the “death truck”? I can’t remember anything.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_111">
        <text>I know few, but this few is something really really bad. Ultimately talking on this topic, especially with you, is not what I’m gonna do. Call it superstition if you wish. So begone, Marked, in an amicable way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_12">
        <text>What must I do to make you believe me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_access_121">
        <text>The trader must examine you, and we’ll just get acquainted. If you are a normal one, don’t grip the gun naively and generally familiar with your reason, we’ll find common language.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_guard_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Marked, stop, there is no way for you to the camp now!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_guard_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Hi, Marked. What do you need?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_hello_0">
        <text>Greetings. Wish to sell something?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_0">
        <text>You are familiar with majority here. What has this crowd gathered here for?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_1">
        <text>Yeah, it’s hard to say unambiguously, from doctors of science to laid-back bandits. Everyone receives the task to its wit. Militaries usually guard the perimeter, rarely entering the Zone. Bandits are settled on the stalkers’ paths. May bereave of bribe or even life. Scientists are set somewhere deep inside it, searching for the bloody truth, idiots! There are several stalkers’ clans, but that’s another matter. People here in the camp are rather quiet and peaceful this is understood – freshly, anxious newbies. Unless the “Wolf” is familiar in here. This one has seen a lot, but to my mind he’s a bit freaky with stalkership and all, he wants to cut off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_2">
        <text>You’ve mentioned some stalkers’ clans. Can you give more specified information?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_21">
        <text>You see, it’s really hard to survive in the Zone by yourself. So such clans are gathering here and there. Some for convictions, some for money. But there are lots of free stalkers, as I am. Everyone is free to chose: join someone or act alone on own hazard and fear. Concerning groupings I can give roundup on the “Duty”, “Mercenaries” and “Monolith”</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_3">
        <text>Concerning the bandits. Why not to perish them once and for all? Admittedly everyone has weapons.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_31">
        <text>Well, generally we’re trying to do that. But if ones are shot, another come.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_4">
        <text>Tell me about the “Duty” grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_41">
        <text>These consider themselves to be Zone hags. They think that the Zone is the malignant growth on the Earth body, and going to clear the Earth from the Zone and its inhabitants, haven’t yet decided how indeed. Thus shot all the mutants without distinction.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_5">
        <text>Tell me about the “Mercanaries” grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_51">
        <text>Generally those have gathered there are not satisfied by the war in the “outer world”. Extreme Zone conditions shooting enthusiasts. Ready to fulfil any, even the most dirty work. Well equipped, by occidental weapons in majority.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_6">
        <text>Tell me about the “Monolith” grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_61">
        <text>Why they’re kind of strange ones. Don’t gather artifacts. Don’t make any liaisons. Don’t trade. Believe in some crap like aliens and evolutional module inside the center of the zone, which shall change the civilization on the earth for good. But these are rumors. I haven’t had personal contacts with them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_611">
        <text>And do you yourself believe in something? What’s in the center of Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_hlam_talk_people_6111">
        <text>I believe that even the most intimate dreams are granted in the center of the Zone. But I don’t have a clue what’s in there. I trust that some day I will be able to make it there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_novice_start_dialog_2">
        <text>Hi, Marked. How can I be useful?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_novice_start_dialog_3">
        <text>How did you get here!? You mustn’t be at the camp!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_dynamite_done_0">
        <text>Take this present. Sorry that it isn’t packed properly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_dynamite_done_1">
        <text>Hehe. Thanks. My compliments with splendid fireworks. Take the money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_hello_11">
        <text>Well, hi. Whatcha want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_hello_12">
        <text>Hello. I was told that you had saved one of ours from mere death. Thanks, man. Take this artifact as the sign of our gratitude. You can exchange it at Trader’s on weapons, shell or food.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_hello_13">
        <text>How did you pass the guards!? You can’t go inside the camp, Marked! Leave, while you’re alive!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_0">
        <text>Got a few questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_1">
        <text>Shoot. I’ll do my best to help ya.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_10">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2">
        <text>What do you know about the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_21">
        <text>Well, quite a lot. What do you particularly need.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_211">
        <text>What’s inside the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2111">
        <text>This is the very question, which I wanted to find the answer to last two years. But the safe path to the center of the Zone hasn’t been found yet. Several times I tried to break through with my friends. I have hardly made it to return, my friends haven’t. If you ask how we got there, I’ll tell ya that we were seeking for the dream, for the wish master.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_21111">
        <text>Why do you think that the dreams are to come true there?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_211111">
        <text>There is a stalkers’ legend of the “wish master”. A place located in the center of the Zone, where all, even the most incredible, wishes come true. But you know what I’ll tell ya, I do know that there is the mere death in the center of the Zone, and that “master” is noteworthy. So, don’t run risks in vain.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_212">
        <text>Where has the Zone come from?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2121">
        <text>Well, something boomed in 2006. Then it came. I know that this is barely an answer, but believe me that the truth is clear to very few.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_213">
        <text>What has led you inside the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2131">
        <text>You unprofitable mine has been closed in 2008. Insufficient money. Then the rumors came about the Zone to give a chance to grow rich. I had no lack of army experience, so I ventured to do it. I can’t say that I an extremely rich now, but I’ve got a fair bit of brass behind my back. Typical story, as well as many others.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_214">
        <text>What’s the most dangerous in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_2141">
        <text>Well, it’s hard to say. There are so many things still dangerous and unknown that I’ve hardly seen the whole enchilada. My body is the vivid example of the Zone’s dangers: bit off toe, thinned hair over the radiation, right hip burnt in “Zharka”, bloody thing by the way. Anomaly which isn’t standing on the same place, but flying. Had a face to face contact with the bloodsucker once. I dread even recollecting it. Basically we can talk it through and through, but if you haven’t felt it on your skin – you won’t understand. Just one advice – be careful.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_3">
        <text>Have you heard anything about the Gunslinger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_31">
        <text>Kind of tough stalker to my mind. Not really familiar with him. However I’ve been wandering at the center of the Zone too long ago, and here to the boundsthere are quite a lot of newbies. You ought to talk to somebody working in the depth of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_4">
        <text>What do you know about the “death trucks”?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_info_41">
        <text>I don’t know anything at all. Sorry, I see that you’re from there. But it’s too mystified. But working a bit in the Zone makes you superstitious indeed. Corpses in the body, dead men at the wheels… Who they are? Where have they come from… Hope not from the other side.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_0">
        <text>Got any work?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_1">
        <text>I’ve been too long inside the Zone. And I’m really sick and tired of it. And that will do! I got friends in the “outer world”. But before that I’d like to leave the present to one of my friends. Guys were carrying it to me, but those bandits perished them. So this present must be returned. I just don’t want to hazard my life before leaving. And you’re new here, and most certainly need money. I’ll pay you few grands. Well… those bandits are now settle at the factory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_11">
        <text>Okay, deal. Just tell what to fetch.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_111">
        <text>Agree. Ah, the present… nothing extraordinary, just a case with dynamite… If you need any help – there are our guys nearby the factory making an ambush to the bandits. Talk to them – they may help.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_12">
        <text>No way, deal with it yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_121">
        <text>What’s up, too scared? Well it’s okay, I’m not offended.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_lager_volk_job_2">
        <text>There is nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_artefact_0">
        <text>Here is your artifact! Okay?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_artefact_2">
        <text>Yeah, sure. Client will be satisfied.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_blockpost_box_0">
        <text>Done. Take this case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_blockpost_box_2">
        <text>Well done, thanks a lot. Not that you can be stuffed with the mere “thanks”. Weeell, 1000, no let it be 500 rubles and we’re done.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_0">
        <text>Here is what Fox handed to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_1">
        <text>Perfect, not everything is much clearer.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_11">
        <text>What’s so important in there? Frankly speaking I understood nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_111">
        <text>Well cut it off. The time will come and you’ll get everything. Can only admit that I need a “special” man for the “special” job. Don’t you know such guy? Hehe.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_0">
        <text>Well okay, take my first artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_1">
        <text>Marked, listen to my messages carefully next time. Thanks for the artifact but wounded needs your urgent help. Take this medikit and don't you lose it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_1311">
        <text>empty text</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_2">
        <text>Okay then. Goods shouldn’t be wasted.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_tutorial_artefact_3">
        <text>Marked!!! Move it to the trailer nearby the road. You'll find wounded stalkers who were returning from my mission. Why a hell did they put fire on that helicopter... now they call SOS all the time... Hand this medikit, move it...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_0">
        <text>What kinda work have you got?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_12">
        <text>No, nothing yet.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_15">
        <text>Okay then. Anything else?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_2">
        <text>All as usual. First of all I need artifacts. I pay usual price not more, not less.\n Sometimes I need specail people for special work.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_3">
        <text>Deal. Well if I find something, I’ll try not to forget and bring it to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_4">
        <text>Maybe you’ve got a special work for a special person?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5">
        <text>Got an order on “Gravity” or “Twist” anomalies. I don’t really care where you find it, but I can aim ya: there is an accumulation of Gravity anomalies to the north from the factory, artifacts may be often found somewhere there. By the way if there will be no artifacts, just wait until someone traps into the anomaly, dog of human, doesn’t matter. Anomaly will make artifact out of him in a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_51">
        <text>Generally speaking, “Agroprom” handed the thing I really need to the army post. White plastic case. It has to be stolen. Just be careful. When miliraties resent they make so much noise here, that even rats scatter. If I were you I would try to make it at night and as quiet as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_511">
        <text>What kinda case is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5111">
        <text>Nothing special in it. Plastic white grip-sack. Why I do need the very thing inside it. These documents – preliminary report on the military expedition to “Agroprom”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_53">
        <text>Well, has just appeared. I’m conducting kind of investigation. Tell you later. Well, you must contact the person, who’s carrying important information. He’s called Fox. He doesn’t want to be put on view here, so meet him at the khutor behind the bridge. I’ll send you the coordinated. By the way, Marked. He isn’t a newbie so far so you can ask him on your matter. That’s it. Move out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_531">
        <text>I’m off.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5311">
        <text>Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_532">
        <text>Aha… dream on… Breakneck pace. Am I a pushover or what? Another time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_5321">
        <text>Do as you wish, but I thought that it was really important for you to know about yourself, who you are and what has happened.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_6">
        <text>Agreed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_61">
        <text>Okay, I’ll try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_7">
        <text>No, I don’t want.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_71">
        <text>No, I don’t agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_8">
        <text>Deal.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_81">
        <text>Well, bring it first, then we’ll dole out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_9">
        <text>You pick.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_jobs_91">
        <text>As you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_171">
        <text>So, brought it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_181">
        <text>Branded One, what YOU are doing here? Did I not say clearly – rush to the cabin!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_2">
        <text>To make it short, Marked, I’ve saved you and I won’t play dignified. Conduct some tasks for me and we’re done. Besides we’ll see how fast will your head restore from amnesia, and I’ll try to find about your case. A hell knows why do you need that Gunslinger, I don’t care of the outside problems. If you want to kill him, then there is the reason.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_21">
        <text>closer to the point.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_3">
        <text>Oh, I like it that way. \n Now choose how shall I treat with you. Either I should wash newcomers’ brains or I’ll treat with you like with skilled stalker – received the task, carry out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_31">
        <text>Let it be like with the newcomer. I remember nothing.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_32">
        <text>Better like with skilled, while it isn’t effaced from the memory.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_321">
        <text>Î! That’s how we do that. Listen then: \n There is the “Mincer” anomaly field nearby. And the artifact in the center. Local novices from the camp are afraid to poke in there. Well it’s scattered somewhere there for about a week. It’s written all over your face that you’re not a newbie, although you remember nothing. So even in such condition you’ll manage to bag it. Okay. Get to the job. I’ve sent the coordinates of that place to your PDA along with the information on the Mincer and its artifacts.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_3211">
        <text>It’s all settled.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_4">
        <text>Hi, Marked. Glad to see you alive.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_5">
        <text>Hi, Marked. How is it going?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_6">
        <text>Listen, Marked, I've told you everything, now get to your job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_0">
        <text>I need answers on several questions.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_1">
        <text>Shoot, but I know few. You see, I’m stuck here for the eternity, while the real life is outside in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_10">
        <text>Thanks for the information.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_2">
        <text>What are the militaries doing in the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_21">
        <text>Military guard it, what else can they do. The one thing I don’t get is whether they protect outside world form the Zone, or Zone from the outside world. Yep, I still don`t get it. Military expeditions sometimes come here. Must be searching for something. But I tell you, military men do not respect the Zone, and Zone pays back the same. Lots of then found they dead end here. Yep, dead.\nWhat, tell more? Well, those guys look down on us all, like some kind of supreme beings. Don`t give a damn about stalker laws, never help, even in the worst possible situation. No, lying, they can soot you, but not out of pity. Its just runs in their blood: Shoot first, think later. But I and they deal pretty well. Vodka, men magazines, in exchange for my private peace. So I advise you not to bother them in vain.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3">
        <text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_31">
        <text>Zone... is not just a peace of territory 40 kilometers in diameter, with its center near the nuclear plant. Zone is really strange being. I don`t think there is a person in this world who can give you a definite answer on your question. Because Zone is something not from this reality. I think it`s another world. Dangerous, strange, but, damn, it`s attractive. It`s like Eldorado, there even the most miserable bum can became very, very rich. And the deeper you go into the Zone, the closer you come to your fortune.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_311">
        <text>And what’s so dangerous in this “other world”?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3111">
        <text>He, he. Nothing dangerous, besides that you can die any second. And not from the bullet of stupid military, by the way there are a lot of this guys lately. Must also tell, that be killed with a shot is the nicest death here. Really nice, compared with dying in anomaly - invisible death is the scariest one. Even mutants try to avoid them. Mutants, yes, “children” of the Zone. \nNasty creatures, tell ya. So you better don`t go to the Zone without a gun. And talk to stalkers, they are good advisers as for the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_312">
        <text>Rich? I would like to know more about getting rich...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3121">
        <text>Dude, don`t tell me you know nothing about artifacts. They are the source of your wealth. People outside pay good dough for these souvenirs form the Zone. They are more dear then gold and diamonds. Because no gold can draw aside bullet that heads right into your belly. And artifacts do this, and many other funny and useful things. You can get most common ones even here, but to find a treasure, you`ll have to go to heart the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_313">
        <text>And what lies there, in the heart of the Zone?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3131">
        <text>People tell a lot, if interested, ask other stalkers. But I don`t believe in this mystic staff. I do believe that in the center of the Zone lies an Eldorado, a place rich in artifacts. But I met no people who could either confirm, or deny it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_4">
        <text>Any ideas of what happened to me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_41">
        <text>Son, you ask hell of questions. Everything is shady about it. You where found in the death truck - vehicles loaded with corpses sometimes appear from the center of the Zone. Where they head to, no one know. You truck crashed – bad luck, but you stayed alive. This is the most intriguing fact to me. Stalkers often find broken death trucks, but never found any survivals. Sorry, have nothing more to tell. You`ll have to figure it out yourself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_5">
        <text>Who is Gunslinger? You know this guy?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_51">
        <text>I think I heard of this stalker. Rumors tell he is one of few, who got to the center of Zone. Well, there are a lot of legends about “stalker who made it to the center and back”. So, can`t guaranty the story is true, I personally had no business with him. Maybe he works with other dealers. Want to find him, ask stalkers, maybe some of them will tell you a way.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_6">
        <text>Spectral stalker, heard of him?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_info_61">
        <text>Its another legendary man. Not heard about him for a long time. He must have died somewhere deep in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_0">
        <text>Tell me about this place.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_1">
        <text>Suburbs of the Zone, military cordon. In general it is usually calm and quite here, just military guys have fun sometimes. Stalkers only pass by, only freshmen linger on, and sometimes forever, hehe. There is the novices’ camp set nearby me in the village. They can pull the trigger sometimes though. No worthy loot here. Abandoned factory by the road. Farm remnants to the North, blockpost to the South. By the way, militaries has set landmines in some places, watch it. There has been the bridge in the center, but in has been ruined. That`s it, I guess.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_10">
        <text>Okay, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_2">
        <text>Tell me more on the army post.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_21">
        <text>Few dozens of soldiers, they are allowed to shoot on sight. So you better pass them by. When military guys are too worried, start calling help from special forces. Those fellows are really tough. After their visits I have no clients for months. So you better not to disturb them. I know their commander a little. He is a total drunkard. Only thanks to his I`m still here.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_3">
        <text>Tell me more about the ruined bridge.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_31">
        <text>300-400 meters to the North. You can’t miss it. It was once an expensive bridge, but had been destroyed during the surge. Militaries like to lie in wait for stalkers, returning with the bribe there. So you’d better avoid that embankment, if not crucial.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_4">
        <text>Give me the picture on the factory?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_41">
        <text>As you cross the road, you’ll notice it. Ruined brick building. Everything that could be stolen, has already been stolen, so the only half-tumbled down core remains. The favorite bandits place. I am not aware if they’re still there, but in any case stay prudent. You’ve still got nothing to take away, but do you really need it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_5">
        <text>Give me a wrap-up on the farm?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_talk_level_51">
        <text>What a boring one you are. Simple farm as every other one. Pigs pegged out until the Perestroika.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_0">
        <text>How are you, alive?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_1">
        <text>Oh, damn, I’m bleeding. Hand a first-aid please!?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_2">
        <text>Have it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_21">
        <text>Thanks bro. I won’t forget it. I’ll pass it to the Wolf, he is senior in the village camp. He’ll appreciate it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_3">
        <text>Sorry bro, I’m all out.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_31">
        <text>Search the corpses… Guys from our grouping must have had it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_4">
        <text>You’ll kick the bucket anyway why should I spend kit on you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_wounded_give_medkit_41">
        <text>What kind of bastard are you, don’t you understand that next time you can be in my shoes?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_21">
        <text>Well, fellows! Let’s kick arses! Assault!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_assault_talk_22">
        <text>So be it! I’ll return in a moment.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_11">
        <text>At last Wolf has sent help! Okay, listen, we’re going to knock bandits out of the factory, but the 2nd floor is ocupated by one prudent goggleeyed bastard and looks right into our direction. Silence won’t make any good there. Your task – to insensibly infiltrate the factory and give him a beat. As soon as we notice him missing, we’ll force our way in.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_111">
        <text>Clear. I’m gonna lay him down.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_112">
        <text>Maybe it would be better to attack the factory all together?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_1121">
        <text>You chicken out, aren’t you? Me too, I’m not for so long in Zone as well, if you wanna stay alive it’s better not to show yourself. Vodka should be good here, for bravery.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_11211">
        <text>Ah, I wish I had vodka now.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_112111">
        <text>Perhaps you should visit trader then? If you don’t want to make a silent assault.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_1121111">
        <text>Fine. I’ll be back soon.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_11212">
        <text>I’ve got vodka, here take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_112121">
        <text>Good… Well… hic… lets move out! Stay aside… don’t panic.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_1121211">
        <text>Lets kick asses!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_113">
        <text>I have to think about it, and look around… well, you understand. I’ll catch up with ya latter.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_factory_attackers_12">
        <text>Well, have you thought it out? Able to take off that basterd from the 2nd floor? No other chances to approach, I think.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_2">
        <text>Sydorovich, don’t waste your time… close to the case.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_21">
        <text>Generally speaking, “Agroprom” handed the thing I really need to the army post. White plastic case. It has to be stolen. Just be careful. When miliraties resent they make so much noise here, that even rats scatter. If I were you I would try to make it at night and as quiet as possible.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_211">
        <text>What kinda case is it?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_2111">
        <text>Nothing special in it. Plastic white grip-sack. Why I do need the very thing inside it. These documents – preliminary report on the military expedition to “Agroprom”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_21111">
        <text>Ok. I'll try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_211111">
        <text>Well bring the case first, then we'll deal with money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_21112">
        <text>No, I don't agree.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_trader_done_gift_211121">
        <text>As you wish.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_0">
        <text>Can you tell something interesting?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_1">
        <text>I have a lot to tell. But possibly you’ve heard of that kinda vermin like mutants a lot. I can acquaint you with us, “Duty” grouping. But don’t you dare to ask me about those morons from “Freedom”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_2">
        <text>Tell me about your grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_21">
        <text>We’ve been here from the very beginning. The grouping itself has been found by the toughies from one of special task forces, sent in the Zone to investigate the full picture of its appearance. We got into a serious scrape there. After the half of our troops has perished under the terrible circumstances, the ones survived swore that wouldn’t leave until they coped with the task.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_3">
        <text>You’ve mentioned about the “Freedom” morons?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_31">
        <text>Total imbeciles and bloody scums. They can’t get it clear that the Zone is the world’s pest place. Besides they want to stretch the Zone all over the world, to the every single distant place. They may use all the possible and impossible means for their goal. I can’t wait when we finish them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_about_4">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_0">
        <text>Why don’t you let anyone pass to the North?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_1">
        <text>Cos we don’t need that rabble at “Rostok”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_2">
        <text>What’s there on the “Rostok”?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_21">
        <text>It concerns you not! You’ll learn when you come there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_3">
        <text>Listen, mate. I urgently need to go further. You understand?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_31">
        <text>Too insolent for the newbie. Or is it kinda gentle hint?! Well it may cost you about 500 rubles to get through.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_311">
        <text>Now we are talking. Take these money.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_3111">
        <text>Deal, you can pass.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_312">
        <text>No thanks, I’ll make it myself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_3121">
        <text>Hehe, what a greedy one you are. Well, try.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_acces_4">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_guard_start_2">
        <text>Stop! You can’t go further! Newbies have nothing to deal with “Rostok”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_guard_start_3">
        <text>You’re not a bad guy, go ahead.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_guard_start_4">
        <text>Thanks my friend! You are doing quite well killing mutants. You can access the "Rostok" area any time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_guard_start_5">
        <text>Well, buddy, you are a mere pro in getting rid of monsters. When you are in "Rostok" area - make sure to come to see our leader. Possibly you will find common language with him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_guard_start_6">
        <text>Why are you standing? Move on.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_start_2">
        <text>Hmm… What do you want?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_start_3">
        <text>Hi, I’m glad that you also don’t like mutants. It was fun. You’re decent guy. We’ll admit you to the North.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_start_4">
        <text>Hey. I'm glad you hate mutants too. It was funny. You are a good guy. We will let you pass to the north.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_start_5">
        <text>Great! You gave them a hard time. Should everybody kill so many mutants as you, they would have vanished long ago. The path to the north is open to you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_0">
        <text>Can you tell something about the Dump?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_1">
        <text>Well there is nothing really essential in there. Dump as it is. Unless some maniacal bastard on the bridge that shoots everything that moves. It’s said that his head is wanted for reward. Moreover the northern road to “Rostok” is guarded by the “Duty” soldiers. You’d better don’t deal with those, guys in “Duty” a really gloomy ones. That’s it, I guess.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dram_novice_level_2">
        <text>Noteworthy information, thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_2">
        <text>Thanks for saving. Now I’m in debt. How can I thank you… O! Information costs money, so listen. I’ve seen monolithians while moving from the Dark Valley. Morose guys in brown uniform. I’ve never noticed them coming to the border so closely. And the bandits who arranged big base in there, I’ve hardly made it to escape. So be careful, if you wander there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dramm_novice_start_3">
        <text>Ho ho! Hi, mate! Thousand thanks for saving my ass. I promise I’ll requite like for like.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_0">
        <text>Are you gathering here for no particular reason or what?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_1">
        <text>Bandits have plagued nearly everyone. Now I’m prepared, so lets move and give those bandits a rape session.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_2">
        <text>Can I go with you?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_21">
        <text>No its personal. No strangers, sorry.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_3">
        <text>Heard anything on the Gunslinger?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_31">
        <text>Yeah, but not too much. It’s said that he made it to the center of the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_4">
        <text>Haven’t you been acquainted with stalker Seriy.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_41">
        <text>I think that I’ve heard that he was waiting for someone on garage. But be careful – bridge near the crushed truck with corpses is occupied my that maniac bastard.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_411">
        <text>What is that maniac?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_4112">
        <text>Ordinary Zone’s loony. Shoots everyone on sight. No chance to approach, cos of the immediate fire.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_412">
        <text>What kind of a corpse truck?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_4121">
        <text>Recently in stormy night the truck has crushed here. Overloaded with stalkers’ corpses. Where they were taken to and from stays unclear.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_413">
        <text>Fine. I’ll be cautious.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_4131">
        <text>Please do. Caution hasn’t yet harmed anyone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_kran_stalkers_about_5">
        <text>Thanks.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_0">
        <text>Wait, Seriy, stand firm!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_1">
        <text>I am, I am. Got a med kit?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_2">
        <text>Sure. Take it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_21">
        <text>Oh, thanks. I want to share secret with you. Take this flash drive, information on it will help you to get to the center of Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_3">
        <text>Well.. Seriy.. I think it’s just not your day…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_help_31">
        <text>Dammit…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_2">
        <text>I’ve been shot… Shit! I’m unwell…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_seriy_start_3">
        <text>Hello, mate. Thanks for you help then.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_stalker_about_level_0">
        <text>Can you tell about the local?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_stalker_about_level_1">
        <text>Well, listen. We’re now standing at big fetid dump. All the bloody radioactive refuse and debris has been taken here after the accident in 1986. So it’s totally filled with that rubbish, above and beyond the anomalies here and there among the trash. That’s why the only one you can meet here is an ordinary newbies. Why the newbies gather bandits around them. Thus it’s better for you not to stay for long here. Further to the North – radioactive hot beds, trespassing without protection is fatal. If you go to the North, you’ll find the abandoned “Rostok” factory, stalkers’ bar in there you’ll find it with ease. Dark Valley to the East, gloomy, foggy place. “Agroprom” territory to the West. I’ll mark places on your map where you can get safely to.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_fox_flash_info">
        <text>Restricted.\nTo: Leader, “THRUTH” project \nKGB colonel V.Ì. Kruchelnikov \nFrom: Commander, «Search-2» group, \ncaptain D.F. Maksimenko \n\nReport.\n\nIn period from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012 our group incorporating with KGB task force section has been inspecting the facilities of former “Agroprom” research institute, which researched the problem of farming on lands contaminated with radioactivity. The very first inspections draw suspicion upon their non-farming activities of the last 2-3 years before the “X” day. \nFurther worse, the first part of collected materials was sent under the escort to Dytyatky army post on May, 16th, but according to the information provided by army post commander lieutenant V.P. Chuguykin no one came for that data. Radio communication with the center is unstable and recently because of the increasing Zone activity communication service is out at all.. We don’t send any other Agroprom materials as the remaining group is reluctant to be split. During the delivery of first part of collected materials two soldiers of the escort died: sergeant R.D. Dubko and ensign K.P. Ivanets. We couldn’t fetch the bodies, since all the bodies were missing. \nColonel, sir, I insistently demand on considering this situation. With all the proper respect sir, we’re at the breaking point. My people are dying and no one has any mere dealings with us and our tasks!!!. Where a hell is that damn group of military stalkers I was promised? Or our replacement? Where are the promised air support and rations?!!! For what damn reason an antique tank without any fuel or ammunition was sent here? Yes, it has arrived, inane wonder of engineering… Mutants jeer at it… Stop teasing us!!!.. If the situation doesn’t change, I’ll take my men away from the Zone on my own… Got that?\n\n28.05.2012. KGB captain Maksimenko D.F.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_borov_flash_info">
        <text>These zombies from Monolith base need people. As if for some kind of experiments, I didn’t quite dig in. They pay with artefacts and the expensive ones. If you send them the imprisoned, tell your lads that the password is NUCLEAR WINTER. I described your uniform to Monolith guys, so make sure you put it on when going. If they take you for some shitheads, they’ll take to their guns.\n You surely get it who is to be rewarded for the info, right?\n Zmey.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_seriy_flash_info">
        <text>Received from Bugay: \n Seriy, I found out that Mole's grouping has gone towards Agroprom's factory. Searching for Gunslinger's cache, want to become familiar with his trip to the North. Supposed to know the rough cache place. Will camp on the gactory during the search. So, the point is that you are wandering nearby - go chat with them. You're a communicative person indeed - so outtalk them to give you information. Huh? \n \n Send to Bugay: \n Bull, listen, I won't peep there readily. Militaries are fumbling in there. I don't wanna have a bullet and all. However, I understand they'll get back to the Bar later on. And I'm gonna camp in Garage on the Dump. Got a task from scientists for bloodsuckers' heads. So, when it is comming back - I'll manage to intercept them.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_gunslinger_cache_info">
        <text>You asked me to find out about the location of Gunslinger's stash. Listen, here's what I discovered. Not far from SRI Agroprom there is a factory. Make sure you circle this one around from the north. Nearby the fence breach you will spot an entrance leading to underground. Get inside to find yourself on spiral stairs. Climb down to procede to the spacious indoor area. There in the far corner you will locate the stash. Beware of mutants though, they are said to have densely occupied the underground territories. And don't forget to share a lump of loot with the one who has helped you out with the info.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
        <text>Received from Phantom: \n \n Gunslinger, I've got very disappointing news. Fang has perished. We were ambushed at the village near the depots. And in my opinion they were waiting for a long time. Threesome. Looked like usual neutrals. Fang smelled them somehow. You know about his keen scent. Two of them were killed - obviously they were total newbies, and the third one appeared to be much more clever - camped in 100 meters with Screw-gun. So Fang is gone. So only two of has can go to the Center next time. And there is more: Those two had our description. I don't have a tiny clue who ever said that. Though many have grudge against us. The third is gone. One of the free lancers to my mind. Heavy scar on the face. Bright eyes. I'll try to find him. \n That's the way the cookie crumbles. Good luck and watch out. \n Phantom \n \n To Phantom \n \n "Hi mate. \n I leave an info for ye. That's the way to get in touch. I've noticed somebody shadowed. \n Dude, I'm gone to the North: to where we've been: I'll try to get through myself: Sorry, but I don't have enough time for that: Explain later. \n And that moron, who killed Fang will regret the day when he was born... I'm irritated... You'd inquire about who is he, and I'll be back soon, we'll see to it. \n Meet at our common friend. You know who's he and where he is. :) \n Good luck. \n Gunslinger" \n \n To Gunslinger. \n \n "Hello. Been there. Haven't met you. Your trip to the center alone was all for nothing. Although that's not the point. Where and at whom I should look for you is most certainly familiar :) \n Phantom"</text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_crazy_flash_info">
        <text>1: Today we set off to the village for a round of art hunting. Everything as usual. \n\n2: Where these beasts come from? Must be from Radar, where else. All fell dead, and I’m sitting on tower waiting for the beasts to calm down. Will try to escape by night…\n\n3: I don’t remember how I pulled out – but it was a mere hell… My head is splitting – images, sounds, I don’t know where they come from, damn radiation. And the bitched meter broke down. I have to take some rest, will get better then. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_flash_ugrumy">
        <text>1: What the hell forced me to go to the Radar, could barely escape it – another little bit and there would be one more exhibit with brains thinned out. \n\n2: Four of gangsters surrounded me as toddler, my fault too – failed to spot the ambush. I was saved by their talkativeness and greed, instead of riddling me, they jumped out and wanted to undress me first – hankered after the suit. That was their last mistake, one of them though hurt me a bit, well – I’m getting older…\n\n3: Gunslinger’s messenger was breathless by the time I arrived. Yes, not everyone can cope with three bloodsuckers, and this one got four down and several bloody traces stretch in different directions. The only information he had with him is the door code (19840519), but it is unclear right now which the door it is.\n\n4: We caught some military going to the Radar. Had no documents and orders with them, but at least we got ammunition resupplied. Will hide away my RG6 in the basement for now, will pick up later.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_courier_doc">
        <text>Courier’s documents.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_flash_bandit">
        <text>Damn, bastards from “Duty” have ousted us from the booty-plentiful area. They’ve entrenched around our hamlet. We haven’t even managed to pick up our stuff from the garret. It’s ok, the “Freedom’s” base is nearby, so it won’t take long before they are smoked out of there.   </text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_flash_max">
        <text>Today we held up some military going to the Radar and secured a couple of RG6s. Excellent stuff. One was grabbed by Lukash, another one was hidden in house basement by Ugryumy in the village. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_code_door_info_name">
        <text>Code door</text>
    </string>
    <string id="rad_code_door_info">
        <text>The scientist had a map with door marked</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_help">
        <text>Help me!!! I need medikit.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_new_task">
        <text>New tasks received.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_complete_task">
        <text>Task completed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_fail_task">
        <text>Task failed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_update_task">
        <text>Task updated.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_in_item">
        <text>Object acquired.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_out_item">
        <text>Object lost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_in_money">
        <text>Money gained.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="general_out_money">
        <text>Money lost.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
        <text>To talk to someone point sight at him and press ‘E’ button.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
        <text>To activate PDA, press 'P' button.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
        <text>To activate map press 'M'.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
        <text>Find artifact in the place pointed on the map and bring it to the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
        <text>Search dead bodies, you may find some useful staff.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
        <text>Hand a medikit to this dunce.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
        <text>Press Contact (Ñ). In and on minimap on the screen other stalkers with activated PDA will appear. Their attitude to you will also be stated on the screen. Be careful if you see enemies on the screen. However bandits and, heh, monsters usually don’t use PDA, so you better watch out in the Zone.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
        <text>Watch out! You’re nearby anomalies. Use bolts to define their borders.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
        <text>Marked, watch out. Next time it may be you!</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
        <text>Hey, there is some kind of action near you. I send coordinates to you. Check, what are going there.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_killed">
        <text>Well, Marked, it’s up to you. This way or another, you’ve passed the examination, but deal with Wolf and his team on your own. Generally I’m waiting for you, got some job.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_death">
        <text>empty text</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_helped">
        <text>Well done, Marked. If it continues, you’ll acquire many friends. Come into mine, we’ll have a chat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
        <text>Branded One. The military uncovered something  in SRI “Agroprom”. And this is something I’m very after, so as you I guess. You need to gain the info and deliver it to bartender in stalker bar. Get on it.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="gar_dolg_warning">
        <text>Stalker, you’ve have intruded territory under Duty control… Any assault attempt on our people will be punished by the mere death.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tips_garbage_rush_starter">
        <text>Attention everyone!!! Duty outpost online. The pack of mutants is moving towards the Bar from the Black Valley. Everyone who will help us to shoot out that scums will be granted gratitude from our side. You have Duty word.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="info_val_give_suicider_task">
        <text>Branded one, stalkers whisper of Hawk stalker to have shown up in the village vicinity. He wasn’t seen around for over six months now. He attempted finding a passage to the zone center and disappeared without trace, and now popped up back again. He was seen recently in Dark Valley, somewhere behind the Monolith base. When time allows, find out what’s about him.  </text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_info_max_village">
        <text>Branded one, be careful – a new anomaly is said to have shown up in the village – it’s moving swift-fast, and moreover, the damn thing can’t be seen.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_info_max_mines">
        <text>Mind the mines – sapper can be mistaken twice…</text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_info_freedom_radio">
        <text>If you sit for the whole night in the village on Tower – something will definitely happen… :) </text>
    </string>
    <string id="mil_info_to_all">
        <text>Attention, all the volunteers to thin out your brains – the passage to Radar is guarded by Monolith squad. I gather you are aware they shoot up everyone. Good luck.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_wounded_start">
        <text>Hey, Marked, one stalker just returned from deep raid into Zone. He is wounded and can't move anymore. Help him, may be he know something about Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="escape_stalker_help">
        <text>Hey, Marked. There is a badly wounded stalker not far from you, he was coming back after a trip deep inside the Zone. Help him, he may know something about the Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_krot">
        <text>Meet the stalkers</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_gunslinger_cache">
        <text>Gunslinger’s stash</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_military_case">
        <text>Procure military documents</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_escape_eliminate_gunslinger">
        <text>Kill Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="storyline_escape_find_gunslinger">
        <text>Find Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_find_artefact">
        <text>Find artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_find_artefact_0">
        <text>Find your first artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_find_artefact_1">
        <text>Find the first artifact.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_find_artefact_2">
        <text>Deliver the artifact to the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_help_wounded">
        <text>Help the wounded.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="tutorial_help_wounded_0">
        <text>Find the person who survived after the firing and help him.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_need_electra_artefact">
        <text>Find and bring artifact from gravity anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_need_electra_artefact_0">
        <text>Trader needs any artifact from gravity anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_need_electra_artefact_1">
        <text>Find artifact. You can get it, if you lure someone into the anomaly.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_trader_need_electra_artefact_2">
        <text>Bring artifact to the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_help_wounded_from_raid">
        <text>Deliver the information to the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_help_wounded_from_raid_0">
        <text>Help the trader obtain the information on the reconnaissance.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_help_wounded_from_raid_1">
        <text>Meet the stalker called “Fox”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_help_wounded_from_raid_2">
        <text>Deliver the information from the trader to “Fox”.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_blockpost_case_to_trader">
        <text>Steal the case from army post.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_blockpost_case_to_trader_0">
        <text>Steal case with important documents from army post commander.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_blockpost_case_to_trader_1">
        <text>Steal the case from army post.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_blockpost_case_to_trader_2">
        <text>Bring case to the trader.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dinamit_to_volk">
        <text>Get dynamite for the Wolf.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dinamit_to_volk_0">
        <text>Collect dynamite from the bandits on the factory and take it to the Wolf.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dinamit_to_volk_1">
        <text>Meet with the Wolf’s team.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dinamit_to_volk_2">
        <text>Find the dynamite on the factory</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_dinamit_to_volk_3">
        <text>Deliver the dynamite to the Wolf.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="garbage_meet_stalker">
        <text>Meet stalker on the dump.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="garbage_meet_stalker_0">
        <text>Meet stalker in the garage on the dump and get information about Gunslinger`s clan.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_get_military_documents">
        <text>Get militaries’ documents from “Agroprom” research institute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_get_military_documents_0">
        <text>Get military documents from “Agroprom” and deliver them to barman in stalkers’ bar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_get_military_documents_1">
        <text>Get military documents from “Agroprom” research institute.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_get_military_documents_2">
        <text>Deliver the documents to barman in Stalker bar.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_meet_krot_band">
        <text>Meet Gunslinger's grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agr_meet_krot_band_0">
        <text>You found out, that some stalkers gather on the abandoned factory near “Agroprom” institute. They may lead you to Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_find_gunslinger_cache">
        <text>Find the secret cache of Gunslinger’s grouping.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_find_gunslinger_cache_0">
        <text>Find and search the cache of Gunslinger’s clan. There you may get information, where to find Gunslinger himself.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_find_stalker_phantom">
        <text>Find Fantom.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="agroprom_find_stalker_phantom_0">
        <text>The Ghost knows for sure where to find Gunslinger.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wounded_to_trader_gift">
        <text>Hand over the package to the merchant.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="esc_wounded_to_trader_gift_0">
        <text>Hand over the package to the trader. It may help you.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="inventory_item_use">
        <text>Pickup item ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="character_use">
        <text>Talk with the person ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="dead_character_use">
        <text>Search corpse ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="car_use">
        <text>Open door ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="physic_shell_use">
        <text>Move object ()</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
