<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="Army">
		<text>Army</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bandits">
		<text>Bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Duty">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Killers">
		<text>Mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Loners">
		<text>Lone stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Military">
		<text>Militarised units</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Milstalkers">
		<text>Military stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mobile-groups">
		<text>Research groups</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mobile-labs">
		<text>Mobile science lab</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Scientists">
		<text>Scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Social">
		<text>Societies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stalker-clans">
		<text>Stalker clans</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zomstalkers">
		<text>Zombie stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_military_army">
		<text>Regular army soldiers. They protect approaches to the Zone, patrol its perimeter, kill mutants and catch looters. \nArmy Spetsnaz - elite troops. Normally dispatched to the Zone to conduct rescue operations and other special missions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_military_milstalkers">
		<text>Soldiers who underwent special training following their service in the Zone or stalkers who signed a contract with the Army. They are usually fitted out with a great deal of support equipment and well-armed. These stalkers are used mainly for studying the causes and effects of the catastrophe and also map the Zone. They can work on their own or in groups of up to five people. Military stalkers do not allow normal stalkers to approach and open fire on sight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile-groups">
		<text>Erased</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile-labs">
		<text>A mobile lab looks like a small metal bunker with tiny tinted windows. The laboratory is capable of withstanding most damage known to man and can work autonomously for several months as it is equipped with reliable life support systems. The bunker is delivered into the Zone by a transport helicopter. The lab staff never allow visitors past the external air-lock chamber, so no stalker has ever been inside one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_bandits">
		<text>Members of the criminal underworld who came to the Zone for different reasons; to make money by selling artifacts, hide from the law, buy or sell weapons. The Zone is full of such people who range from common thugs to serious criminals most of whom are members of gangs. Although there isn't a single united gang in the Zone these criminals pose serious problems for normal stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_duty">
		<text>A clearly militarised group noted for its strict discipline with members living according to a code. Only Duty representatives refuse to trade unique items from the Zone with the outside world. According to rumours, all artifacts found by members of this group are passed to scientists. Every member considers it his primary objective to protect the world from the Zone. Most of the group's operations concern destroying monsters and so Duty's raids often save normal stalkers from many practical problems. The faction has long been in a fierce war with Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_freedom">
		<text>Anarchists and daredevils who declare themselves to be fighting for free access to the Zone and consequently find themselves in constant conflict with army units, military stalkers and Duty. These freedom fighters believe that information about the Zone must not be hidden from humanity and challenge the state's monopoly over the Zone's secrets and wonders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_killers">
		<text>The most clandestine and secretive group in the Zone; some don't even believe in its existence. There are those who regularly use the mercenaries' services as they are true professionals in their business able to quickly deal with any stalker and even annihilate a small group. They appear to demand a King's ransom for their services in money or artifacts. The location of their base remains a secret, suggesting that it is deep inside the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_loners">
		<text>Stalkers who explore the Zone on their own. Most stalkers work in this way since membership in a group takes precious time thus limiting one's income. Some simply prefer solitude and independence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_monolith">
		<text>This group has many features of a religious sect. Its members believe in the existence of an evolutionary alien crystal, the Monolith, in the Zone's centre. Most stalkers treat Monolith adepts with contempt and consider them lunatics. From its inception the group has attempted to block progress towards the Zone's centre fearing that stalkers have ill intentions regarding the Monolith. Rumours say that the group has a large base near the centre of the Zone, but its exact location is know only to its members.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_zomstalkers">
		<text>Those who were subjected to prolonged exposure in Amber and a few other sectors. Careless stalkers quickly go mad and turn into walking corpses. Many of these corpses wander the Zone and some even reach the perimeter. In any case, they are beyond help because the destructive process is irreversible. While zombified stalkers are still able to use their weapons they are quite stupid and can be heard mumbling meaningless, fragmented sentences to themselves. Zombified stalkers gradually lose all their previous skills and turn into zombies. They are normally very aggressive and can present a serious threat in large numbers.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
