<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="Blind">
		<text>Blind dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Boar">
		<text>Boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Crow">
		<text>Crow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Flesh">
		<text>"Flesh"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="General">
		<text>General information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Mutants">
		<text>Animals and mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Poltergeist">
		<text>Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pseudodog">
		<text>Pseudodog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pseudogiant">
		<text>Pseudogiant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Snork">
		<text>Snork</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Tushkano">
		<text>Jerboa</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zombie">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_blind_general">
		<text>The dog species has seen several generations since the first catastrophe, which have all been increasingly affected by the Zone. Mutations and evolutional development lead to the improvement of previously peripheral abilities, often at the expense of primary ones. The main physiological change was loss of sight, which became almost useless after a rapid improvement in the dogs' sense of smell. Blind cubs, for example, survived in the Zone just as well as normal ones if not better. As a result, normal dogs quickly became extinct in the Zone and gave way to the new breed - blind dogs. These animals identify and avoid anomalies, radiation and other invisible dangers that plague the Zone with great ease. Just as their ancestors blind dogs hunt in packs and an encounter with a large group of these animals presents a serious danger even to a well-armed stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_bloodsucker_general">
		<text>This semi-legendary monster is described by experienced stalkers as a tall, hunched humanoid with a mess of tentacles instead of a mouth. According to these stalkers, the creature uses the tentacles to feed by clinging to the victim's throat, paralysing him and sucking him dry of blood, leaving only a dry, mummy-like shell in place of what was a living human only seconds earlier. The most astounding feature of the bloodsucker is its ability to become invisible. It seems that these creatures are responsible for the deaths of a large number of stalkers. Few of those who have seen one were lucky enough to survive the encounter and according to them bloodsuckers prefer damp places around marshes and subterranean areas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_boar_general">
		<text>A large animal that can reach 1.5 metres at the shoulder. The boar's ability to survive and aggression surpass that of its relatives outside the Zone and resemble that of most mutants. Mutagenic processes engendered by radiation and anomalies have played a significant part in shaping these mammals: they have lost all fur in places and grown long, bristly fur in others. The animals' hooves have changed in shape and become sharper, acquiring a resemblance to claws; their pupils have become colourless and pigmentation disorders and deep wrinkles have appeared on their bald heads. Zone boars resist radiation well which allows them to spend long periods in heavily contaminated areas. They normally attack by charging at their victims and attempting to rip them to shreds with their claws or knock them over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_crow_general">
		<text>Only one type of bird survived in the Zone. The others could not endure radiation and were unable to learn to avoid anomalies. Military pilots use complex detectors to avoid gravitational disturbance but the crows' secret will soon drive ornithologists and biologists mad. Many theories attempting to explain this phenomenon exist and all of them conclude that this miracle can only be explained by the development of crows' brains, which has helped them develop highly advanced reflexes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_flesh_general">
		<text>Like many other living creatures, domestic pigs in the Zone underwent serious mutation, which affected genes responsible for their metabolism causing the animal's phenotype to change significantly. A mutant pig of this type, know as "flesh" among stalkers, is one of the clearest examples of the Zone's perversion of nature. The pigs have developed a protective layer of scales and bones, their regeneration potential grew significantly and their nervous system became more complex. Just like a normal pig, "flesh" is an omnivore and may attack a stalker if hungry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_poltergeist_general">
		<text>Truly supernatural invisible creatures that can be found only deep inside the Zone and live mostly inside ruined buildings. Nothing is known about their origins although rumours in circulation claim they are spirits of stalkers who were hit by a massive wave of radiation. The mechanism of their appearance corresponds to poltergeist legends (hence the name) and is quite diverse: from regular howls and laughter to dangerous fireballs appearing from nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about this phenomenon originates from unclear and contradictory stories of questionable validity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudodog_general">
		<text>Despite the name pseudodogs developed from wolves. The wild animals inhabiting the Zone's forest when the catastrophe occurred gave rise to one of the most dangerous mutant species. Pseudodogs are about as different from mutated dogs as wild wolves are different from mongrels. The creatures mark and guard their territory, attacking those who enter without mercy. Their reaction, mobility and sharp teeth make pseudodogs very serious enemies for large mutants and well-armed stalkers alike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudogiant_general">
		<text>The pseudodogiant is a massive drop-shaped abdomen with a couple of disproportionately large limbs sticking out. The limbs are both arms and legs and are used by the creature to move around and grab its victims. An adult pseudodogiant can weigh up to two tonnes and stand 2m tall. Their clumsy appearance is deceiving as they move rapidly: their muscles are exceptionally powerful and their bones are as strong as steel. The creature's brain is protected by a very thick (100mm!) skull while many complex functions are controlled by the spinal medulla. Another astonishing feature of this beast is its ability to create localised shock waves, which damage all living things in its vicinity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_snork_general">
		<text>It appears that these creatures were at one point humans, however it is difficult to imagine the conditions that could turn a human being into this disgusting animal. Snorks are crazy creatures that lead an animal life and differ little from other carnivorous monsters in the Zone. They move on four legs, jumping along and constantly sniffing the ground in hope of picking up the scent of their prey. They hunt carefully and in a calculated manner, ambushing stalkers like wild animals. Their sharp reflexes and powerful muscles allow snorks to make accurate long jumps and tear their victims to shreds in a matter of seconds. Parts of army uniforms and other clothing are sometimes found on their bodies making it reasonable to suggest that they are what became of missing military stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_tushkano">
		<text>In reality these animals are not related to jerboas although there is a distinct resemblance. Determining the species from which the Zone's jerboas developed has so far proved impossible although it can be said with certainty that their ancestors were gregarious rodents. Reaching up to 40cm at the shoulder they are more mobile, aggressive and ravenous than the normal desert animal. Mutant jerboas live mainly in basements and destroyed buildings feeding on everything they can get their teeth in, from plants to careless stalkers. Sometimes jerboas attack and kill big animals and mutants in a large group tearing them apart before they can escape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_general">
		<text>The brain burner completely destroys personalities leaving only the bodily shell. After wandering in the Zone for a while these brainless bodies begin to turn into real zombies that are left with only the very basic instincts, no weapons or clothing. As a result zombies are little more than sluggish walking corpses that care only about food and sleep. Zombies eat and drink just about anything they can get their hands on so they are virtually soaked in radiation and toxins. Normally these creatures wander aimlessly in the Zone or lie in abandoned buildings like corpses. However, as soon as a zombie senses the presence of a human being it attacks immediately. Experienced stalkers have learned to avoid these clumsy emptied shells.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg">
		<text>Boar hoof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
		<text>Boars' hooves are used by scientists to make a number of drugs including anti-radiation serum.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail">
		<text>Dog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to chemicals and electricity has long been the subject of growing scientific attention. Due to the lack of fat in dog tails they are the best objects for lab studies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
		<text>Flesh eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>After the mutation the enlarged eye acquired a number of characteristics, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate the lens. The specifics of this process are as yet unclear but their discovery promises to revolutionise medicine. You can play your part in scientific development by selling the flesh eye to scientists for their experiments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles contain a special gland that secrets a ferment capable of dissolving skin and simultaneously preventing blood from clotting. If scientists could determine the ferment's composition, it would help to make great medical advances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
		<text>Pseudodog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to chemicals and electricity has long been the subject of growing scientific attention. Due to the lack of fat in dog tails they are the best objects for lab studies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg">
		<text>Snork foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
		<text>Snork feet, unlike those of humans, contain a huge number of highly elastic tendons. This explains the snork's ability to make unbelievable jumps.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
