<?xml version='1.0' encoding="windows-1251"?>

 

<game_information_portions>

    <info_portion id="news_escape_blockpost_attack">

        <text>Listen to me:Chaps, stay away from outpost 

              ..Some idiots attacked the : All in all it`s hot there :There will  certainly be a punitive raid again.</text>

    </info_portion>

    <info_portion id="news_escape_blockpost_case">

        <text>Bartender`s courier was taken at outpost recently. He had some stuff with him: A real titbit - box with artifacts: Outpost commander now has  

              it :So, if there is any fellow tired of his life, he can  take a risk.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_escape_electra">

        <text>Attention all. To the north from the bridge on the outpost,

                            100 meters from the derelict armored troop-carrier, I found gathering of electros:The one who uses this info - buys me beer.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="new_escape_bridge">

        <text>Men, military has resumed patrols under demolished bridge on the  

              outpost. And it looks as if their sniper sits there:Couldn`t make him out for sure -

 had to take my heels:</text>

    </info_portion>    

 

    <info_portion id="news_escape_bandits">

        <text>Listen all:On the plant on the outpost some bandits have settled 

              again. They take stalkers loot:Is there are any "advanced" nearby, 

              take care of bastards :I`ll pay you back.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_escape_dogs">

        <text>To the east from the bridge on the outpost I saw troop of dogs -

            about 20 or 30 of them: So draw your conclusions, gentlemen:</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_escape_artefact">

        <text>My friends stalkers:I am in urgent need of Night Star:For worthy bread, of course:People say there is one left on the outpost after previous Blowout:</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_marked">

        <text>:Vaska tells one more marked appeared in the Zone, he has just 

              left the trader. You know, what to do:</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_fedya">

        <text>Someone hit Fedyka the Black in the garages: I have a feeling, 

              bandits appeared again.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_dolina">

        <text>Stay away from Dark Valley, there are crowds of zombies there: 

              Spare your ammo, guys. This palace must be cleaned long time ago.

              What on earth Duty stalkers are thinking about?</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_dolg">

        <text>I think I saw some of Duty guys at the dump. I wonder who they  

               are after?</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_herovo">

        <text>:I'm feeling quite bad, iwas hit. If there is somebody not far from the Rusty lake please give me a hand, I'm always returning kindness: Anyway, I'll try to get out myself but: we'll see.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_gunslinger">

        <text>Gunslinger is back! Heard that from the competent people: Returned from the very center! It means that its possible, damn, it means that we'll make a great break-through to the center soon. Than we'll se who will win:</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_garage">

        <text>Three men hiding in the garages: Seems to me that it's a bandits fell back into their old ways: Everybody attention and be careful.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_garbage_dogs">

        <text>I'm at the dump, there a lot of goddam blind dogs around here:

            Looks like new troops came from the center. Be careful.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

    <info_portion id="news_agroprom_mili">

        <text>Everybody, carefully.  Looks like that the militaries are here for a long time.

        Their base is in the institute building. I've seen pair of dozens of men  and there was a sniper on the roof.</text>

    </info_portion>     

 

    <info_portion id="news_agroprom_box">

        <text>I have overheard from patrol`s talk, that military store all their 

              findings on the third storey of institute building. If someone wants to take risk - try and get it.</text>

    </info_portion>    

    

</game_information_portions>
